Nah, I swear, mate.
I just shushed him. Shushed him!
As in, you know,
“Shut your cave, mate.
“The main feature's started.”
I mean, the bastard talked all the way
through the coming attractions!
Are you calling because
you want Jane and me to post bail?
You know, Lil, your cynicism
frightens me sometimes.
You're my sister.
In times of crisis, family members
should be able to turn to each other.
I mean, you know,
if you and Jane wanted to discuss bail,
I wouldn't be averse.
You are unbelievable.
You know that Dad's estate
went to that bloody con man.
Yes, which is why I'm in this mess
in the first place.
I was trying to do the decent thing,
God help me — get your money back.
We didn't ask you
to get our money back!
Well, who else is gonna
get your money back?
Can't you see that
you guys posting bail for me,
it's a win-win for everyone?
Oh!
An old mate of yours,
apparently, Greene.
Cleaver Greene.
Yeah.
You know...I've still got
that Justin Bieber bracelet.
Oh, yeah.
You were part of Cal McGregor's
Praetorian Guard.
I'm surprised you're not
deputy commissioner by now.
What are you in for?
They say it's perversion
of the course of justice.
You've obviously been pissing
in the wrong end of the pool.
Cleaver, I'm sorry about
all that shit we put you through.
We were just following orders.
Right.
You're a barrister, right?
You gotta be kidding me.
Cleaver, you've gotta help me.
I'm a bent cop. If I stay in here
I'm a fucking dead man.
Greene.
Your bail's been posted.
Cleaver, please.
Oh.
Please.
Justin Bieber bracelet.
Fuck that was funny!
You sure
you can afford this?
I've got a bestseller,
Cleave. Remember?
I'm about to have a second.
And just so that you know,
there's going to be a movie.
I'm sorry?
They want to make a movie
about Josh and me.
Who's ‘they'?
Ron Howard's company.
Ron How...Ron Howard's company?
Potsie?
Richie.
He's producing and directing, yeah.
Richie is making a movie
based on your life?
- I know. Strange world, huh?
- Hey, Melissa! Cleaver!
Ladies and gentlemen,
I have had charges of manslaughter
levelled against me.
They're charges of which
I'm entirely innocent.
I have no further comment
to make at this moment.
Melissa, can you confirm reports
that Scarlett Johansson
will be playing you in the upcoming
movie based on your book?
I can't confirm
anything at this point,
but it is true that Scarlett's
one of many actresses
very keen to play the part.
And can you confirm
Daniel Craig for Josh?
That I can confirm.
And who will be playing
Cleaver Greene?
Uh, Judi Dench —
or Dame Judi Dench, I should say —
will be playing
the role of my barrister.
We've rethought
the role a little bit.
And how honoured
do you feel, Mr Greene,
to be played by one of the great
actresses of the modern age?
As I have said, ladies and gentlemen,
I have no further comment to make.
Thank you, thank you.
- Did you get that?
- Yeah, I got it all.
Judi bloody Dench? You're kidding me.
Ron is an ardent feminist
and the thinking is
it's somehow truer to the story
if you were played by a woman.
How can it be truer to the story?!
She's British,
she's an octogenarian
and she's a ‘she'.
How is that true? This is gonna
be a bloody train wreck.
I've always thought
Ron Howard was a hack.
Houston, we have a big
fucking problem here.
They've put me up in a hotel.
Oh, yeah. Of course they have.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Oh, yes, the day that
just keeps on giving.
Mate, how is this my shit?
I cancelled the job
and the job wasn't to kill anyone.
And the ‘anyone' certainly
wasn't the guy who's now dead.
You know that moron you subbed
the job out to came to my place?
The cops were tailing him.
That's how they put
two and two together
and came up with the usual 15.
If anyone should be in trouble,
it's that fucktard.
Don't worry about Darce, mate.
He knows the score. He'll be sweet.
Kirsty, how are you?
You look fabulous!
How great is this news
about you and Col?
Am I hearing wedding bells
anytime soon?
Ohh!
Fuck, yes, you're right.
Marriage is seriously overrated.
No! Kirsty!
Cleaver, you listen to me
very carefully.
Are you listening very carefully?
Yes, I'm listening carefully.
OK, you never came
to see Col about Lane Hole.
We didn't have anything to do with
that old bloke. You understand me?
OK, yes, I'll see what I can do.
Not good enough!
Arggh!
Alright, OK. I'll...I'Il...
I didn't come and see Col
about Lane Hole. Fuck!
Ohh...
Good.
Alright, great.
Ooh, Cleaver, one more thing.
You have 14 days
to repay me in full.
I think it's about time
we cleared that debt.
Don't you?
You know my situation.
Do I look like I give a shit
about your situation?14 days.
♪ I'm tired of sin
♪ And straying, Lord
♪ Now I'm coming
♪ Coming home
♪ I'll trust thy love
♪ Believe thy word
♪ Lord, I'm coming
♪ Coming home... ♪
Oh, congratulations!
I'm so happy for you!
Oh, my God.
♪ Lord, I'm coming home. I
Thanks, Viviana.
I'm so proud of you.
Thank you.
um Oh...
Oh, darling. What a thing!
Thanks for coming.
Sweetheart, of course, of course.
It means a lot to me.
Oh, I... Well...
Hi, Doc.
Do you know where I am?
Judging by the tone of voice,
a place of righteous indignation?
Very close.
I am standing in the church hall
where you were arrested
and your son was just baptised.
Now, I know you have
a lot on your plate,
what with having
recently murdered a pensioner...
I didn't murder him.
And the charge is manslaughter.
You know why Fuzz insisted
on getting baptised?
To cleanse himself of sin,
Cleaver, your sin.
That's all he talks about now,
“The sins of my father.”
Well, he's gonna need a bloody
big vat of holy water, isn't he?
Cleaver Greene
has spent his entire career
making sure that society's scum
are free to roam
our streets and neighbourhoods.
To this end, he has
successfully defended
7 terrorists, 186 rapists,
93 murderers,
countless thieves, frauds,
perverts, drug dealers
and at least one cannibal.
It is a client list
the criminal barrister
has been heard to boast of.
The question now
is has justice finally caught up
with Cleaver Greene himself?
This is Polly Nesbitt
for the ‘Today Project'.
Ooh, if it isn't the first lady
of the British theatre.
I'm gonna kill you.
It wasn't personal. I promise.
How can a nationally broadcast attack
on someone's personality
not be personal?
You're lucky it was me.
My EP wanted to go much harder.
Aren't we sort of seeing
each other or something?
You could've just said no.
I can't. I'm in a tricky
situation at work.
How?
I had a thing with the EP's niece.
His niece?
Yeah, I was experimenting.
She was this hot
19-year-old pro surfer
and things got a little bit weird.
Oh, did they?
Turns out she'd never
been with a woman before,
but since our ‘thing'
she's become a committed lesbian.
The family's devastated.
Well, I guess that makes pummelling
me on national telly OK, then.
Come on.
I guess it was just a lapse of memory
that you happened to forget
that plugging Lane Hole
was actually your idea
in the first...
I was fooling around!
No, no. Don't touch me.
Come on.
Oh, get off me.
Are you sure?
Oh, what am I gonna do with you?
I've got a few thousand ideas.
- Hey, Cleave!
- What the fuck?
Melissa has just agreed
to let me do an in-depth profile
on her for the show.
What? The whole two minutes?
What happened with Col and Kirsty?
Nothing!
Who are Col and Kirsty?
Oh, just a couple of
gangster friends of Cleave's.
The network loves gangsters.
How can I help?
You can't. You can
leave it alone, OK?
Please. I beg of you.
Don't...don't go near them.
Just... They had nothing
to do with anything.
Bullshit.
Am I, um, misjudging
the vibe in the room
or should the three of us be
taking a bottle of tequila to bed?
Cleave's given up three-ways, Pol.
He's worried he's not going to be
the centre of attention.
- To justice!
Sorry it's not French. Got a couple of
marginals up in wine country.
So, Jimmy, go on.
And don't leave out a thing.
Well, it looks like
a complete cock-up, Cal.
The real target seems to have been
the old bloke's neighbour,
a scumbag by the name of Lane Hole.
Um, I've heard of him.
ASIC's been on his case.
Ripped off Greene's
old man, apparently.
Oh, right. So a vendetta?
Ooh, sounds serious.
Pity it's just manslaughter.
What do you reckon he'll get?
Two years. Three at a push.
Two years?! That's fucking playtime.
Mm.
What about going him for murder?
Wasn't at the scene,
wrong bloke got killed.
It'd be impossible to prove intent.
Manslaughter's a much safer bet.
Huh. Bloody shame.
Mmm.
Yeah.
He came to your flat?
You are kidding me.
What sort of moron is this guy?
Uh, a ‘sub-moron'
I think is the technical term.
Anyway, I think he's done a deal.
Who with? The cops?
No, with Col and Kirsty.
If he keeps them out of it,
points the finger at me,
does a little quiet time,
then they're gonna look after him.
Col said, “Darcy will be sweet.”
They were his exact words.
I'm fucked, mate.
Morning.
Mate, it's manslaughter.
It's not like murder.
They don't have to prove intent,
just that you behaved recklessly.
I am aware.
I hate to say it,
but you're in for a world of pain.
I didn't mean for anything to happen.
It was just meant to be a warning.
And I called it off.
And they got
the wrong fucking guy!
Hey, Barn.
What if it wasn't manslaughter?
Sorry?
What if the charge was murder?
What are you talking about?
Well, then they'd have
their work cut out.
Like you say,
they'd have to prove
that I intended
to kill the poor old fella.
Hate to be Mr Picky, but the charge
isn't murder. It's manslaughter.
It doesn't have to be.
It can be changed.
You want the charge upgraded?
You're insane!
Listen to me.
If it's manslaughter,
I'm rooted, right?
I reckon.
But it it's murder, then I would
actually be in with a shot.
Why stop at murder, Cleave?
I reckon you'd stand an even
better chance with genocide.
Captain Buzzkill.
How do you propose
to get the charge upgraded?
Ladies and gentlemen,
ever since it was publicly revealed
that I had an affair with
the former premier of this state,
her ex-husband, the Police Minister
and Attorney-General Cal McGregor,
has pursued a relentless vendetta
against me.
You better believe it, buddy.
He has used his enormous power
as both Police Minister
and Attorney-General to harass me.
He's had me arrested
on numerous occasions —
all without charge, I might add...
..In an attempt
to humiliate and intimidate me.
Ooh, the humiliation isn't
over yet, pal. I promise you that.
It's a pathetic attempt by a cuckold
to try and reinvent himself
and restore his manhood
in the eyes of the community.
You're obviously throwing
some mud of your own here.
You're alleging that Cal McGregor
was responsible for bringing down
the former premier,
Claudia Marshall, his own wife.
Look, Tony, I don't think
it's any mystery.
From the Premier down,
everybody knows that Cal
threw his own wife under the bus,
metaphorically speaking,
so that he could keep his own job.
And I challenge you, actually,
to ask the Premier
who leaked the text messages
that brought down Claudia Marshall.
This is why the Premier's
in Cal's pocket.
Have you got
any evidence at all..
..to back up what you're saying?
Look, it's not really
my place to produce evid...
Hello.
Uh, yes, yes, Premier.
Yep, well, I know. I... Listen.
I know, but...
God, would you listen
to me, Stevie?!
Greene's all bark.
The story's got no legs.
You wait, mate. Who could possibly
wanna run with that bullshit?
I'm not making any comment
on Mr Greene's guilt or innocence.
All I'm saying is he's raising
some very important questions
about the integrity
of the justice system
that is currently under
Cal McGregor's watch.
I mean, let's face it.
As both Police Minister
and Attorney-General —
the first person ever
to hold both posts, I might add —
he wields enormous power.
And the question
that needs to be asked is,
“Is he abusing that power?”
And I think that question ought to be
asked by a royal commissioner.
I want Greene in a maximum security
facility by morning tea
and I never want him
to see the light of day again.
Do you understand?
I told you if we run
a murder charge against Greene
there's a 98% chance he'll go free!
There's gotta be a way, mate,
unless you're not happy
in your role as director.
Fair go!
God, you've gotta have something.
You won the university medal,
for Christ's sake.
Look, there is one possibility.
But, gee whiz, there's some
serious evidentiary issues.
Mate, you get me the charge,
I'll get you the evidence.
Cleaver Greene.
The charge against you
of the manslaughter of Albert Platt
has been withdrawn...
Oh, you don't say, Len?
..and replaced with a charge of
conspiracy to murder one Lane Hole.
Sorry. Did you say
conspiracy to murder Lane Hole?
Yes, Cleave.
Because I...I was expecting
that it might be a charge
of murder of Albert Platt.
Are you sure it's...
Positive, Cleave.
“Conspiracy to murder Lane Hole.”
It says so right here.
So...
So now they might
be able to prove intent.
I didn't game this out
particularly well, did 1?
So how much could you be looking at
for the conspiracy charge?
Maximum's life.
So you could end up with life
instead of, what?
A couple of years for manslaughter?
Oh, Cleave, what were you thinking?!
Well, I was hoping
that they would charge me
with the murder of the sweet old guy
rather than conspiracy
to murder Lane Hole.
Is that it?
What?
I've got fellowship.
Right.
You do realise the gravity
of what I've just told you?
I think so.
You might go to jail
for the rest of your life
because you didn't get the sort
of murder charge you were after.
Oh, yeah.
I don't want you to go to jail, Dad.
I really don't.
But there's not much I can
practically do right now
and I've got fellowship.
Fuzz, you do realise we might not have
a whole lot more time together?
So what?
You want me to drop
something I care about
because you screwed up
massively again?
Fuzz!
If I spend the rest of my life
dealing with your screw-ups
I won't have a life left
to live of my own.
Jesus.
See you, Mum.
OK, have fun happy clapping.
J And God said to Noah
- ♪ “There's gonna be a floody-floody!” ♪
- Cleaver...
♪ God said to Noah
♪ “There's gonna be a floody-floody!”
♪ “Get those animals
out of the muddy...” ♪
Arggh!
Fuzz.
Fuzz, Fuzz!
Shit!
Why is it you have to mock
anything you don't understand?
Anyone and anything who's different,
who even slightly challenges
your fucked-up world view...
..you have to reduce it
to a funny line.
This is why you're gonna
end up sad and lonely.
He loves you, Cleaver.
He just...
He wants to be able to count on you.
All of us do.
It...it's like you assume
we could only ever want you around
for a bit of colour.
But you need to understand that
the people who love you need you.
So stop being such a dickhead,
wise up and beat this charge.
Cleaver. Cleaver!
It was just a moment.
A rush of blood. I was pissed.
I didn't mean for anybody
to be killed.
“The awful daring
of a moment's surrender,
“that an age of prudence
can never retract.”
Pius the Incontinent?
T.S. Eliot.
Bloody Anglican, mate.
High Anglican. We count them.
Well, whatever I intended
to happen or not,
a nice old bloke is dead
as a result.
Our actions always
have consequences.
You know that, Cleaver.
If we mortals have no way
of knowing these consequences,
if they can be so random that
they're beyond contemplation...
God gives us free will
sO we can make our own choices.
Bullshit.
There's no choice out there.
Just fucking chaos.
My beautiful boy took a swing
at me today.
And I deserved it.
So he's a fighter like his dad.
How's his mum coping?
A little too well, actually,
from my point of view.
Oh. Oh.
Oh.
Oh, I'm sorry.
No, no, no, it's me.
No, it's not you, Roger.
Yeah, itis.
It's not. It's...you know.
I have an ex-husband
facing a murder charge.
I have an evangelical son
who until recently —
well, God,
I hope until recently —
had a fetish for older women.
I'm just in a very weird place
at the moment.
I'm really sorry.
What?
It's not you, Wendy.
So it's true. There is illegal
gambling in Sydney after all.
Right. You and I
can talk freely, Col.
We're mates.
I told you, Bump,
I'm not saying a word, mate.
I'd love to be able to tell
the court you were cooperative.
This is, after all, your...
..11th offence.
Judges these days, mate,
they frown upon recidivists.
Changing the subject completely,
have you heard the news
about Cleaver Greene?
Nasty business.
And we are hoping that anyone
with any information
that can assist us with our inquiry
will come forward.
Yeah, it was a nasty business,
wasn't it?
Cleaver said he'd come
to the end of his rope.
You know, he'd tried everything
that he could think of
to get to Lane Hole,
but nothing had worked.
Then he said, “He's gotta die, Col.
The prick's gotta die.”
And I said, “No, Cleave,
that's crazy talk, mate.
“You know, violence
never solved anything.”
Then he asked me
if I knew anyone
who could do the job for him.
“A paid assassin?”', I said.
“Nah, nah, Cleave, mate,
you've got to come to your senses.”
So after a few months,
I broke it off with Cleaver
because I'd fallen in love
with somebody else.
Somebody kinder, gentler.
Somebody who understands
the true meaning of love
and has a, um...a deep respect
for law and order.
Cleaver didn't take this
very well
and not long after that,
his father passed away.
It turns out
that this Lane Hole fellow
conned Cleaver's father
out of his share portfolio.
So, you know,
Cleaver became quite obsessed
and I recall him expressing
on no less than, um...
..one...two...three occasions
his desire to see
Lane Hole murdered
in ways that I couldn't...
possibly describe.
Quite frankly, I was terrified.
Kirsty.
Kirsty! What the fuck?!
Don't you know it's a crime to
threaten or badger the witness?
Don't you know it's a crime
to commit perjury?
Prove it.
OK.
You know what?
I'm not going to threaten you
or badger you or...
what was the other thing?
Oh, that's right, pay you.
Oh! You'll pay me, Cleaver.
One way or another,
I'm going to get my money.
Oh, do you honestly think
I give a flying fuck
what you do to me now?
Yeah, but you do give a flying fuck
about your friend Melissa.
You two, you're very close.
From what I understand,
she put up your bail.
And from what I read
in the paper...
Kirsty...
..she can afford it.
Melissa has nothing
to do with this, alright?
We'll see about that. She might
want to make a contribution.
She's staying at the Sheraton,
isn't she, sweet?
Why do you know that?
See you, Cleaver.
Oop!
Lyle! How you doing?
I was just thinking about you.
Listen, I've got a favour
I want to ask of you.
Oh, fuck!
Missy, it's me.
Just...
Sweetheart, um, call me
when you get this, OK?
And just...
I'm coming to see you.
Don't leave your room
whatever you do, OK?
I'll be there in a minute.
Can you call me when you get this?
Missy!
Oh. Judi Dench
is the Protector.
That's a microphone.
Why don't we just pay her
the fucking money then?
I didn't come here to ask you
to pay Kirsty for me.
I came here to tell you
to get on a plane.
If she'll have you hurt,
what choice do I have?
She'll have both of us hurt.
All the more reason
to pay her then.
Listen, can you not just
get on a plane, please?
You're going to go anyway.
Leave you here to be killed?
Look, I think I would die
a worse death
if you actually paid Kirsty,
alright?
Cleaver...
That debt is a monument
to my bad judgement
and self-indulgence
and I need to sort it out,
and I will sort it out.
And so if I have to do some time
for the poor old guy's death,
or...or lose an eye to Kirsty,
then so be it, OK?
I would rather look at my son
half-blind than as a coward,
and I will not be able
to live with myself
if anything happens to you.
How do you think I would feel
if I could have saved your life
for two hundred grand?
It's not just
about you, Cleave.
Yes, itis. I'm a narcissist.
Get on a plane.
http://hiqve.com/
What the hell?
I'm sorry.
I know this doesn't look...
Are you crazy?
I had to see you.
Now?
Well, you haven't been
answering my texts.
Nicole, listen...
I've left Bevan.
What?!
Yeah, this morning.
OK, OK. Uh, look.
You might need to see
someone about this
because what you're
going through...
Barney, I'm pregnant.
Whoa.
You know, that doesn't necessarily
mean I'm the father,
does it?
And the thing is,
Bevan and I made this deal
that we wouldn't have relations
for three months
before the wedding, you know,
to make the night
special, so...
Oh, God. Oh, God.
I can't talk about this now.
Oh. Right. I'm sorry. I just...
I had to tell you.
Y-yeah.
l...I guess you did.
Have you, um...have you got
somewhere to stay?
Do you need money for a hotel?
‘Cause I've got some cash if...
You don't have to worry
about money.
Uh... Yep.
You alright?
Barney?
Oh. Jesus.
I don't feel very well.
I need you to do me a favour.
OK, yep.
Morning, Nicole.
Um...yes.
Red?
Barney's as sick as a dog.
He thought you could use a hand.
You're many things, Cleaver,
but you're not a killer.
I call Callum
Dalgleish McGregor.
Your Honour,
my friend, the accused,
is yet again attempting
to mock this court
by turning these proceedings
into another of
his lamentable circuses.
Every witness
my friend attempts to call
is a citizen of high office
whom he seeks to traduce
for his own base motives.
Mr Greene,
the fact that you may share
a certain history
with Mr McGregor
has no inherent probative
value whatsoever.
Your Honour, this is a witch-hunt
being conducted at the behest
of the Attorney-General.
Mr Greene,
for the very, very last time,
I do not grant leave
to subpoena Mr McGregor.
We will break there.
We will resume at two o'clock.
All rise.
Why don't you call me?
What?
Call me.
I used to work for Cal.
I know where a couple of bodies
are buried.
The judge isn't going
to let you get in the box.
What?
Maybe that's not
such a bad thing.
Your Honour,
I call Scarlet Rachel Engels.
Your Honour...
Ms Engels is not only known
as a friend of the accused,
she is also
a disgruntled former employee
of the Attorney-General
with an axe to grind.
It's just another act
in the same circus.
Indeed it is.
I have had dozens
of conversations
with Cal McGregor
in which he spoke
with unnerving zeal
of his desire to be the author
of Mr Greene's demise.
He bragged of his ‘Cleaver Unit',
officers whose sole purpose
was to intimidate...
..and harass Mr Greene.
Let me make this clear.
I do have an axe to grind.
Because Cal McGregor
is abusing his power,
and in the interests
of democracy
and the people of the state,
he must be stopped.
Now I am prepared to face any
scrutiny from him or anyone else
but, as a lawyer, I would rather
answer those questions
in a court of law
and under oath
where the penalty for perjury
iS severe.
How about you, Cal?
Thank you.
Ah, we just have to
sit tight, boys.
Once the guilty verdicts in,
her words will be
lining budgie cages.
I like to be watched
while I'm doing it.
I don't...l don't fool around
with her.
I mean,
that would be just sick,
but just...having her in the room,
it just helps, you know?
Just in terms of
my performance.
Does she have a name?
Yeah.
Ruth.
Yeah, Ruth.
[...I don't have to talk to her
or anything.
Just helps if she's in the room.
Watching?
Does that idea bother you?
Wendy, I like you.
I like you so much, and I'd
hate this to be a deal breaker.
Every other aspect of my life,
I am completely normal,
almost to the point of boring.
So...
..c-could we just give it a try?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Who is it?
Kirsty, this is Melissa.
Cleaver's friend.
Oh!
Got the money?
You know, you've saved yourself
a lot of grief.
What about Cleaver?
Oh, it's neither here nor there.
His life's over.
He gets to cross-examine you today.
Oh, big fuckin' whoopee.
He can't break me
and he knows it.
He also knows what really happened.
So?
It's the story you spin
in this town that counts.
And I'm gonna keep spinning
my story
until Cleaver Greene is in jail
for the rest of his life.
Why?
The combination's 4-3-7.
Is it all in there?
There's no money.
There's no fuckin' money!
What the fuck is this?
Col.
You're gonna fuckin' die, bitch!
And I'm gonna fuckin' bury you
where no-one will
ever look for you!
Do you understand me?
Fuck!
Oh, hello.
Is this some kind of joke,
Cleaver?
Ah, Kirsty.
How are you?
Yeah, well, there are gonna be
some serious fuckin' consequences.
Kirsty, if you look up
to your right,
you'll notice what looks like
an abandoned truck.
Now, inside that truck,
there's a film crew.
It's amazing what you can pick up
on a long lens these days,
you know?
I'm also reliably informed that
there's quite a few of those
teensy-weensy little
cameras and microphones
inside Melissa's car.
And if you squint
your beady little eyes,
you'll notice me marching forward
with, uh, Polly Nesbitt from
the ‘Today Project.
I've been under a course of
strong medication
for rheumatoid arthritis.
Um, and I've been
suffering from...
..persistent and acute sciatica.
I'm told the medication may have
caused auditory hallucinations...
..along with a sense of anxiety
and paranoia.
I've also recently been
diagnosed with depression.
As a consequence,
my perception of events
may be less than reliable...
..and, uh, my conduct erratic,
given my, um,
unpredictable mood swings.
I wish to apologise
without reservation to the court...
..for any misleading testimony
I may have given
regarding Mr Greene's conduct.
I find the witness
in contempt.
Take him down.
Questions must be asked as to why
these two witnesses were prepared
to perjure themselves.
Was it simply for personal reasons,
or were they in fact suborned
to give false evidence?
Is this in fact
yet another conspiracy
orchestrated by
Cal McGregor?
In the interests of what's
left of justice in this state,
the Attorney-General must face
this court and explain himself.
Mr McGregor, will you be resigning
after this behaviour?
This is disgraceful. The public
needs answers, Mr McGregor.
I made you premier, Stevie.
Just like you made Claudia premier,
Cal.
Don't try to play the loyalty card
with me.
Here's what's going to happen next,
in plain English.
You're going to ring
your fuckwit uni mate at the DPP
and you're going to tell him
to call you as a witness.
And you are gonna answer every
question Cleaver Greene puts to you
with a fucking smile.
And you are gonna put this thing
to bed, or you're finished, Cal.
Do you understand?
Let me be crystal clear about this.
I have never met
Kirsty Corella or Colin Mancusi.
Never?
Never.
And the idea that I would suborn
anyone to give false evidence
is offensive and absurd.
Mm. But you could have
directed others to approach them.
I could have, but I didn't.
Indeed.
Thank you, Mr McGregor.
Mr McGregor, are you aware
that the charge against me
was originally manslaughter?
I am.
Can you tell the court how
the charge came to be upgraded
to one of conspiracy
to commit murder?
No idea. You'd have to
ask your learned friend.
Is it not the case
that you used your influence
to have the charge upgraded as
a result of media interviews I gave
which you found
a little bit embarrassing?
That is not the case, Mr Greene.
Because, of course,
my learned friend here
is also your old uni pal
and the man that you appointed
director of public prosecutions.
Your Honour, this is outrageous!
Mr Greene, unless you have evidence
of a conspiracy between
the Attorney-General and the Crown,
I cannot allow this line of
questioning to proceed.
Your Honour,
it's painfully obvious.
Mr Greene, I have had enough.
I'll move on, Your Honour.
You better had.
Mr McGregor, why on earth
did you break into my apartment
and tell me that you'd
planted cocaine there?
That never happened.
But you'll agree, will you not,
that you had me arrested
on April the 2nd
for a child abduction
that never took place.
Oh, I don't know what you're
talking about, Mr Greene.
I see.
So you know nothing of my arrests,
variously,
for, uh, car theft, sexual assault,
uh, desecration of a church,
burning down a kindergarten.
On each of these occasions,
no charges were actually pressed.
This is all pure fiction,
Mr Greene.
I see, Mr McGregor.
So let's be very clear here.
What you're saying is that you
never directed your police force
to harass or intimidate me
in any way?
That is exactly what I'm saying,
Mr Greene.
You're aware, Mr McGregor,
that you're under oath here.
Of course.
I would never abuse my office
or the trust of the people of
this great state in that way.
No further questions, thank you,
Your Honour.
Very well.
You may be excused, Mr McGregor.
Do you have anything else,
Mr Greene,
or can we proceed to
closing addresses?
Um, there are one or two things,
Your Honour.
What's this about?
I'm a friend of Cleaver Greene's.
I'm also a barrister.
I understand you're looking for
some free legal assistance.
Your Honour, I call
Phillip Andrew Saunders.
A Justin Bieber bracelet,
Constable Saunders.
Do you remember one of those?
Uh, Your Honour,
Mr Saunders is a former constable.
My apologies, Your Honour.
Former Constable Saunders,
do you recall one of
these bracelets?
I do.
So you recall the fact
that on the 21st of February,
you were directed to come to
my flat in order to intimidate me.
I was.
Who actually directed you
to attend my apartment that night?
My watch commander.
I see.
And did you further arrest me
on April the 2nd of this year
in relation to the abduction
of a child?
I did.
Now, where did this abduction
take place?
I don't know where
the abduction took place.
We were just told to bring you in.
Right.
Was I charged?
No.
Again, my watch commander
told me to bring you in.
Thank you,
former Constable Saunders.
Senior Sergeant Wilson,
you were the watch commander
on the night in question.
Is there any record of anyone
filing a complaint in this matter?
No.
Then why did you order my arrest?
l...I got a call from
the Deputy Commissioner's office.
Deputy Commissioner,
how did you come to be involved
in my arrest for child abduction?
I received an order to arrest you
from the Minister's office.
Did this order come from
the Minister's office
or from the Minister himself?
The Minister himself.
At last! The truth emerges.
That man, ladies and gentlemen,
is the true criminal in this court.
- That man is the despot who ought...
- Order! ORDER!
Mr Greene!
I have been addicted
to prescription medication
for the past year.
I have relied on it heavily
since the...
..the breakdown of my marriage.
I wasn't warned of the potentially
profound side effects.
Be that as it may, Mr McGregor...
..I will be remanding you
on a charge of contempt
as charges of perjury
are contemplated.
Justice, when it is done,
reflects well on us,
don't you reckon?
Not just the lawyers, not just court,
but society as a whole.
And, today, it reflects
spectacularly well
because, today, we are reminded
that no man is above the law.
Not even the chief law officer
of this state.
Your Honour, in these circumstances,
I must once again move for dismissal.
Your Honour, uh,
whilst there is clearly an issue
of potential malfeasance
on the Attorney-General's part,
Mr Greene has not produced
a single shred of evidence
that any such malfeasance took part
in relation
to this charge
of conspiracy to murder.
Uh, Your Honour...
Quiet, Mr Greene.
Please, go on, Mr Crown.
I would respectfully submit,
Your Honour,
that the Crown
has clearly established
both motive on Mr Greene's part
as well as a connection
with his co-accused,
who told this court
that Mr Greene alone
came to him and paid him
to kill Lane Hole.
Mr Greene.
Do you have any tangible evidence
that Mr McGregor conspired in
this particular matter against you?
Your Honour, I have clearly established
a pattern of beha...
I didn't ask about a pattern.
Do you have actual evidence
of corrupt practices
on Mr McGregor's part
in terms of this specific charge
of conspiracy to murder?
I take it by your silence
that you do not.
Members of the jury,
I must warn you
not to let the events of today
taint what you would otherwise consider
as solid evidence
and I also must direct
that in contemplating your verdict,
you disregard the fact
that Mr McGregor
was found in contempt by this court
and disregard the fact
that he may face charges of perjury.
You must rely on the solid evidence.
Your Honour...
Hi, mate.
Hey, Dad.
How's Tara?
She's good.
God says hi.
Ah.
Well, give him my regards.
How long will it take for a verdict?
Could be hours. Could be days.
I've been thinking I might be ready
to go back to the bar.
But defence now.
You know what I think
my problem's been?
Ever since I was a kid,
I had this expectation
that I should be happy
all the time.
But there's always gonna be
unhappiness in the world.
There's always gonna be shit
we cry about,
shit we ought to cry about.
What business do we have wanting
to be happy 100% of the time?
Hm?
So what do you reckon?
70/30 — happiness and unhappiness?
That's realistic, don't you think?
It was Nicole I had the affair with.
Cleaver's Nicole.
What?
She's pregnant
and the baby's mine.
I don't know what
she's thinking of doing.
I guess this is part of the 30%.
How say you?
We find the defendant,
Darcy Robert Lachlan,
guilty of conspiracy to murder.
We find the defendant,
Cleaver Greene,
guilty of conspiracy to murder.
Darcy Lachlan.
Your cooperation in this matter
does you some credit.
I sentence you
to 10 years imprisonment
with a non-parole period
of six years.
Cleaver Greene.
As a barrister,
you have a duty to this court.
Your conduct has disgraced it
and yourself.
You took the law into your own hands
and now you must pay the penalty.
I sentence you...
to 14 years imprisonment...
..with a non-parole period
of eight years.
Such is life.
♪ I've wandered far
♪ Away from God
♪ Now
♪ I'm comin'
♪ Comin' home
♪ The path of sin
♪ Too long I've trod
♪ Lord
♪ I'm comin', I'm comin' home... ♪
Ladies and gentlemen,
as you're aware,
I'm honoured
to have been elected to lead
the New South Wales
Parliamentary Labor Party.
My goals are simple —
to reform this once great party
and win back the trust
of the people of New South Wales.
♪ Lord
♪ I'm comin'
♪ I'm comin'... ♪
You alright?
OK then.
You are Lane Hole, aren't you?
Good.
♪ So this is the end of
♪ The end of my story, story
♪ This is the end of
♪ Everything is hunky-dory, dory
♪ Children of the Lord
♪ Children of the Lord. ♪
Evening, boys.
http://hiqve.com/