Come on, girls.
Left. Left.
Left, right, left.
At ease.
Attention.
And now, for our Head Prefect.
Each year, we choose a student
who models
academic excellence and leadership.
For the first time ever,
our Head Prefect is
from the girls' hostel.
Mira Kishore.
Thank you, sir.
Congratulations.
- We are very proud!
- Thank you.
Come.
- Assembly.
- Sorry.
Attention.
Hi.
Okay...
Please say the pledge after me.
As a student of my school,
I pledge to honor...
our age-old Indian culture
and live according to it.
It shall be my constant endeavor...
to abide by the rules...
of my school.
I warned you yesterday.
Arms up!
- Why do you have wrong socks?
- I forgot to wear.
- Are they in the hostel?
- Yes.
Please go change them.
She started it.
- Don't lie, you did.
- Shut up!
I don't want to know.
Just not during the pledge, okay?
Now, two rounds of the field.
And tie your hair.
Fine, I'll take it off.
- Congratulations, Mirabai.
- Thank you.
You are very annoying.
- May I come in, sir?
- Yes, come in.
- 11.
- Congrats, Mira.
Work hard.
Mira.
I'm going to be very strict with you
because you'll get me
100 out of 100 in the boards.
Yes?
Yes, sir.
19 out of 20.
- And that is the highest.
- Oh, highest!
Mira.
Mira!
14. Good.
Can you call her?
Can I see your test paper?
- Can you pass it to him?
- 16...
Good.
Srinivas?
Yes?
8.
I thought you to be
from an international school.
10... You need to work harder.
- Hi.
Can you use your special powers
to put this up for me?
Sure.
Flyers stay up for a week.
Can I help?
It's not really a two-person job.
Ah...
Wait.
Flyers stay up for a week.
You can ask for an extension
if you want.
Thank you.
Hi!
Hello!
Please take.
Hi!
Congratulations, ma'am.
Hello, I'm Mira's mom.
Thank you so much!
Hi, come!
I'll explain the rest of the keys later.
There is my Head Prefect!
Hi, sweetie! Come.
I'm so proud!
So proud!
Some older teachers
didn't think a girl could do it.
Give some sweets to the oldies.
In our times,
girls were not even considered.
No chance.
This one's going to prove them wrong.
Thank you, ma'am.
- See you later.
- Alright.
Bye.
Ma, you've to wait at the gate.
Parents aren't allowed inside campus.
But ex-students are!
Okay, you forgot your sweater.
Ani Aunty. Hi!
Hi, dear.
Miss Prefect has
been lecturing me already.
Same!
Just like her dad.
Let's go.
You can look into this
and I'll help you focus.
Okay.
Uh...
You can...
Oh... oh, wow!
- Better?
- That's beautiful!
Okay, boys. Come on!
Okay, come on. Pack up now.
Hello, ma'am.
- How was it?
- Quite informative.
Any of the other girls
from 12th come?
I asked the senior girls but...
It's okay. What can one do?
- Hi, ma'am.
- Hi.
They were really interested,
they had so many questions.
Thank you.
Hands-on learning is best.
Some teachers don't care but...
Come on, Nisarg. Let's go.
Okay, boys. Come on.
I'll bring those boys.
And lock up.
Okay.
- Just lock the gate.
- Alright.
I'll bring this to you.
Boys, back to the dorm.
Quickly!
You are clearly cold.
Thanks.
Aren't you feeling cold?
I am.
Do you want to share?
Maybe we can sit...
Um...
For ten minutes.
Ten minutes.
How did you get into astronomy?
We had a club
back in my Hong Kong school.
Do you miss that school?
Sometimes.
It's different here.
A lot of rules.
But you seem to like the rules.
Mira...
- I have a question for you.
- Okay.
- But you'll have to answer it honestly.
- Alright.
Why did you stay back?
I wanted to help pack.
I think you didn't hear me.
What if we made a rule
that we be honest with each other?
No bullshit.
Why did you stay back?
I don't know.
I wanted to help pack up, but...
I thought...
we could talk,
get to know each other.
What do you want to know?
How about a secret?
Okay.
The first thing
that came to my mind.
I was a total mamma's boy.
And for me, she was the best
and the smartest.
I followed her everywhere.
This one time,
she was changing
and I walked in.
That was the first time
I'd seen a naked woman.
Oh my god!
I ran out immediately, screaming.
That's the last time I followed her.
I don't know
why I said that. I'm...
Okay.
Your turn.
Thinking of something?
So...
I was always losing my things
and...
my mom would get mad.
And in 5th standard,
I lost my sweater,
my water bottle
and my new sweater.
So, I did not want to tell her.
And there was this girl
I didn't like,
so I took her sweater.
And she got punished
for wrong uniform.
And I still feel very bad for her.
Are you still scared of your mom?
No.
Now I just can't stand her.
Don't say anything
if my mom picks up.
Okay.
I'll do one ring and cut?
I'll see you.
Bye.
Can I... kiss you?
No.
I didn't mean to...
That's fine.
- You sure?
- I'm sure!
Okay.
That was so cute!
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Bye.
Where the hell were you?
I'm going to fail.
I don't understand this gene therapy.
I was in the astronomy club.
I'm so brain-dead.
What's wrong?
Give. I'll teach you.
What is this astronomy club?
It's a new club started
by Ms. Bansal
and this new boy Srinivas.
Good morning, ma'am.
- Good morning.
- The key.
Why didn't you return it last night?
Ma'am, I thought I'd disturb you, so...
You know students are not allowed
to have this key in the night.
Apologies, ma'am.
Anyway...
- Can you get the senior girls?
- Sure, ma'am.
Priya.
Take that chair and place it here.
Now climb up on it.
This is what it looks like
when you climb stairs.
Mira, place the other chair
next to her.
Please climb up on it.
Yes, ma'am.
This is the correct length.
Uniforms to your knees.
Pull up your socks.
Come on.
Now! Pull up your socks.
Socks!
Also, girls, be careful with boys.
Don't talk to them
more than necessary.
How idiotic.
You're getting older,
you need to be careful.
You understand?
That's it.
You can go. Dismissed.
Come on.
It's really hot.
- It's supposed to be a little hot.
- It's a lot hot!
So have you had a boyfriend before?
No one interested me ever.
Well, high standards
for the Head Prefect.
What about you?
I had a girlfriend in Hong Kong.
She was a senior.
How long were you two together?
Eight months.
Are you jealous?
I don't care.
Mira?
Mira.
Coming.
Who were you talking to?
What?
I was studying.
I heard you. Don't lie.
Who was it?
Hel--
Who is this?
A friend.
A friend?
At this time?
- You want ice cream with this?
- No.
One or two?
One.
Which practice test
are you doing today?
Physics.
Good.
Who were you talking to last night?
A friend.
Please be honest with me.
I talked to Dad today morning.
Not about this. I'm not stupid.
They're trying to convince Riddhi.
I told them it's too late now.
They put a lot of restrictions on her
and now she's refusing to come home.
I don't want you
to have to hide something from me.
I'm not hiding anything from you.
Then who were you talking to?
I told you! A friend.
A boy.
What's his name?
It changes the voice.
Hello?
Hello. Can I speak to Srinivas
from Veer House?
And you are?
His aunt.
One minute.
Call Srinivas Ram.
Hello?
What?
- I've called him.
- Yes.
- Please hold.
- Yes, no problem.
I'm holding.
- Hi.
- Hey.
Just say we're friends, okay?
What?
Hi, Aunty. I'm Sri.
Hi, I'm Mira's mom, Anila.
I saw these flowers
and thought they were really pretty.
Thanks.
Mira, put these in a vase.
Come sit.
- Bring some water also.
- Okay.
I didn't know
you have such an amazing garden.
It's my mom's.
This house is my mom's.
Mira was saying you split your time
between here and Haridwar?
I always come for her exams.
But this year is very important, so...
I'll be here until her board exams.
My daughter's my priority,
whether she realizes it or not.
Have.
Thank you.
- That's why I wanted to ask--
- Do you miss Haridwar?
No.
Not really.
- What do your parents do?
- My father is a diplomat.
And my mother is a dancer.
She also teaches Bharatnatyam.
You were in Hong Kong before?
Yes, Aunty, for three years.
Before that, Dubai, Cairo, all over.
How do you like it here?
It's okay.
But the food is terrible.
Mira...
get your clothes ready for laundry.
I'll do it later.
He's coming early
for your uniform, go.
We're just friends.
I won't allow anything
more than a friendship.
Of course.
I just want
to get to know her and...
I don't know many people here.
I don't even have a local guardian.
But this can't affect her academics.
I wouldn't want that.
Nice color for a principal, no?
Yes, I like it too.
It's hard being new
in boarding school.
Maybe I can take some food for him?
You can invite him for lunch.
He's a nice boy.
He's very mature for his age.
What are you whispering about?
Mira.
Do you mind
if I see what you've done?
Behave, she is your
bhabhi (sister-in-law).
Seriously, we were only kidding.
Be careful when you sit.
They can see up your skirt.
I'm sorry.
Foreign fucker!
Mira.
I got this for you.
Open it, please.
Sorry, I can't accept it.
Why?
I'm not interested.
I thought we were friends.
I share my notes with you.
I also share my notes with you.
Just think about it?
At least open it once.
No, Hardik.
Priya.
- Hi, Vikrant.
- Hi.
Happy 18th Miss Mira.
Hi, Mira.
Eat a lot and help out a bit.
She'll like it.
Thank you.
You've no idea
how much I've missed home food.
So what was our school like
back then?
Well...
There were two schools:
one for boys, one for girls.
And we could meet only on Sports Day
and Teacher's Day.
Do you know Teacher's Day?
Seniors become teachers, right?
Yes, this year you will be a teacher.
Mira's going to be the principal.
But you met the boys
only twice a year?
- Well...
- No way.
I can't believe it!
I mean...
some girls did mad things.
Like?
Come on. You have to tell us!
Okay, I can tell you.
But don't get any ideas.
"Mira, don't get any ideas!"
So...
there was this boy who liked me.
And he hid in the girls' garden.
I think he wanted to propose.
But then it rained
and they caught him
and I said no to him.
She's too cool for him.
- You want more lemon rice?
- Yes, a bit more.
Thank you.
So who are you like,
your dad or mom?
I don't know.
My parents do their thing
and I do mine.
My dad might forget
I'm in the 12th grade but...
we're friendly.
Who is this one like?
She thinks she's like her dad.
I think she wants to be like her dad.
No?
Good one, man.
Do you like it?
We got it!
Thank you.
Ma'am?
Pratik, Vikrant and Hardik
have been taking pictures of girls
while they go upstairs.
That's why I insist so much
on the school uniforms.
Can we do something about it?
Best strategy is to just ignore.
Don't give too much attention.
But the younger girls get scared.
Picking a fight can
make it worse for the girls.
Can't be everywhere,
can't supervise 24/7.
What about suspension?
Suspension is serious, Mira.
Thank you.
I'll talk to the principal.
You talk to the girls.
They don't want
these photos circulating.
Right, ma'am.
Thank you so much, ma'am.
Five thousand more.
What? I need to shop.
Also for Mira.
What do you want, Mira?
Books.
Yeah, right!
Did they find Riddhi?
Your cousin ran away with some guy.
The police will find her.
They know he's her music teacher.
- What's the point now?
- What do you mean?
She can't throw away her life like this.
Right?
Did she like the guy?
She's 21.
She doesn't know what she likes.
You also didn't know?
He proposed to me when he was 21.
I also didn't know.
It's a little short.
I should try something bigger?
No, this looks good on you.
- Isn't it the right size for her?
- Yes.
We also have other colors.
See?
Can you see my panty line?
Turn.
You can wear seamless panties.
This cut is good for you.
I'm going to try these capris.
Come, dear.
Come.
Study.
In an hour or so,
I'll bring strawberry milkshake.
Wow!
Keep the door open.
Sit.
Ready to study?
See? I can't focus!
Okay, let me quiz you
and I'll learn from your answers.
Ready?
The first law of...
Mendel!
Mendel's first law of inheritance is
the law of dominance.
Correct.
An example of a dominant trait?
Skin pigmentation and eye color.
Snapdragon or Mirabilis jalapa
flower color exhibits?
Incomplete dominance.
Red-colored flowers
and white-colored flowers
produce pink flowers.
Mirabilis jalapa.
I won't if you don't want me to.
It's not that.
Then?
My breasts...
are a little saggy,
so I'm wearing a push-up bra.
You're perfect the way you are.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
This is good, right?
It is!
I got surprised.
I didn't know.
Do you want to know?
Let's finish the chapter first
and then we can have fun.
Okay.
I'll quiz you.
I think I'll take a break now.
I'll come back
and then we can study the chapter.
And then you can quiz me.
I'm slowing you down.
No, you're not.
Your studies cannot suffer, remember?
We both played badminton.
So we could meet and talk in the bus
going to competitions.
But Harish always fell asleep.
How romantic!
Yeah, we couldn't be seen in public.
My mom would've murdered me
if she found out.
First me and then him.
Where's my milkshake?
In the kitchen.
And when she found out?
She got really angry.
I told her I was going
to marry him and then...
I just left home.
That's so gutsy.
Mira, did you know about this?
She's giving me a look
because I'm supposed to be studying.
I'm not.
- Want more milkshake?
- Yes, please.
You know this song?
Mirabilis!
Tiny steps.
Sorry.
- You see this hand...
- Okay.
Yeah.
Sorry.
Follow my lead.
Mira, put your hand here.
You swing?
Okay move, I'll show you.
Your mom's a pro!
I'll see you
at the parents-teachers' meeting.
Your parents are coming, no?
Bye.
That's Anjali.
She's also a prefect.
- Hi. How are you, dear?
- I'm fine.
Yes, Principal sir.
I'll take care of it.
Don't worry.
What the hell was that,
you've embarrassed me before everyone.
What the hell!
What's going on?
- I don't know.
- Come home, this time my slippers
- will meet your face.
- Is this why you go to school?
Do you come to study
or take photos?
Tell me!
I can never buy
anything for myself,
I spent my whole salary
on your fees.
Nothing to report here.
She's doing wonderfully.
Studies are most important.
Mira?
Priya is always with Vikrant these days.
You must have noticed.
I know, they're friends.
It's hard to discipline friends.
But you have to be fair.
No favorites.
Right, ma'am. I understand.
I talked to her, but she said
they're just friends, so...
It's bad for her.
This boy, you know what he's like.
I mean,
especially him!
Yeah.
I don't want to involve
her parents, it'll become messy.
Right.
You please talk to her.
- Yes?
- Okay, ma'am. I'll talk to her.
- I have your word?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Okay, enjoy your break.
- Thank you, ma'am.
- See you in a week.
- See you, ma'am. Bye-bye.
Wait, go up.
This isn't an exam
you can come first in.
I know.
But I want to be prepared.
I didn't think about it
but females have three orifices.
Me neither.
Hey, put your headphones on.
- Sorry. Porn is a key activity here.
- It's fine.
- You okay?
- Yup.
"The clitoris has thousands
of nerve endings
"and becomes engorged
when aroused."
Do you know the clitoris?
Head Prefect Mira!
I want to learn
about male anatomy.
That's so easy!
We should be learning about condoms.
Yeah, but...
I want to know what to do.
I'm glad we're learning this together.
Me too.
You're going out?
Yes.
Movie with Priya.
Wearing this?
- Harish!
- Just asking.
See all the movies you want
after the exams.
The film is only 3 hours long.
I can't study for 24 hours.
Hey.
Hi, come.
Nice skirt.
I knew you'd appreciate my taste.
Hi, Ani Aunty.
I made dessert for Uncle.
Packed some for you.
- Next week, chicken.
- Thanks.
- Want water?
- No, I'm good.
Hi, Uncle.
Ready?
Yes, she's ready.
I trust you, baby. Have fun.
- Let's go.
- Bye.
- Bye, Papa. See you.
Pri, I think I'll skip the movie.
I haven't studied for bio.
I've to go to Reader's.
Don't be such a bore.
It'll be fun. Just come.
No, Pri.
Everyone is coming.
And Hardik wants to talk to you.
Why?
Because you got them suspended.
I didn't get them suspended.
Principal sir decides that.
They know you went and told Bansal.
What did Hardik do?
Enjoy the movie.
You okay?
I'm good.
Did I do something wrong?
No.
- Was it because I touched you?
- No.
You knew what to do.
Did you practice it somewhere?
I told you about my ex-girlfriend.
Right?
So it was back then?
Yes.
Mira, it was before I knew you.
But in the internet cafe,
you were acting as if
you don't know about things.
And...
You know what to do.
I don't understand.
Why would you lie?
I feel silly.
It's like you were secretly
laughing at me.
I wasn't.
I was having so much fun.
And you were so sweet
with your notes.
But I didn't consciously lie, Mira.
I'm really sorry if it hurt you.
I want to learn how to touch you.
Yeah.
I can show you.
It's very simple.
Hi, Ma.
Do you know the time?
I went to Reader's.
You said 3 hours to your father.
Who all were at the movies?
The usual gang.
Should I call Priya?
Call.
I didn't go to the movie.
Priya invited Hardik and the boys.
And they were angry at me
because I got them suspended.
For what?
They were taking...
inappropriate pictures of girls,
troubling them.
So I reported them.
Then where did you go?
I went to Reader's.
There were new practice tests.
Show me your tests.
I didn't buy them.
I just read them there.
Here.
When Sri comes tomorrow,
study in different rooms.
Okay?
Why?
We really help each other revise.
Mira, if your studies suffer,
your dad will blame me. Not you.
I got full marks in my last test.
You are...
- Can you stop that?
- No, I have a lot of work to do.
Don't use my studies as an excuse!
Don't abuse my trust, Mira.
Put that skort for wash.
You have nothing else to wear?
You...
Torture!
Somebody cut it off.
Sri, dear...
Can you step outside
so I can take my clothes?
Yes.
Actually, no.
Just close your eyes.
Okay.
Now open.
I wanted to revise with him,
I finished a chapter.
Revise on your own.
He said he slept late.
Let him rest.
I'm sorry, I can get up.
No, no. Sleep.
But I'm going to lie down
for some time. Okay?
Switch off the fan.
It wasn't easy back then, so...
If you were together,
you got married.
There was no concept of break-up.
Would've been terrible
if I'd married my first girlfriend.
Why?
She liked me, but she liked mostly
that I paid for stuff.
Good that you broke up then.
When you're young,
it's just puppy love.
I mean, it doesn't last.
Then what? Nothing, no romance.
Hi.
Did we disturb you?
Your mom's imparting her
wisdom on romance.
She's an expert, you know!
It's because of these.
- Okay, let's see.
- Stop it!
"Cassandra looks at Brandon.
His smoldering eyes burn into her."
"Make her knees go weak."
- "He looks so good in that suit."
- Enough!
I need to know what happens
to those smoldering eyes.
- I'll gift it to you. Birthday gift.
- Gift it to Harish.
Good idea.
You bought this trash
with his money.
Do you want tea?
- Always.
- Come.
Are your parents going to come
for your birthday?
No, they have to go to Hong Kong.
Here, less sugar.
Thank you.
Wow, you've added cardamom too.
So what do you want to do
for your birthday?
I just don't want to stay
in the hostel.
Hi.
I have an idea.
Let's go to our mountain
for a little pre-birthday celebration?
I love you.
Maybe it's puppy love...
maybe it's big-dog love.
Sri!
Wait.
Come.
- Hi.
Listen to this.
I'll finish quickly
and meet you at the gate?
- For what?
- Just meet me at the gate.
Pri? Can I talk to you
for a minute?
- What happened?
- Come.
- So...
- What's wrong?
Teachers have noticed
you're spending a lot of time
with Vikrant these days.
You're reporting me?
No, I'm just letting you know
so that they don't tell your mom.
Bansy should mind her own business.
Don't hang out
with him so much.
He's not the right person.
I'm doing nothing wrong!
That's why it's all out in the open.
What about you and that boy Sri?
When were you going to tell me?
What?
Mira, I have eyes.
Why don't you tell Bansy about that?
What should I do?
Don't worry about it.
We'll handle it.
She is crossing her limits now.
Keep it quiet, okay.
Hi, Mira.
You know your mom just saved me.
I'm here for you, you know that?
I do, Anila.
I'll make some tea.
Are you hungry?
We also tried on
my Teacher's Day outfit.
I waited for you.
You saw Ms. Bansal...
I figured it would be safest
to meet here.
Did you listen to the tape?
I didn't have my Walkman.
But I'll listen to it tonight.
Will you tell me what you said?
Listen to it.
How was class?
What were you talking about?
To Anila? Just...
some money stuff.
And about my parents.
Nothing important.
You don't want to talk to me?
Mira, it's not...
Of course I do.
I needed help and it's easier
to talk to your mom about some things.
I'm sure she loves it!
Why are you being so mean to her?
She's doing all this just for you.
She's trying so hard
to be a good mom.
You seem to know a lot about her.
I'm just saying...
that it's good
if she feels liked and appreciated.
That's how we get to meet
and the only way we get to meet.
You being rude is not going to help us.
And about the tape, I'm sorry.
I'll listen to it tonight.
Tea's ready.
Come in.
Promise, okay?
Come.
Hello?-Hello?
I'm calling to authorize
a night-out for Srinivas from...
Veer.
From Veer House tomorrow.
- For what reason?
- It's his birthday.
- Who are you?
- His aunt.
Okay, please hold.
Make a wish.
Happy birthday!
Happy 19th!
Get ready for a nighttime visitor.
What?
Terrace.
This is not comfy at all.
You'll get a backache.
I'm used to the hostel rooms.
I can sleep anywhere.
Sleep in Mira's room,
she can sleep in mine.
There's enough beds for everyone.
No, Mira should have her room.
The sofa is great, honestly.
I can't sleep with you, you snore.
- Don't exaggerate. It's not that bad.
- It is.
In that train, you were very loud.
You can handle it for one night.
I have a test tomorrow.
Mira!
I'm not going to, Ma.
Well then,
Sri, you can sleep in my bedroom
and the princess can sleep in hers.
Anila, I don't think
that's necessary.
I think it's for the best.
We have to wake up at five to study.
We'll disturb you,
it's best if he's here.
I'll also wake up.
I'll make you tea.
Don't you think it's weird?
Why?
You've napped there before, no?
And the bed is comfortable, right?
Okay, come. Take your stuff.
Get up.
Come.
Wake me at five, no matter what.
We'll go to the terrace.
- Is this side okay for you?
- Yes.
Good night.
What is it?
- Leave it open.
- Why?
So that I can wake him up.
You can knock.
You think I don't see what's going on?
Sri...
It's five.
Wake up.
You wanted to revise, no?
30 minutes.
Okay, I'll come at 5:30.
It's 5:30. Wake up!
- Already?
- Yes.
Give me 15 minutes. I'll come.
Come on, it's past six.
Get up!
Softer, please.
I can't keep coming to wake you up.
I have to study.
- You study.
- Sri!
Let him be.
You said, "Wake me, no matter what."
You go. I'll come.
Omelet.
- Where's Mira?
- She's outside.
Hi.
Mira, I'm really sorry.
I was so tired,
I couldn't open my eyes.
Your mom was talking to me.
It got so late...
Should I get on top?
Mira.
It's not that I'm not turned on.
I definitely am.
Just a second.
Keep going.
87 out of 100.
Not even close.
77.
Ma'am, can you help me
drape my sari?
Yes, ma'am.
- Mom's sari?
- Yes, ma'am.
Very elegant.
I've never seen your mom
wear a sari.
Turn around.
- Hi, Ani Aunty!
- Hi!
Looking nice.
Turn around again.
Mira, I brought your jewelry.
Put it there.
I can take it from here.
You can relax.
- That's not a problem.
- We already started it.
Don't make her work on Teacher's Day.
We practiced a drape at home.
I'll go help the others.
Tell me if you need something.
Like we tried?
- Tight pleats.
- No need to do that.
Here, let me put it for you.
- Give.
- I'll put it.
- Give it to me.
- Give it to me!
- I'll do it.
I will do it.
- Sorry.
- Go away!
Here.
Bye, I'll see you later.
Look at this girl. All grown up!
- Happy Teacher's Day.
- Thank you.
Beautiful earrings! Coming?
- They're starting some games.
- Yes, coming.
Sri?
I have your blazer.
- Thank you. See you soon.
- Yeah.
Your mother is friendly
with Srinivas?
She's friendly with everyone.
You're friends with him, too?
It's important to have friends
who have similar goals.
And...
These are your keys for the day,
Miss Principal.
Thank you, ma'am.
I'll see you later.
Classes, attention!
At ease!
Miss Principal will say some words.
She's going to speak now.
Hi.
Today, we honor our teachers
and do their work.
So enjoy your day
and listen to your teachers.
Now, the school pledge.
- Anybody wants to come up?
- Nobody will go up!
No.
Miss Principal will do the pledge.
Nice one, Hardik!
Alright. I'm still a student.
So please repeat the pledge after me.
Yeah, sure!
As a student of my school,
I pledge to honor...
Who the hell was that?
Shut up.
...our age-old Indian culture
and live according to it.
Kids in the front, shut up!
Come on.
It shall be my constant endeavor...
Now she knows who's the boss!
It's done. Let's leave, guys.
Boo!
Everyone, leave!
That was fun.
Where will you run?
Miss Principal, bye!
She left?
Well played.
Where are you off to, Princy?
Mira.
Nobody saw me coming.
I checked.
You alright?
Those guys are idiots.
Who the fuck cares about them?
I know you don't care.
You didn't say the pledge.
You know I never say it.
If pledging would've fixed things,
I would've.
Mira...
I don't want to go down.
I'll get you the rooftop keys.
From where?
Bansal.
I won't tell her it's for you.
- She won't give them to you.
- She will.
Why?
Because people also have keys
and Bansal's not that complicated.
See you soon.
There she is.
We have spotted the principal.
Come on.
Principal!
Let's mess with her.
Principal,
we're ready to say the pledge.
"As a student of my school..."
"To abide by the rules," right?
Where's she going?
Mira!
Principal, why are you rushing?
Hey, wimp!
- There she is!
- Let's go.
- Mira!
- Got me suspended, huh?
- Why are you running?
- Wait!
Boys, run!
Boys, she's running to the girls' dorm!
Mira, wait!
Catch her before she goes inside!
Hardik, don't go in.
Listen, hey!
Hey!
Listen to me.
I want to talk to you.
I just want to talk to you.
I know everything about you
and your astronomy. Bitch!
Open or I'll break the door!
Now you're scared!
You've broken my bro's heart.
I'll show you
what you're worth!
Ma! Can you come pick me up?-What happened, Mira?
Come fast.
- Where? At the gate?
- In the girls' dorm.
- Okay, I'm coming.
- Okay.
Call your astronomer!
Answer, bitch!
Or are you too scared?
What a fucking slut, man!
Stop hiding, coward!
We're not going anywhere.
What are you boys doing here?
You're not supposed to be here.
What's going on?
Where's Mira?
- What?
- Mira and that NRI boy, Sri.
What about them?
Ask her, you will know.
Tell me what's going on.
I want to know why you boys are here.
Can't even tell you ma'am,
imagine the worst,
can't even say it.
What the hell!
- What the fuck, Priya!
- What?
What were you doing?
Has this boy Sri
been coming to your place?
- No.
- Mira...
I know you very well.
Don't lie to me.
Ma'am, Hardik proposed to me.
I said no, and this is how
he's taking his revenge.
Yeah, coming.
Just a minute.
What happened?
They chased me.
I want to go home.
- You okay?
- I want to go home.
Okay.
- Who chased you?
- The boys outside. They're still there.
Mira has complained
about them before.
They were even suspended.
This is a separate matter.
They think that Mira
and this boy Srinivas...
- I think you know him?
- Yeah.
They say that...
Mira has been quite inappropriate.
- How so?
- Having relations with Sri.
And you believe these rumors?
I wanted to talk to her.
If it were true,
then it would mean expulsion.
Those boys are hooligans.
Mira's been the top student
here since years.
She's the Head Prefect.
How are you trusting them over her?
Her performance dipped
in the last tests.
In one test!
She was sick.
It seems that this with Sri
has been going on for a while.
- And he's been coming to your place.
- So?
I decide who comes to my home.
Anyway, thank you.
Come, Mira. Let's go.
Get up.
Hi, Anila.
How are you?
- You okay?
- Yes, I'm okay.
Come.
I did come back to the rooftop
but you had already left by then.
I did get you the rooftop keys.
- From Miss Bansal?
- I told you.
What did you tell her?
Just that I wanted to teach
a class on the terrace and...
how she's the only teacher
I learnt anything from.
Is it true?
No.
But...
she likes hearing that.
So you just said it like that?
You didn't mean it?
No.
What do you mean when you say,
"People also have keys"?
Sometimes it's an actual rooftop key.
But when you said it that day,
what did you mean?
It's just understanding
how people work,
what they really want.
What about me?
- Do I have a key?
- You do.
What is it?
No bullshit. That's your key.
It's a good one.
I also want to know this key thing.
What is it?
Nothing.
What's my key?
You really like it
when I enjoy your food. Right?
That's my key?
I think so.
Food?
What? You asked me to eat a lot.
I have been doing that.
No bullshit.
What is it?
Tell me the truth.
You know her...
She needs attention.
That works in our favor though.
So you're using her?
No! But that's how we get to meet.
Come on, Mira.
It's nothing you don't know.
Can I come back next week?
You want oil?
Mira!
Sorry, sorry!
Hold this.
Oil will come on your face.