You know when the carpaccio's
just an hour past its prime?
It's not off but it's tired.
Yeah.
Yeah, well, that pretty much
set the tone for the whole meal,
right up to the catastrophe
they call the tiramisu.
Well, Morley's has always been crap.
You know how bad it is.
We used to go there
for children's birthday parties.
Yeah. Well,
you chose to have kids.
2WE!
And I'm joined in the studio
by State Attorney-General
Joe Sandilands.
My first question to you,
Attorney-General, is
are you a complete moron?
Um... And, er,
hello to you too, Eddie.
Because that does seem to be
the prevailing mood out there
in our city of fear.
This government seems unwilling
to bridle the escalating
ethnic gang violence.
Asian, Muslim youths
are terrorising our streets.
Well, that is clearly untrue, Eddie.
Let's talk about Mary Drouin.
OK.
An innocent young Australian girl
gang-raped by Muslim youths
in broad daylight.
I visited Mary just this week
in hospital,
and she is suffering extensive
bruising, external and internal,
some of which will last a lifetime.
No, well, this is...
It's not just Mary Drouin, is it?
Four other young Australian women
have been raped in this one suburb
in this last 4-month period alone.
Still no arrests.
Well, if I could just get a word in.
Yeah, but words are all we get.
I see you call for calm,
but that's all we see you doing.
And we're not calm, we are angry
because this government has turned
suburbs like Cabramatta and Lakemba
into safe havens for baby Taliban.
What? I beg your pardon!
When was the last time you walked
the streets of these suburbs?
When was the last time
YOU did, Eddie?
Well, I don't think a Western woman
would really feel safe
in those areas
without a full burqa on.
I wouldn't go down there
without a .22 automatic.
But given that I'm not allowed to
defend myself in such a manner,
I have to rely on my
government.
If you would just give me a chance
to answer, Eddie, I'd...
But honestly, I mean, if I was a
young man with a sister or a mother
or, God forbid,
an adolescent daughter,
I know what I'd be doing.
Eddie, look, that is
completely inappropriate.
You have made this war.
You are forcing brave young people
to take up cudgels,
to go into these areas and to
take the law into their own hands —
and who can blame them, really —
calling “No more Mary Drouins!”
This jihad against Australian women
must stop one way or another
right now.
Now, you are advocating
vigilantism here.
Thank you, Attorney-General.
And that was
Attorney-General Joe Sandilands,
once again...
..unable to shed any light
on our streets of fear.
- Oi!
- Had it from this guy!
Oi, you, you fucking dogs!
Who the fuck is that?!
You wanna go? I wanna stay.
Come on! Come on!
Who the fuck are they?
Come on!
Who cares, hey?
You're listening to Eddie
Longhorn, Drivetime, 2WE, 9:66am.
Just go, go, go!
You!
Run!
Straighten it out. Oi!
Oil
MAN: Go on, bro!
23-29 to base, we need
an ambulance here right away.
http://hiqve.com/
Who's Warwick Torrens?
He is the Director
of Public Prosecutions.
Why do you ask?
He called.
What did he want?
Hmm, my guess is
he wanted to speak to you.
Hey!
You slept here, didn't you?
That depends. Where is here?
You are due in court.
Harry-sorry-David and the tax office
await the pleasure of your company.
Yes, I'm onto it.
So you know Darver's
coming back tomorrow.
We have to vacate his room.
Is Darver giving up smoking?
I've gotta get to Ali, fast.
Hey, that is Darver's gown.
Morning!
How is the, er... How's the family?
Oh, hello.
Er, Edwina Langhorn?
For God's sake, call me Eddie.
What's up?
Er, we've got orders to place you
under arrest, if that's alright.
Yeah, um...
Really?!
Well, I guess there must be
a charge of some kind.
Oh, er, right, yeah.
The charge.
Um, sorry. Er, causing a riot,
um, inciting racial vilification.
Oh, dear, I have been busy.
There's, er, no need for handcuffs.
We'll just head on out.
Oh, no, no, no, I insist. I wouldn't
like you to get into any trouble.
Right, OK.
Just mind the Rolex.
Sure.
Why are you still
bloody doing legal work
when you've got a campaign to run?
It's my very last case, I promise.
Mate, the party's smiling on you —
smiles all around,
happy smiling faces —
but there's still
a couple of frowns, alright.
Some people who don't think
you've got the ticker.
Yes, I know, but this is a case I've
been handling for nearly two years.
It should wind up today.
Alright.
Well, the electorate needs
to see you at the coalface
right up till election day, alright?
Ah, here we go.
Nothing you can do
can ever make up for this.
Alright, now, you make sure
you're back in time
for the under-18s netball final,
alright?
They're daughters of
Greeks and Italians.
We are knee-deep
in a racist shit storm
courtesy of the rabid Ms Langhorn.
It is vital that
we be seen publicly
with some of your, er, less
controversial ethnic groups, OK?
Is it necessary to do it,
dancing in these hats?
We'd do it in nappies
if it'd win votes.
Yep, stick it in the boot, Ali.
In the boot.
Good, eh? Half yoghurt, cat piss.
Old village trick.
Good on ya. Thanks, Ali. Good, mate.
Anytime, anytime.
Yeah, see ya.
Right, let's go, Reg.
Your Honour, this matter
has dragged on for 22 months
in which time Mr Greene
has failed to produce
one shred of documentary evidence.
We again submit
that Mr Greene be required
to produce the documents under
subpoena or be held in contempt.
Yes. Mr Greene?
Cometh the hour, cometh the man.
Er, I...
Oh, shit. Er...
Er, I agree, Your Honour.
Um, er, this thing has
dragged on way too long.
Um, I'm as anxious as anyone
to put it right,
which is why I'm very happy to say
I can now lay this matter to rest.
I have the documents with me.
As has been established, Your Honour,
er, my financial records
were severely storm damaged,
um, but I have managed to track down,
er, almost all the relevant
surviving papers.
According to the subpoena,
Your Honour,
I was required to produce financial
records for the years 2004...
...er, 2005.
Very difficult to make copies
of these, Your Honour.
God! What is that smell?
We're not entirely sure,
Your Honour. It's possibly rat urine.
They were very badly damaged.
Get them out of here!
Your Honour, we can have this matter
dealt with within a couple of hours.
Look, get them out! How dare you
bring that into my court!
I wasn't aware that they actually
smelt as bad as that, Your Honour.
I have a deviated septum.
I think we may guess how you got it.
Mr Greene, you are in contempt.
Remove this man from my court
and place him in remand.
How dare you mock this place?!
Er, mate, do you mind if I...
Oh, yeah, mate.
Thanks.
Er, Lily, listen, you've caught me
at a rather awkward time.
When isn't it
an awkward time for you?
How is every little thing,
big sister?
Dad's had a stroke.
He's in hospital.
Is he alright?
He's doing Latin dancing
as we speak.
I really just rang
to hear your voice.
I mean is he gonna live?
Here's a crazy suggestion —
why not drive up here and find out?
Alright, look, I-I'm gonna be a little tied
up for the next couple of days, OK,
but I'll try and get up there
on the weekend.
Yeah, well, you do that and I'll
tell him not to die before then.
Oh, yes, yes,
keep the good times rolling.
Gentlemen.
Cleave?
Nab. How are ya?
What are you here for?
Oh, you know, mate, nip and tuck,
bit of lipo.
Bucket, how are ya?
Give us some room there, Tuvo.
How are you?
Take the weight off, eh?
How you going? Alright?
This morning at 10:15am
we arrested Eddie Langhorn.
Thought that'd get your attention.
No, Warwick, I was just intrigued
by the way you said 10:15am
as if the time of day mattered.
Look, if this is about
her Joe Sandilands diatribe,
I'm not sure that it'll stick.
Well, she seriously overstepped
this time.
There was a riot, people got hurt.
In any event, I've heard you
bitch about her so often,
I'm reasonably confident
you'll be putting your back into it.
Hmph, more than my back.
This isn't about liking or hating.
Oh, yes, itis.
Someone's here to see you, Cleave.
I take it Harry-sorry-David
told you of my change of address.
Well, it was spectacular,
even by your standards.
It even rivals
your nude fountain display.
You shouldn't have come here,
sweet Missy.
I wanted to see that you were OK.
Well, as you can see,
a Rembrandt portrait.
More like a Jackson Pollock.
You're doing coke again, aren't you?
No.
You know you can't handle it.
My old man's knocking on
the Pearlies, apparently,
but the spawn of his loins
is doing just fine, thank you.
Why are you here?
Because you matter to me.
I thought Harry-sorry-David Potter
mattered to you.
How is our little magician,
by the way?
Cleaver, don't start.
He's gonna pop the question
any day now, you know that?
People like Harry
have got life plans.
For God's sake.
You should be at home sorting out
quotes for your wedding napkins
instead of visiting old Cleave
in the slammer.
You're 1,000 light years
away from Earth, aren't you?
‘May we walk our separate but
unique paths and always together.”
That's what Barney and Scarlet
had on their napkins.
Well, you shat all over
those napkins, didn't you?
Listen, maybe it's good
that you're in here.
You can straighten yourself out.
Ah! The corkscrew
calls me bent, does she?
You're right —
I shouldn't have come.
You know, you're gonna die
if you keep this up.
Hello! It's just me. I came to pick
up a file. We don't have to speak.
Who the hell are you?
Scarlet, right?
I'm Sylvia. Adam's home from school.
He's got a fever.
Didn't Barney tell you?
How dare you parade a strange woman
in front of my children
without consulting me first?
If this is Sylvia, the kids have
met her and they like her.
You should have called me
the moment he got sick
before pulling in some mystery shag
to help bail you out.
There is a protocol to
this sort of thing, you know.
Well, you've waived all rights
to talk protocol.
Those are my children
and I won't have that slag near them!
Never speak about Sylvia
like that again.
She's wonderful.
I have to tell you that
the sex is brilliant.
Well, I'm pleased for you.
Genuinely.
You know, I have moved on
with my life too
and I have never felt more content.
But next time, you call Natalie.
She's in Melbourne, remember?
Well, just get my mother!
So she can give Adam another
4-hour lecture on the Holocaust?
It's our people's history.
Will you just call next time?!
Whether we're together or not,
we still co-parent.
Sister.
I've SMS'ed you the hospital
details. You'd better come.
He keeps asking for you.
I need your car for the weekend
to visit my dad.
I will pay and I'll get it back
Sunday night, alright?
You've only got this room
for six weeks.
That's a no to the car?
Bravo, Cleaver, your family
must be very proud.
He only speaks in sarcasm, you know.
Your little stunt in court
finally sounds the death knell
on one very shabby career.
The conduct committee
will have no choice this time.
Not in the mood, mate.
Oh, do forgive me.
I've had a shit of a day and
my old man might be on his way out.
Oh, please! The dying father?!
You have no moral compass, do you?
Nicole!
Tolga Urdan, man or woman?
Does it matter?
I'm not expressing just my views
here or the views of the NSW Bar!
You have no ethical core,
you're a borderline sociopath
and a disgrace to the profession.
Hello, Cleave.
Why me?
Your station can afford
a chorus line of silks.
I know you.
Yes, you do at that.
Well, you must know that
I don't agree with
a single opinion you express.
I know what I said caused a fuss.
No, no, a fuss
is when you fart in a lift.
Several people hospitalised,
a kid on life support.
A girl was gang-raped in
broad daylight and no charges laid.
I have every right to question
this government's piss-weak stance.
There's a line between questioning
a stance and inciting a race riot, Ed.
It was quite a rant.
Yeah, it was, wasn't it?
So, are you going to rescue
a damsel in distress?
No. No!
Cleave, don't be like this.
Come on, just give it a try.
It'll be fun.
I can't!
These are my people. Don't you...
Look, Tolga and his family.
That girl there, I'm godfather to that girl.
I'm actually running late
for something. I've gotta fly.
See you later, Ed.
Cleave.
Eddie! Eddie! Eddie!
How did they know to come here?
I didn't know I had an office
until 38 minutes ago.
Welcome to my life.
Yeah, yeah. Alright, alright.
Thank you. I will make just
one short statement.
When my right to express an opinion
sees me handcuffed
and dragged from my family home,
this is not the country that
my family raised me to love.
Our streets are not safe,
nor are our suburbs,
nor even our beloved beaches.
We must take pause and ask ourselves
what's happened to this country?
May I add something?
Of course.
Can anyone here lend me a car
for the weekend?
Nothing alcoholic,
nothing up the nose.
Yes, alright, get off my back.
You know what I mean — he slips up
once and you call me.
I don't wanna go with him!
Why am I being subjected to this?
He has got a point. The man
was unbearable when he was well.
I always thought he was sweet.
That's because
he's good at faking it.
Well, he's his grandfather
and death should have some meaning.
And I want you to talk to him
about Vampira.
He hasn't spoken to me
since I kicked her out of my place.
Well, he's still seeing her.
The tissue box is full,
there are no stains on the sheets,
he's not doing it to himself,
he's getting it.
You do realise what you just said
is a little creepy, don't you?
I don't think you can
talk to me about creepy.
I see you're defending the gorgon.
No, I'm not. I said no.
Just you wait.
I haven't seen her in over 10 years.
And the last time you did,
she ruined our marriage.
No, I did that all by myself.
Just talk to him! It's the only
reason I'm lending you the car.
You do still have a licence,
don't you?
Fuzz.
Mate, it can't be...
can't be good for you, listening...
Oh, well, this is bloody riveting.
Dad.
Hi.
Hi, Pop. It's Fuzz.
How are you in there?
B-better for seeing you.
OK, that's it. Come on, let's go.
Did he say anything, Fuzzy?
He said he was better for seeing us.
Oh, hello, handsome.
Hey, Aunty Jane.
Mwah.
Oh, it's you.
I'll drop by the hospital again
in about half an hour.
OK.
Did HE go?
Yeah, he did.
HE's here too, you know. You can
talk DIRECTLY to him if you like.
That'd be a waste of breath,
wouldn't it?
Can we please not start?
You haven't see much
of your grandad, have you?
No, not for a while.
He's a great bloke.
He'd take you fishing, talk
your ear off about rugby league.
Yeah, great bloke if you never
had to live with him, that is.
Your father's twisted.
You stay living with your mum.
Just because he didn't lay into you
doesn't make what happened to me
any more acceptable.
What exactly do you think
he did to you, Cleave?
Does it have to be like
Christmas Day every time?
No, it doesn't.
Let's finish this cup of tea
and this fuck-awful fruitcake
and get out of your hair, alright.
I've done my bit.
You sat in the hospital room
for two minutes.
We've been there
every day for weeks.
Grandad had such high hopes
for your father.
“You watch our Cleaver.” So sad.
How's your handicrafts store, Jane?
Please Bob In.
Oh, no, that's right, you went broke.
Who would have picked that, huh?
You'll spend time defending
that cow Eddie Langhorn.
What?
Yep, we saw your photo.
But you won't give any time to
the man who devoted his life to you.
Who says I'm defending her?
What, are we in the middle
of a Susan Sarandon movie here?
Alright, mate, you want the facts?
He had a giant leather strap
and he used to lay into me with it
and he'd leave welts
all up and down my body.
- Once.
- ONCE!
And that was after
you tried to burn the school down.
The whole town
wanted you bloody lynched.
He was always laying into me.
Did you burn down your school?
No!
One classroom. A demountable.
On principle.
He always had to be
the centre of attention —
find some stupid busted cause
and put himself...
I never had a proper relationship
with the man and you know it.
Not like you two.
“Oh, Dad, Thommo's bowling,
can we go?”
Cricket bored him rigid
but he'd still take you
to all the Sydney Tests.
It wasn't the only time
he belted me, you know, mate.
Problem was
he didn't belt you enough.
Oh, I'm sorry you have
such a gobsmackingly dull life
with lan the Rotarian
and his porcelain cat memorabilia.
But why would I bother making it up
if it wasn't true?
I don't know, Cleave. Maybe you
have to work that one out yourself.
Here, Fuzzy,
have a browse of these.
Tell me if any of these snaps equate
with your father's TRAGIC world view.
And I spent three hours
cooking you that fruitcake.
Mum ever talk to you about
the female menopause, mate?
Right.
Do you wanna ignore me?
Do you wanna dump me too?
Go ahead, get out.
I mean it! I am sick of people
passing judgment on me!
You don't wanna talk to me,
there's the door.
Fuzz.
Fuzz!
Why am I copping shit for this?
What, your mum chases the woman
down the street.
She calls her Vampira to her face.
Mum's always done stuff like that.
She's allowed to, I'm used to it.
But you rock up once a week
and pretend to be
this cool, anything-goes guy
and in reality
you're just a bloody fascist!
I don't remember Hitler
expressing an opinion
about sons rooting
their English teachers.
I can handle you being a shit dad
because I always thought
you were my mate.
We are mates, Fuzz.
We have such great times, mate.
What about Souths games
and...and skiing last year?
You spent the whole time
shagging the ski instructress!
Oh, yeah, alright,
not a good example, but, mate...
Why don't you understand
how much I love her?!
Fuzz, mate, can we not
hate each other, please?
It's all gonna end in a single bed
in some Dickensian hospital
breaking wind
and pissing into silverware.
Dad...
I fucking love you, Fuzz.
I would take a bullet for you, mate.
Dad!
Wendy, will you calm down?
It's largely superficial.
Look, I...I will pay.
I'm good for it.
No, it's just...l...
Did Pop really take you
to see the cricket?
You always said
it was a girls' game.
I was unsure of my sexuality.
I rang again on July 9.
Er, correction. 10.
And then again on the 16th.
As I say, Elspeth, this is more
of a council matter than...
On August 2, I wrote
the Prime Minister.
Again, the Prime Minister
is federal.
I'm standing for State Parliament.
So, you'll do nothing, then?
No.
On the contrary,
I will be writing to council
and putting considerable pressure
on them
to act on this, er, grave matter
of...of the...
Weekly collection of garden waste.
Yes.
He's all piss and wind, darling.
But I like you.
OK, I think I can
swing my block for you.
I should have known when you said
“Pick a restaurant,”
you'd be a little uncomfortable
with Lebbo.
Assallam aleikum.
Wa aleikum sallam.
Mmm.
Just wish you'd told me it was so
casual. I feel a little overdressed.
She's not Lebanese, by the way,
she's Egyptian.
She'd be very offended
if you call her a Lebbo.
I was thinking about
our last time together.
Oh, that weekend in Pretty Beach.
Yeah.
Mmm.
I distinctly remember you being
pro-native title, anti-mining
and saying that you thought
Paul Keating was
the most admirable man alive.
I said no such thing.
You did.
No, you're thinking
of Etta Greenburg. Ugh.
Really?
Mmm-hmm.
So, Ed, this shit you talk on air,
you really believe it?
Oh, absolutely.
Except maybe the weather.
Thank you.
I'm glad you came.
I need you.
Right. I remember the last time
you said that.
Just...will you hear me out, please?
Look, Ed, you do know, don't you,
that of those five rapes,
only your girl Mary Drouin
is dead certain it was a Muslim gang
and only two of the four other girls
even mentioned the word ‘Muslim'
in their statements.
Where did you hear that?
I've got friends in low places.
Five rapes, four months, one suburb.
Come on, Cleave,
it's gotta be the same gang.
No, it doesn't! It doesn't
have to be anything.
It just suits you if it's that way,
suits you to be able to
sling the words ‘Muslim', ‘gang'
and ‘rape' together on air
because it gets your demographic
all fired up, doesn't it?
Gets the blood boiling. “Yeah, yeah,
too right! Bloody towelheads.”
Have you ever been
to an Islamic country, Cleave?
Oh, don't start this shit.
Some of the most beautiful, erudite
people I have ever met
are Muslim women.
But their men, their men think
women are second-class citizens.
Not only do they think we should
neither be seen nor heard,
they think we should
be able to be traded
for two goats
and a diesel generator.
Are you really OK
about those attitudes
being imported into this country?
Well, I'm just thinking about
that diesel generator.
Right. Clitoral circumcision.
Oh, hello.
It's been outlawed in this country
for 15 years
but some fathers defend it
as a cultural right,
despite the fact that
they have sworn an oath
to obey the laws of our country.
How can mutilating your daughter
be a cultural right?
And the people that could stop it,
the people that could
enforce the laws,
men in power like Joe Sandilands,
they run a million miles
in the opposite direction
because they're too
politically correct to offend
and they're beholden
to their party room hacks
that won't alienate
their multicultural electorates.
Ed, Jewish women aren't allowed to
sit with their menfolk in synagogues.
They're not allowed to pray at the
Wailing Wall. What's that all about?
..smallest percentage
of practising Jews!
And of course my dear old beloved
Catholic Church has really been at...
Well, the Catholics are fucked...
..forefront of feminist thinking.
The same day that
I spoke to Joe Sandilands
three other jocks made the same
call to arms and no charges laid.
Why? Card.
Because they're inside the tent.
And Joe Sandilands
is scared shitless of them.
I can make a difference.
I can beat these boofheads.
I just have to get inside the tent.
Why do you have to
go camping with them at all?
Because I always liked a good fire.
Eddie, I'm such a fan.
It's so great to meet you.
Well, thanks for coming down. Did
you hear me on the radio last night?
Look, you must know
by now she's the devil.
Come on, Red, democracy's built
on the inalienable right
to express moronic opinions.
Except she isn't a moron,
she's the devil.
That is what the devil looks like,
that is what the devil sounds like.
She hasn't broken the law.
The devil never does.
All she has to do is sow doubt.
Doubt leads to fear,
fear leads to discord,
discord leads to some poor kid being
hit on the head with a baseball bat.
She got up Joe's nasal chambers.
She opened a debate.
Any passionately held opinion's
gonna cause conflict.
Choose a god, choose a footy team,
back a politician,
you're now a part
of the great divide.
Should Israel build settlements in
the Occupied Territories?
Oh, please! Let's not pretend
this is about freedom of speech.
No, she's a performing seal
for the politically powerless.
You really don't like her, do you?
Within two hours
of Ms Langhorn's diatribe,
seven separate incidents broke out
in south-western Sydney.
Eight people were injured,
one teenage boy seriously so.
The defence will argue
that she did not intend this.
But Ms Langhorn is
a highly intelligent woman
with Arts/Law degrees
from Melbourne University
and a masters from
the Columbia School of Journalism.
There is no doubt that she knew
precisely the parameters
of the law that she was breaking.
Edwina Langhorn
is a human starting gun.
And we will prove it.
Mr Elliott, you have been convicted
of causing grievous bodily harm.
What prompted you to go out and
beat up a group of total strangers?
It's a bloody war out there,
and she gets that.
I mean, none of you lot live
where I come from.
You don't hear them yelling at us
from cars, spitting on us,
hitting our women.
If we don't fight back,
then we're losing who we are.
Oh, that would be a pity indeed.
If you hadn't have listened
to Ms Langhorn's broadcast,
would have you still gone out and
attacked these people, do you think?
Dunno.
What does the word ‘prevailing' mean?
Not sure.
What about ‘bridle'?
To get married?
Er, yes.
But as in “to bridle a horse”.
What does that mean?
To marry one?
OK.
Er, what about ‘causal'?
When you don't have to wear a suit.
Right, so not the sort of clothes
you'd wear to marry a horse?
Your Honour!
Your Honour, these were all words
used by Eddie Langhorn
in her broadcast.
Mr Elliott doesn't seem to know
the meaning of any of them,
which does beg the question
did he understand a single word my
client was saying in her broadcast?
Thank you, Your Honour.
What in the blue blazes is this?
Er, livestock of some description?
No, no, it's a human organ, isn't it?
I'm pretty sure it's an animal.
Where was the town where your
parents renewed their wedding vows?
Pardon? Where they...?
Renewed their wedding vows.
San Gimignano.
I thought that's what you said.
Just think, some poor bloody idiot
has wasted nine months of their life
gluing bits of blue and yellow
ceramic onto lycra,
and no-one can tell me what it is.
Got second prize.
I see our camel has caught your eye.
A camel!
Local girl. Julia Robinga.
Lives just two streets away.
All local artists.
Well, there you go, Dave,
so much talent in just
the one little electorate, eh?
Bob Menzies. Named after
our famous prime minister?
No, after a car dealer from Moorang.
You're 2WE's general manager.
What sort of asset has Edwina
Langhorn been to your station?
Oh, she's a cracker.
Smart, hard-working, tough.
No airs and graces.
I mean, not too many women
could move from print into radio
but she goes it toe to toe
with any of the boys.
And your revenue from
her Drivetime slot?
Increased by over 120%.
I read a report
in the ‘Financial Review'
that Ted Gorman,
your King of Breakfast,
has hinted that he might be leaving
at the start of next year.
That must be of huge concern.
Oh, well, Ted's
a once-in-a-generation talent.
And would you think of Ms Langhorn
as a possible replacement?
Eddie's hat will be
one of several in the ring.
Oh, so I suppose anything that
heightened her profile
or improved her demographic
would be of enormous benefit
in securing that show?
Eddie's been banging on about
this Mary Drouin case
long before Ted
made his announcement,
if that's what you're insinuating.
Yes, but Ted Gorman announces
his departure on July 1.
And on July 8,
Ms Langhorn goes ballistic
and her photograph ends up
on the front page of every paper.
And you, as the 17-year operator
of one of Australia's
most profitable radio networks
really see no correlation
between those events?
No, I don't.
Well, why didn't you tell me about
Ted Gorman leaving?
How could you not know?
What rock have you been living under?
The rock that doesn't listen
to your fucking radio station.
You are the worst kind of snob.
I don't appreciate
you humiliating my listeners.
Who would that be?
The boy in the stands.
You were rough on him.
What, the boy who used a baseball bat
on somebody's head?
Look, if he hasn't had the benefit
of a decent education,
if he is genuinely concerned about
the future direction of his country,
then I am proud
to speak on his behalf.
You of all people
should understand that, Cleave.
How many AVO applications have you
successfully defended?
Oh, don't start this shit.
No!
Women living in fear of being
assaulted, raped and murdered
but you represent those men.
Yeah, yeah.
Why? Why?
Because somebody's got to.
That's what a defence lawyer does.
We're both just advocates for hire.
We're two sides of the same coin.
Don't you think it's about time
you....grew up and worked that out?
You're killing me.
RED!
Red, what are you doing?
What are you doing?
Is Venus to the left or right
of the Southern Cross?
Red, come on.
Do you know?
Red, come on, sweetheart,
we've gotta go.
You see, Barney knows.
Yeah, on a clear night,
he...he takes the kids out
and he talks to them
about the stars.
I don't know, I think
it's one of those low ones.
Barn.
Scarlet was attacked last night.
What? Is she alright?
Yeah, yeah, she's fine.
It was just a bunch of thugs who
wanted to scare the shit out of her.
Why? What did they want?
Nothing, as far as she could tell.
Is this your client's work?
Eddie isn't like that.
Sympathy for the devil, is it?
Go do your job.
Here's what I think we should do.
No seconds. I have a lecture.
After the election
and before I get sworn in,
I think we should go to Italy.
You're kidding!
The full deal —
Milan, Rome, Florence.
And then I think we should end up
in San Gimignano.
Where?
Where your parents
reaffirmed their vows.
Yes! Right.
I couldn't find that cathedral
you described online.
I'll keep trying.
I hope I haven't confused it with
the church I was confirmed in,
which is in France.
You know, sometimes
you confuse and distort
memories from your childhood.
No. No, not really.
Anyway, that's where I think
we should go because, er...
..well, that's where I think
you and I should get married.
Sorry, mate, the Mary Drouin thing
is out of bounds.
You should know better than that.
My hands are tied.
Yeah.
I understand, I...
No, I just thought that...
Leave it. Leave it, alright?
There's nothing I can do.
You right?
Yep.
Oh!
Sorry, mate.
What's the score?
Oh, three apiece.
Three apiece?
Yeah.
Let's call it a draw, eh?
Hey?
Yeah, mate, neither of us
is gonna get to nine.
I'm gonna hit the showers.
Oh, come on!
No.
Say hi to Scarlet
if you see her, will you?
Yeah, sure.
See ya, mate.
See ya.
Hey, you forgot...
So in your conversation
with the Attorney-General,
you were merely trying
to elicit answers
about the brutal rape of Mary Drouin?
And the four other girls,
that's correct.
Did you, through your choice
of words, intend to cause
racial unrest and/or a riot?
Absolutely not.
“People are forced
to arm themselves.”
“If I was a young man
with a sister or a mother...
“..I know what I'd be doing.”
What would you be doing?
Well, I meant that I sympathise
with their anger.
Our streets are not safe.
Surely you meant more than that.
You describe it as a war.
Well, the ‘Sunday Sun' is currently
running a war on fat.
I don't think
they're advocating that
their readers run out
and machete people with cellulite.
I mean, clearly I was
speaking metaphorically.
You talked about right-minded people
arming themselves,
taking the law into their own hands,
picking up cudgels.
That doesn't sound metaphorical.
What other possible meaning could
your listeners interpret from this?
The need for action.
Not violent action.
As Al Gore says,
I raise an inconvenient truth.
An interesting example, because you
don't buy global warming, do you?
Well, only stupid people
don't buy into global warming
but intelligent people
question its causes.
We could debate this all day
but I don't wanna bore the jury.
I mean, you do feel it, don't you,
the tension, the fear in this city?
Ms Langhorn, please.
The Germans stood idly by.
How dare you appropriate
the Holocaust for your own...
Ms Engels.
Apologies, Your Honour.
Er...Your Honour,
I request a brief recess.
- Mr Greene?
- Er...
Ask Eddie about a visit she got
from Mary Drouin's sister
a week before the riots.
Why?
You have 15 minutes.
I've gotta give it back.
Sylvia is an agency nanny,
by the way.
She charges 32 bucks an hour.
Oh.
She seemed nice.
She is.
Home stretch.
Good.
Because I've booked a place
at Pretty Beach for the weekend.
How does you, me
and no Etta Greenburg sound?
Ms Engels.
Are you done with the defendant?
Not quite, Your Honour.
One or two more.
Your friend Mary Drouin, you know
her sister Tamsyn also, don't you?
I met her once.
I understand that she came to visit
you a week before the broadcast.
How did you get on?
Oh, she seemed pleasant enough.
Must have seemed
a little more than pleasant.
I believe that you gave her $20,000,
did you not?
As a matter of fact, I did.
I see.
I gave her money to help Mary
with her various psychological
and medical needs.
Why did you give the money
to Tamsyn and not Mary?
Well, Mary's in no fit state.
So it wasn't to keep her quiet then?
Objection, Your Honour.
Apologies, Your Honour.
Ms Langhorn, what did Tamsyn Drouin
tell you when she visited you?
Oh, she, um...
She came to me with...with
a wild story. I didn't believe it.
Oh, what about her story
didn't you believe?
Five girls were raped...
over four months in the same area.
Your Honour, I'd ask you to direct
the defendant to answer the question.
Ms Langhorn.
She was suggesting that
the rape had not happened
quite as Mary had described it.
I felt she was clearly...
What did she say?
That it had been a family member.
And that the whole story
about the Muslim gang
had been invented by the family
to cover up the truth?
You meet Mary, you meet Tamsyn,
you tell me who you think's
the more reliable!
So let's just be clear here,
shall we?
You chose to give $20,000
to the sister whom you thought
to be unreliable?
Er, Your Honour, my client is charged
with inciting racial hatred.
This is a case about
the words she used.
Whether or not she paid money to
Mary Drouin, Mary Drouin's sister,
her great-aunt or her cat,
is irrelevant to
these particular proceedings.
I would ask that the exchange between
Ms Engels and Ms Langhorn
pertaining to this money
be deemed irrelevant,
and, respectfully, that you ask
the jury to disregard it.
- Your Honour.
- I quite agree, Mr Greene.
Members of the jury, you must not
take into account any testimony
as to any payments from
Ms Langhorn to Ms Tamsyn Drouin.
Well, I guess on the upside,
I got you off.
Yeah, I suppose you did.
It was never really about that,
though, was it?
It was a publicity drive.
No.
You made Mary Drouin
the poster girl for your cause
and then you discovered
that she wasn't raped by a Muslim
gang but her own dad.
So that was another
inconvenient truth.
One that could never
see the light of day.
Sometimes the cause is bigger
than the individual.
Four other girls were raped.
Somebody's gotta be angry for them.
Well, my guess is you've set
the cause back a good long way.
I know in my heart
I did the right thing.
And I know in my heart
I won't be coming to Pretty Beach.
Ooh, yeah.
Steak?
Don't tell me
you are actually cooking.
The start of the new me.
Thickly sliced, grass-fed,
prime Angus Scotch with green beans.
Huh?
Just the steak and beans?
All a growing boy needs.
No rehab?
Oh, they tried to make me
go to rehab but I said no.
No.
And you're sure?
You'd be surprised at my willpower.
I would.
Mmmm.
There's a turd on your plate.
Mortimer Gross unsalted
peanut butter. Go on.
Mmmm.
That is so much more
than peanut butter.
Yeah.
Still, questioning its proximity
to the steak...
Do you?
♪ I could never lose control
♪ I never lost control
♪ No, I never lost control
♪ The time you get from me
I swear I'll pay you back... ♪
It is good peanut butter.
David and I are getting married.
♪ Despite all we've seen and heard
♪ Don't believe a word
♪ They say... ♪
It's five minutes past midnight
and you're with Edwina
Langhorn till the wee small hours,
bringing you the best in
easy listening and classic music.
Can you turn
that wretched harpy off, son?
Be my pleasure, Dad.
♪ I have not lost the will to live
♪ But I might have spent it all
♪ I used to have so much to give
♪ Now I got nothing at all
♪ 1 won't let you down
♪ 1 will not let you fall
♪ 1 will not let you fall. ♪
http://hiqve.com/