Within the spreading darkness
hirogaru yami no naka
I pledged a vow to the revolution
kawashiatta kakumei no chigiri
I won't let anyone get in my way
dare ni mo jama saseru wake ni wa ikanai kara
The future that the forbidden fruit foretells
kajitsu ga tsugeta mirai
I'm going to make that dream come true
yume risou ni kaeru
The 'ending' that everybody wants
dare mo ga nozonda 'owari' o
Within the spreading darkness
hirogaru yami no naka
I pledged a vow to the revolution
kawashiatta kakumei no chigiri
I won't let anyone get in my way
dare ni mo jama saseru wake ni wa ikanai
Someday I'll show you
itsuka boku ga miseteageru
A bright and ideal world
hikarikagayaku sekai o
The Shinigami Realm
Rebirth
Otoharada
Kurou
( 42 )
Otoharada
Kurou
( 42 )
Otoharada
Kurou
( 42 )
Unemployed
Shinjuku
Killing Incident
Random
Otoharada Kurou
Otoharada
Kurou
tL NoTe
|
All the different variations of writing the name "Shibuimaru Takuo."
To be continued
I had a dream that no one could see
dare ni mo mirenai yume o mite
I threw away everything that I didn't need
iranai mono wa subete suteta
I'm holding these feelings that I can't give up in my heart
yuzurenai omoi kono mune ni yadoshite
Even if my feet fall victim to the shackles of sacrifice
mada real to ideal no hazama ni ite
In between reality and my ideal
gisei no kase ni ashi o toraretemo
I can't hold back the flooding impulses
afurereru shoudou osaekirenai
Because I have a strong desire to accomplish
tsuyoku motomeru kokoro ga aru kara
'Deceit', 'fear', 'vanity', 'melancholy'
'itsuwari', 'osore', 'kyoshoku', 'urei'
I'm not weak enough
samazama na negative ni
To believe any of these negative perceptions
torawareru hodo yowaku wa nai
I'm a trickster who doesn't know solitude
kodoku mo shiranu Trickster
Next Episode Preview
Kira, kill everyone.
Do you want to send this message?
Send
Name:           Rococo
Kira, kill everyone.
Misery
Next time
Confrontation