You want me to repeat the question?
You have any idea who the father might be?
- No.
Are you aware of any other
intimate relationships
that Carolyn may have been in?
Would you be willing to
submit to a paternity test?
Are you enjoying this, Tommy?
I am-- No. I'm not.
She was a friend and a colleague.
Your response?
Am I a suspect?
I just got the case.
God.
How long had you been fucking Carolyn?
- Are you kidding me?
- We had a personal relationship, okay?
And this was something you
didn't think you needed to tell me?
No, it was a personal matter.
I just lost an election-- my career--
- in part due to your personal matter.
- Okay. No. No.
That is not true.
- Bullshit!
- No.
This investigation
was the nail in my coffin
- and I put you in charge of it.
- No. No.
Look, you asked me to do it.
You imposed it on me. I did not want to.
It didn't occasion you
to think to yourself,
"Hold on.
Maybe I have a conflict of interest here.
- Yes, of course it did.
- I am having sex with the victim"?
Raymond, of course it did.
- She was pregnant with your child?
- Okay, I can't.
I just, pl-- Come on.
Rusty.
Hey, Rusty.
Listen, it would be good if
you could do that paternity test.
Remove your hand.
All right.
Get a warrant.
Yeah.
Hi.
- Hey, B.
- Hey.
Where are the kids?
They're upstairs.
They're doing their homework.
- They eaten?
- Not yet.
Can you sit down?
Yeah, sure.
I was just informed that...
Carolyn was pregnant
and they think that it was mine,
and I'm a suspect in her murder.
But it ended a year ago.
It did.
But it started back up again
just... briefly,
for not even-- less than a week.
I'm sorry.
You didn't even suspect anything?
Of course not.
You think I would have allowed for that?
- You might have pretended not to see.
- Well, I didn't.
I need to call Barbara.
What? Why?
Because she's my friend.
She's gonna wonder-- maybe assume--
that you knew about the affair,
which means she'll wonder if I knew
and I need to assure her that I did not.
You know, I think you should wait a minute
until Rusty has a conversation
with her first.
How long had this been going on?
I just found out about it myself, Lo.
That doesn't answer the question.
Well, I don't have an answer.
Why are you attacking me?
Because people sense things
about their friends, their colleagues.
You have a very good nose
and this happened right under it,
which means that is a reflection on you,
which makes it a reflection on me,
which gives me the right to be pissed off.
Poor Barbara. My God.
It's easy and quick.
- Five minutes.
- Five minutes?
That's plenty of time.
- What are we doing?
- So you're gonna come up and out.
- Up and out.
- Yeah.
Then up...
- Up.
- Then out.
- Okay.
- Other way.
- Why is it-- Okay.
- You're not--
We're going the same way,
so then it's...
But if we're going--
What?
Motherfucker.
Bunny Davis murder.
What about it?
There was a second spermatozoa sample
in the victim besides Liam Reynolds?
Yeah, inconclusive.
Yeah, but that wasn't in
the evidence doc that we--
that we handed over to the defense.
Not my problem.
No, but it is your problem,
because it's potentially
- prosecutorial misconduct if we didn't--
- Hold on.
It was an older sample on a different day.
No, but that doesn't matter.
It was potentially exculpatory.
Carolyn had all this information, Sabich.
But I didn't!
Well, then maybe you should
read the freaking report.
I don't know what to tell you.
There were two different spermatozoa
samples at the scene of the crime.
And again, Carolyn knew all this.
What did you tell her?
That the only sample
we could identify was Reynolds.
The other semen was inconclusive.
It was contaminated.
Was it yours?
We concealed evidence! We--
I didn't conceal anything.
It's all in my goddamn report,
and you need some serious fucking help.
Goddamn it. Fucking pick up.
You've reached Detective Rodriguez.
Please leave a message.
Rigo, it's me.
Can you call me back?
It's very important, okay?
Just call me back.
Fuck.
You're saying he physically assaulted him?
He grabbed the guy by his fucking throat.
He was, like, fucking doing this.
He's sick.
You know what I'm talking about.
He's fucking sick.
Yeah. Tommy, take a seat.
I don't need to sit down.
Listen, this guy...
Just take a moment.
I'm fine.
As delicious as the prospect is
that Rusty may be culpable...
Yeah.
I just want you just to follow the facts.
- I got you. I know what you're saying.
- Right?
'Cause our job is not to get Rusty Sabich.
Our job is to get it right.
I'm a professional.
I understand what you're saying.
So, just let the evidence be your guide,
not your fucking feelings.
You've reached Detective Rodriguez.
Please leave a message.
Hey.
Hey, Dad.
- Hi. What you eating?
- Hey.
- Chinese.
- How was work today, Dad?
It sucked.
You guys want a napkin?
What happened?
A lot.
Guys, phones down please.
Phones down.
So something has happened.
And before you hear it from others,
I would like you to hear it from...
us.
So your father has something
he would like to...
tell you.
I don't think that now
is the time or the place.
Is there a better fucking time or place?
You want them to hear it
on the news? School?
What's going on?
Carolyn Polhemus and I
were having an affair.
It wasn't going on for very long,
but the detectives in the investigation,
you know, have a lot of questions
about it-- about that.
And I think that your mother is right.
I think it's better
that you hear it from me
than see it on the news
or hear about it
from one of your friends at school, so...
I want you to know that I'm sorry
and that I love you.
Kyle.
I will not be alone with this this time.
I'm sorry, honey. I'm sorry.
It's all right. It's a shock.
I know.
Now, listen, real life has come early
and we are in
for some difficult days, okay?
But we will get through this.
Are you gonna leave him?
I don't know yet.
Your father is a good man...
and I think he loved her.
And that is very difficult for me.
I...
I just don't want anyone to get hurt.
Me or you, or...
I just think...
we're at that point.
I can't do this anymore.
Don't you agree?
"Just a simple guy," you said.
"Still wet behind the ears."
A lot of junk about American ideals.
Yeah, this is certainly a lot of junk,
all right.
Now, look, Senator...
I don't know.
This is a whole new world to me.
Hey.
- Hey.
- You okay?
Do you love Mom?
So much.
Then why?
Kyle?
Hey, it's not even 06:00 in the morning.
Come on.
Come on. You're making a lot of noise.
I couldn't sleep.
Kyle. Kyle.
Just come inside. Come on.
- I'll make you some pancakes.
- I don't want any fucking pancakes, Dad.
Claude, what are you doing?
Sorry, Rusty. Search warrant.
My wife and daughter are inside.
Well, they're gonna get woken.
I'll give you the honors,
but we gotta go in.
Come on. Let's go.
Why are they taking my computer?
- Honey, they have to take everything.
- Dad, it's mine.
Rusty.
- What's going on?
- This one's for...
It's the other.
We could bring you to the lab,
but it'd be easier here.
Tommy, just a minute.
- You come to my house at dawn?
- Hey, don't do this.
In front of my family.
My children.
We typically serve warrants at dawn,
as was your preference.
In fact, you had files from this office
which didn't--
- They were cases I was working on.
- You're not working on anything anymore.
As of this moment,
you're on administrative leave.
You think I don't understand
what you're doing?
- Get your face out of mine.
- How's it going, buddy? You all right?
- Come on. Why don't we do this--
- Don't even try and do shit like that.
- You're out of control.
- I am not.
Medical examiners.
You're threatening district attorneys.
You're threatening me.
I'm not threatening you.
You are, with words and tone,
and body language.
You are.
You really think that I killed Carolyn?
Really?
- Look, that is not for me to say.
- Really?
What I can say is that
you willfully misdirected
- and you impeded this investigation.
- Oh, my God.
- That is not a good look for this office.
- Okay.
- All right. Yeah.
- It's not a good look for you.
Fuck.
You lied to your therapist.
I thought you said
this wasn't gonna be about blame.
We had a session alone and you--
You deceived me point blank.
I am not a liar.
Well, you are. Of course you are.
It is the lie of omission.
- You told me--
- No, I lied about that.
You told me that the affair had ended.
I lied about that
and I lied about Carolyn.
I lied about the affair,
but, like, only that.
- Well, the good news is--
- I'm not a liar.
The good news is that Barbara is--
she's here.
A lot of people wouldn't be.
So what are we doing?
What's the goal?
Barbara?
I don't know.
I guess I feel trapped.
By?
We have kids.
Rusty, you want to salvage this marriage?
Yes. Yes, I want to salvage it.
And not just because we have kids.
I love you.
I know that that sounds hollow right now.
If you're arrested--
No, the--
There's not an "if."
I will be arrested.
I mean, they're going through
my phone and my computer right now
and they're gonna see
that I was obsessed with her.
I mean,
I was basically stalking her, you know?
I mean...
the breakup wasn't good.
If I was a prosecutor,
I wouldn't fucking hesitate.
And it's being Tommy Molto,
there's no "if."
When will the DA name a suspect?
No, we're not prepared
to name a suspect at this time,
but we're confident
that one will be forthcoming.
I ran for this office on
a promise of vigilance.
It's a vow that I intend to keep.
Gone are the days when
the district attorney
sees crimes against women
and simply shrugs.
Carolyn Polhemus's killer will be found.
And that killer will be held accountable.
Enough of that.
Is Raymond here?
Yeah.
They raided the house.
They took my phone
and my computer, Barbara's, the kids'.
Yeah. Well, what do you expect, Rusty?
I mean, you did it
a thousand times yourself
to a thousand different people, right?
It's the drill. Now you know how it feels.
They're gonna charge me.
You know this for sure?
Yes. They're going to go through
the computer
and see that there were a lot of emails
to her in that last week.
They're going to go
through the cell phone.
See there were a lot of calls and texts.
They're going to say
that I was stalking her.
And you add that to
the prints at the scene.
They don't have evidence
leading to anyone else.
And Tommy Molto is
certainly not going to go looking.
You better get yourself an attorney.
That's why I'm here.
Oh, no.
No.
I need somebody
who is versed in Delay and Molto.
You need someone who is versed in defense.
No, I need someone who can
get into their heads, Raymond.
You are the best lawyer that I know.
And I need you.
Do you have an ounce of fucking humility?
The gall it takes for you to
come into my house...
- I should've told you. Listen to me.
- ...look Lorraine in the face--
Listen to me.
It--
It was wrong of me.
But you know what?
It's a fucking surprise.
I did it because I wanted you to win.
It wasn't the right thing to do.
But do you really think that I killed her?
Do you? You know me.
I thought I did.
Fuck!
Come on.
Where the fuck have you been?
Pick up.
Hey.
Where have you been?
I've been trying to call all day.
Fuck you, Rusty.
Listen, I need your help.
Please.
Listen, I need you to get me
in to see Reynolds again.
Look, they've taken me off the case.
There's nothing I can do.
No, no. Listen.
Just please, please listen.
Rigo, I need you, okay?
There was a second sperm sample
and I know that Reynolds knows something.
I need to get back in to see him
and you can get me in. Just please.
Why are we meeting here?
I have--
I don't have security clearance today.
So you're just a regular visitor?
No more "officer of the court."
This is perverse.
I know you know something.
Are you a suspect?
I'm here, Liam, because if you
have any information
that leads us to the real killer,
you might shave some time
off your sentence.
You like perversity?
Even if you had Carolyn killed,
it could work in your favor.
You'd have to have an accomplice
which means you'd have something to trade.
Right now, you're serving
a life sentence for killing Bunny Davis.
By pointing us to Carolyn,
you could possibly see
the street again, you know?
Even if you had a hand in the murder too.
Now that is perversity.
Okay, so, just to be clear,
you're telling me incriminating myself...
- If you had an accomplice.
- ...in a prosecutor's murder,
- could lead me to my freedom?
- Yes.
What's certain is that you are currently
serving a life sentence without parole.
And I am offering you an
opportunity to change that.
Oh, God.
This is beautiful.
You're desperate.
So, nothing then?
Not yet.
- Not yet.
- Well, he's a sick guy, you know?
I mean,
he had it out for her, he threatened her.
She was killed
the same way Bunny Davis was.
Bunny was stabbed.
And tied up like Carolyn.
I don't know how many times
I have to say this.
I just need to get to the truth.
I'm just-- I--
I mean-- And--
I mean, short of that, I just--
Just some fucking reasonable doubt.
You could have told me, you know?
That I was sleeping with her.
If for no other reason than
to save me some fucking time.
I didn't kill her.
I mean, I--
I can't even-- Like--
You know, the police certainly
aren't going to be looking for who did.
I mean, at least not many of them.
So I need you.
No more fucking lying to me.
Yeah?
- I didn't say yes.
- You didn't say yes.
- I did not say yes.
- You didn't say no.
You cherished Carolyn.
- It's not about Carolyn.
- Yes, it is.
She's the one who was murdered.
Look...
if I thought for a second
that Rusty was responsible--
You did think it for a second.
You told me.
- Rusty couldn't have done this.
- Bullshit.
Whether he did it or not--
He's my close friend.
Maybe my best friend.
I mean, it's not inconceivable
that I would want to help him.
This is how you retire?
Why can't we just travel
like we talked about?
You know, get a little place in Florida--
Does it have to be Florida?
Florida's for dead people. I'm--
I'm not dead.
I mean, sometimes I feel like it but...
That's what this is about.
Your not wanting to be dead.
Right now, my legacy...
I went out in defeat.
I was beaten by a conniving shithead
who's holding press conferences every day,
dancing on my political grave.
If I could avenge
those two tiny little suck fucks...
That would be meaningful.
And it's not a crime for me to want
to wake up every morning
to a life that has meaning.
I'm sorry you feel it doesn't right now.
This isn't about you.
You are my wife.
You mean everything to me. You know that.
Just not enough.
Hey.
Jay...
will you look at me?
Where's your mom?
Out back, smoking by the tree house.
Not that I know that though.
Hello?
Hey, we got the lab results back.
Paternity confirmed.
Sorry, Rusty.
I know it's not what you wanted to hear.
What's that?
Jay, go get your mom.
Go get your mother.
- Okay.
- Jay?
Jaden,
I love you.
Mom!
Mr. Sabich,
we have a warrant for your arrest.
You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say can and will be
used against you in a court of law.
Please turn around and put
your hands behind your back.
You have the right to an attorney.
If you cannot afford an attorney,
one will be appointed--
Look, it's a sad day.
It's a very sad day when a member
of our law enforcement community,
who's entrusted to safeguard the public,
is accused of such a heinous crime.
When a public servant so betrays his duty,
so violates his commitment to justice,
to humanity,
by taking another individual's life.
If there is any consolation,
we can all take heart
in one of our most cherished
jurisprudence ideals.
Nobody is above the law.
Nobody.
The arrest of a former prosecutor
has sent shock waves,
not just here in Chicago.
This case is sure
to attract national attention.
Mr. Sabich was taken into custody
at his residence last night.
The arrest was
evidently made without incident.
Mr. Sabich spent the night in detention,
in the building behind me
where he now awaits arraignment.
Criminal case 861246.
The People of Illinois v. Rozat K. Sabich.
The defendant is charged herein
that he did commit murder
in the first degree
and that he did knowingly, intentionally,
and with malice aforethought
trespass with force and arms
upon the person of Carolyn Polhemus,
thereby taking the life of
the aforementioned...
Your Honor, Thomas Molto,
Chief Deputy District Attorney
for the People of Illinois,
registering my appearance
as well as the appearance
of District Attorney, Nico Della Guardia.
Raymond Horgan for the defense, Judge.
Your Honor,
the defendant is present in court.
We would acknowledge
receipt of the indictment
and waive the remainder of formal reading.
On behalf of Mr. Sabich,
we would like the court to
enter a plea of not guilty to the charge.
Plea of not guilty to the indictment.
Bail is set at 1.5 million signature bond.
Is there a request from either party
for a pretrial conference?
Your Honor, given the depravity
visited upon a beloved member
of our law enforcement community,
the People would ask
that a pretrial conference
be set at your earliest convenience.
That would be an unnecessary waste
of the court's time.
The charge in this case is entirely false.
The reputation of one of
the city's finest public servants
and attorneys has been impugned,
perhaps destroyed
without any basis in fact.
Justice in this case must be swift
and we therefore ask the court
to find an immediate trial date.
Be careful what you ask for, Counsel.
I have made my request.
The defendant has
waived pretrial conference.
The matter will be set
immediately for trial.
Defendant's motions
to be filed in 14 days,
and the prosecuting attorney
to respond seven days hence.
Now, Mr. Molto, Mr. Della Guardia,
this case is likely to inspire
many speeches
which you seem predisposed to give.
Mr. Horgan is correct when he observes
that these are very serious charges.
Against a lawyer who has served this court
with distinction for many years.
Let us aim for justice to be done.
And it need not be
served with any extra pomp.
And that goes for you too, Mr. Horgan.
I don't do pomp, Judge.
The defendant is remanded.
His bail will be processed.
This proceeding is adjourned.
- Thank you for--
- Yeah, goes without saying.
Don't talk to anybody in there.
And get something to eat, will you?
You gotta be kidding me.
I am definitely not kidding.
This is as serious as I get, Nico.
Maybe we should start with wiping
the smiles off our respective faces.
Fuck-Thing One. Fuck-Thing Two.
It seems you got a good draw
with this judge.
Yeah, she's an ex-defense lawyer and she--
she's fair, you know?
I just wanted to say I know that...
today must have been really hard
for you all.
I wanna say thank you for being there.
Is it good that it's happening fast?
Yeah.
Time favors the prosecution.
So the faster, the better.
For all of us.