Good morning.
Morning.
What are you doing?
Eating breakfast.
That's not breakfast.
Where's Mum?
In the bathroom, crying.
Right.
Why?
Didn't like the picture
in the paper.
I think she looks really pretty.
Come on, unlock the bloody door.
No.
I don't want to see you.
I can't see you. Go away.
You have to see me.
What the hell is this about?
Nothing happened.
Well, something bloody happened.
There's a photo of it, woman.
We just kissed, that was all.
I don't believe you.
That was it.
OK, he...he felt my breast briefly once,
then we realised it was wrong.
Open the fuckin' door!
What the hell were you doing there
in the first place?
I just...l felt so alone.
Oh, screw alone. Talk to me.
I can't.
I can't take any more
humiliation, Barney.
How am I going to face anyone?
Oh, I'm not much interested
in muckraking, Neil.
Tick-tack.
You know, you and I,
we don't trade in gossip.
If David Potter chooses to knock off
a good mate's wife, his business.
But what does hurt is...
..Ms Engels was a trusted...
Mum, where are we going?
Shh.
.. member of my inner sanctum.
Privy to all manner
of private information...
This is miles away.
What, you've got legs, haven't you?
Move, quickly. Go.
The sort of information that could
jeopardise the health and safety...
Mummy loves you very much.
..of folk like you and I and the great
people of this great state.
I dread to think...
..what state secrets were traded
in that hotel bed.
But, look, you know who I blame
in all of this, Neil?
Me.
Yep, the buck must rest here.
trust too much,
I believe in giving people a fair go.
I wanna hope that people can be
better than they think they are.
Quite frankly, Neil, it hurts.
Uh...'m only human.
And not a bad quality to have,
mate, in one of our pollies.
Oh, that's very nice of you
to say that, Neil.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Reverend Ron Drury is,
as his stepbrother was before him,
a prophet imbued with
the gift of healing.
Now, the complainants in this matter,
by their own admission,
consented to being, and I quote,
“rubbed with unguents and oils
“and further CONSENTED to
sexual intercourse with the accused,
“in the hope that they may be
healed of possession by the devil.”
Ladies and gentlemen,
it was only much, much later,
after the complainants realised
that the rashes they were suffering
were not in fact the devil's work,
but the result of aggressive solvents
used in the Reverend Ron's giftware
shop, where they were employed,
did these women think
to cry foul rape.
Now, ladies and gentlemen,
a charge of rape cannot be made
simply because one regrets
consenting to sex.
You'd be locking up 90%
of the population on that basis.
The complainants in this matter
seek vengeance, ladies and gentlemen,
and vengeance never
results in justice.
Vengeance results in misery.
Mr Greene, have you done
the community any favours today
by getting Ron Drury
off rape charges?
Polly something or other, right?
On the ‘Seven Days This Night
This Day Today...
..This Night Will Be The Same
As Tomorrow Project'?
Yes, one of those. But you haven't
answered my question.
Ask me again.
Ron Drury has a history of abusing
women and getting away with it...
No, he doesn't.
Reverend Ron Drury has a habit
of treating sick women
who are seeking
alternative therapies,
having been abandoned by the
conservative medical establishment.
It's the AMA you wanna
be pointing your finger out.
What's your surname again?
So it's appropriate for Drury
to continue practising
his voodoo, is it?
That's a hell of a surname.
Maybe we can make a deal.
Oh, yeah?
I don't really wanna do this story
about you getting
a serial rapist off.
Don't you now?
No.
I'd rather do a story on
your little friend Melissa
and how she's coping after
the death of Joshua Floyd.
You obviously haven't met Melissa.
Nobody who knows Melissa
would describe her as ‘little'.
So do we have a deal?
Oh, how I wish we had a deal.
Um, no, I don't think so.
Melissa's not doing any interviews.
That's a pity.
Yes, it's a pity.
I guess I'll see you
on the telly then.
I guess so.
It's, uh, Nesbitt, by the way.
Polly Nesbitt.
Mmm.
I'll see you on the telly, Nesbitt.
Yes.
So guess who managed to score
two el primo tickets to
Mr Neil Diamond this evening?
You're kidding me.
You are fucking kidding me.
You sweet man, you!
Mmmm.
Oh, God!
The show's not till 8:00.
Yeah.
So I was thinking a really,
really long breakfast in bed.
Oh, oh, yeah.
Hey, sweet?
Mmm?
There's one more thing
angel needs you to do first.
You name it, I'll do it.
Cleaver's missed another payment.
Right.
Come on, it's just business.
Yeah, I know.
It's 200 grand.
Oh, don't be grumpy
with angel, sweet.
Look, it's just a little hard
for me. You know, I owe him.
I sometimes think
if it wasn't for Cleaver,
you and I wouldn't be together.
Oh, don't say that. Never say that.
We were always meant to be together.
It's a lot of money, you know.
I won't let him get away with it.
I can't let him get away with it.
Yeah, I know.
So I was thinking,
maybe I could sub Cleaver out.
Sub him out?
Yeah, well, I've got
this mate of a mate.
He's new in town,
he's from the UK.
He's never met Cleave,
he's got no history,
he's got no emotional involvement.
I'd be really,
really grateful, angel.
OK, I will give Cleaver
two more weeks,
but I'm doing it for you,
sweet, and not for him.
And if nothing comes in
in that time,
you're gonna have to call your mate.
Fuckin' love you.
Fuckin' love you too.
This is nothing in
the scheme of things, mate.
I know it's nothing.
We didn't do anything.
I believe you.
Well, there's no reason
to drop your case against Greene.
The man has got away with every sort
of abuse under the sun.
He has to pay.
Couldn't agree more.
Weakness to let him off.
Oh, come on, mate. Nut up.
He'll call me back into the box.
He'll call Scarlet.
He'll eat us alive.
Dave, take him on.
After all, he screwed her too.
That's gotta count for something.
I thought you said you believed me.
Yeah, but I'm paid to.
I did not have sexual relations
with that woman!
Oh, God!
David Potter and I did not have sex.
Oh, I'm sure you didn't.
That's just politics, Engels.
I didn't plan to drag you down.
You just presented me with
this gold embossed gift, so...
Look, I have a family.
I'm not rolling over.
I will hit back.
Hey.
Hi.
There she is, a married woman.
Ah, Mrs Nicole Lee at your service.
How was your honeymoon?
Oh, good, yeah. It was fantastic.
You've been to Ubud, haven't you?
Mm-hm.
Lovely and romantic and...
Great. That is so good.
Mm. Big breakfasts every day
and long walks.
Fantastic.
Yeah, lovely. It was...it truly was.
So.
Yeah, I just wanted to
sort of catch up
before we see each other
in the office.
Didn't want there to be any tension.
Oh, God, no. Nor do I.
No, I'd hate that.
Yeah. So let's not have it.
Yeah, just being alone
with Bevan again
reminded me of all the reasons
I married him.
He doesn't know about us, does he?
No, nuh.
No, that was...
Yeah, I wasn't married then.
It'd be different now, of course.
Of course.
Oh, but I...seriously, Barney,
I want us to keep in touch.
Oh. Oh, we will.
Yeah. As friends.
We will.
As really good friends.
Alright.
I am so happy that you're happy,
I really am.
Happy, I'm happy.
Happy, happy, happy, happy.
Happy, happy, happy.
You must be loving this.
I take my pleasure
where I find it, Harry. Sorry.
Shove it.
You win.
I withdraw the action.
The whole thing?
You heard me.
You deserve to burn, but...
There's, uh...there's
the small matter of my costs.
My time doesn't come cheap,
you know, mate.
Everything about you comes cheap.
What does it say about David Potter
when he withdraws a libel charge
against a man who accused him
of being, and I quote,
“a sadistic, cowardly, lying buffoon
whose contempt for common decency
“makes a mockery
of the position he represents.”
Our Shadow Attorney-General clearly
thinks he is all of these things.
If that is true,
Mr Potter must resign.
Cleaver Greene?
Oh, for God's sake.
For the last time, she's not
giving any interviews, OK?
And I'm not her fucking agent.
No, that would be me.
My name's Gloria Beckford.
I've been trying to get
in touch with Melissa
but she's proving
to be quite elusive.
I'd be grateful
if you'd pass this on.
OK.
Hey. How was your day?
Oh. I watched
a documentary on cancer.
Great.
Now, look, I thought we might
head out and celebrate.
I've had a couple
of little victories today.
I'm going to bed.
Oh, come on. It's not even 7:00.
I don't wanna go out.
Come on, sweetheart,
you can't hide away forever.
You go out, do whatever you like.
Look, a couple of laughs,
a couple of, you know, drinks.
You could have a little shower
or something,
freshen up a bit,
get glammed up.
It might turn out
better than you think.
Come on. Please?
It's on me.
Alright, that's enough.
Thanks, mate. Keep that change.
Melissa. Melissa.
Cleaver, why here?
No, here is good.
Here's good. Here's good.
It's all fine. Come on.
No. She's just after a quiet night here,
boys, quiet night.
VIPs coming through.
Cowra corn-fed chicken
with citrus foam and asparagus.
Where is the asparagus from?
I'm sorry, sir?
Well, you've given me
a postcode for the chook
as well as
its pre-death eating habits.
You've done the same thing for
the mussels, the oysters and the steak.
I know for instance that the cow
lived happily in Gippsland
where it ate grass.
But there is absolutely
nothing in here
about the formative years
of the asparagus.
So if you could please ask the chef.
He'll have the chicken.
I don't know anything about Cowra
except it's where they kept the Japs
during the Second World War.
I hope my bird fared better.
What's going on?
They've taken 1,000 shots of me.
What are they expecting me to do?
- Oh!
- What's going on?
- Come on! Shove off.
- No, no, no, no.
Have you thought any more
about the second book?
Why do you ask?
Well, I just...I think it could be
an important part
of the healing process.
I wanted to support you in that.
I mean, you're gonna need
a legal consultant, aren't you?
I presume I'm gonna be
in the second book.
No, actually, if you think about it,
it's like, you know,
there's more than one perspective
on the story, isn't there?
It doesn't just have to be about you.
You know, Josh touched
both of our lives, didn't he?
Just a thought.
Um...that arrived.
Some woman. I don't know.
Ah.
Fried green tomato ice-cream.
Pumpkin and chive sorbet.
Where are they going
with these sorbets?
Avocado and nashi pear gelato.
Pumpkin...
OK.
Good.
Good. So that's good.
Sister, I was just about to call you.
I've been trying to reach you
since yesterday, Cleave.
Oh, this bloody phone.
Dad's...died, Cleave.
Right.
I'm sorry, Cleave.
OK.
So, um, it'll be at...Dad's church.
You know?
OK.
Um, the wake will be at Jane's.
Good.
Can I...get another bottle?
Oh!
What happened to Wednesday?
What happened to Wednesday? Fuck.
Miss, it's me.
I'm just, um, ringing to apologise.
I'm sorry I was insensitive
to your needs.
Good. Um, listen, I could, uh...
I could really do with a lift.
Um, and could you bring a suit?
Your dress is caught up.
He prided himself
on being a decent man
who worked daily
to put food on the table
and to teach his children
the worth of human values.
Love of family always came first.
It gave his life meaning.
And what a life he gave them.
Malaysia, Singapore,
where our intrepid explorer set up
a business in the copha trade,
before returning here with
his lovely wife, Kate, and the children
in 1979.
With the money he made there,
he set up a travel agency
where his attention to detail...
I thought your dad
had a hardware store.
Wrong funeral.
..wonderful times abroad.
The Nankervises have always
had a reputation
for being an intrepid bunch.
Keith and Kate took the kids,
Bridie, Wally and Joshua...
Excuse me. Thank you.
Here you go, ladies. Thank you.
One each. Thank you very much.
Excuse me. I'll just give you
one of these. Thank you.
Can I give you one of these?
Give one of these a read.
Sorry, what is this?
It's a...it's a factual account
of the true circumstances
about David Potter and myself.
I need you to know that what's being
said in the tabloids and on the radio
about certain misinterpreted events
is not accurate.
But my details are included
if you have any queries...
OK. Thank you.
Hurry, darling, let's go. Come on.
You didn't even know my old man.
Oh, I'm not crying about him.
It's about Keith Nankervis.
His life had such meaning.
Oh,
and every corner was occupied
by people he'd spent
a lifetime avoiding.
Oh, Aunty Edie.
Sid.
My sister Jane.
So, not close then?
Where were you?
Uh...
Hi, Dad.
Mate, how are you?
So, what was so pressing you felt
you could miss your own father's
funeral, for Christ's sake?
We decided to go
to Keith Nankervis's instead.
The travel agent? Why the hell...
He seemed like a wonderful man.
This is Melissa.
I know who you are.
Yes, you told me St Thomas's.
His old church.
He hasn't stepped foot
inside St Thomas's since...
..Father Bart
and the Youth Camp.
Do you honestly think I wanted to go
to fucking Keith Nankervis's funeral?
Do you think I could feel
any more gutted than I do?
His granddaughter read a poem
that she wrote herself —
‘Who Will Be In The Armchair
At Christmas?'
You fucking snake in the grass.
Aunty Jane, it's a funeral.
Just stay out of this, kid.
It's between me and him.
I just want to say to you that
I will never speak to you again.
Finally, an upside.
He went to the wrong church.
Oh, bullshit.
We all know why he didn't come.
Oh, yes, why was that, Jane?
Denlion Holdings.
Denlion Holdings?
What, is it a West Indian cricketer?
You were too gutless
to do it yourself,
so you got somebody else
to do your dirty work for you.
What is the mad woman talking about?
So you're saying
you know nothing about
Dad selling off all his shares
two months before he died?
Exactly when you learnt
you were getting nothing!
I have no idea what
either of you are on about.
Dad sold everything off
to this company called Denlion
when he was in care.
They gave him less than
a third of the value,
not even enough
to pay off the mortgage.
Why would he do that?
Well, apparently this guy
convinced him
that the world was
about to collapse
and if he wanted to leave
Jane and me anything...
..then he'd have to
sell it all off.
He knows. He's bluffing!
I don't bloody know.
I don't... don't think he does.
When he lies, he taps
the fingers on his left hand.
And leans to one side.
Yeah, his left. He's not lying.
You really weren't behind this?
Do you honestly think I am that bad?
Sorry, Cleave.
Everyone's just
a little bit emotional.
Would some cake help the jaw?
No, some cake wouldn't help.
How was the funeral?
Oh, um...Don spoke...at length.
I think Keith Nankervis's funeral
might have been the wise choice.
Is, um...is Melissa OK?
She's not exactly
looking in top form.
I'm sensitive to her needs.
Oh, that's what I was afraid of.
I'm sorry about your dad.
He was a lovely man.
‘Bye.
See you, darl.
That's not it, Dad.
What's not what, mate?
There is a life beyond death.
Yeah, it's called
becoming a judge.
Come to a prayer night
with me, please.
Oh, mate.
You always said not to judge something
without trying it first.
That was just drugs, alright?
In all other matters I'm very much
a “judge early and often” kind of a guy.
See ya.
Pull over.
Just pull over.
What are you doing to me, comrade?
You must be the only man alive
who could lose a defamation case
against Cleaver Greene.
Withdrew. Not lost.
First whiff of trouble,
you pop on a skirt and play dead.
What more do you want me to do?
I've denied it, she's denied it.
Would you please stop denying it?
We've won focus groups.
You're onto a good thing.
Women are taking notice of you.
Men are jealous. The chick is hot.
For a moment there you looked like
you might be a bit of a player.
I would have been
crucified in court.
I am a lawyer.
Soam I!
So's everyone.
Just go out there and own it,
or go to the back benches.
And how are you gonna
manage that, Jack?
We don't even have the numbers
to field a cricket team.
Who are you gonna promote, Allsop?
One more cock-up like this
and I'm giving you Health.
No. Not even in jest.
Lane Hole.
That's gotta be
his porn name, hasn't it?
This is the bloke
who cleaned my old man out.
What do you think about us
getting married and having a child?
Pardon?
Seeing the Nankervis family today,
how much they loved him,
how rich his life was because of family.
Yeah, uh...well, you also
met my family today.
You wouldn't describe that as rich.
We die. That's what struck me today.
Without loved ones,
it's all bullshit, Cleave.
Fucking Keith Nankervis.
Autumn leaves, hey?
Still, wouldn't be any kind of year
without them brightening our days.
I guess not.
A layer of scraps, leaves,
some fertiliser, seaweed —
perfect compost!
Speaking of which,
I'm looking for a Lane Hole.
A lot of people doing that.
He lives above me, in number two.
You have yourself a terrific day.
I take it you are
the delightfully named Lane Hole?
Yes.
I believe you saw fit
to defraud my father, Errol Greene,
of his share portfolio.
Your father signed the papers.
Yeah, while he was in care, and
for a third of what they were worth.
What sort of pond scum are you?
He was of sound mind.
Listen. Listen, mate.
Let me be crystal clear about this.
I am a criminal barrister
of considerable standing.
I win the unwinnables.
If you think you can cheat my family
and walk away untouched,
you are seriously fuckin' deluded.
Would you excuse me, please.
You have unleashed
a force of nature here, pal.
If you don't make
immediate recompense,
I will fuckin' crucify you in court.
OK.
So you'll pay back the money?
OK, what?
OK, see you in court.
Oh. OK, then.
You bet you will.
Who's gonna be the best guy
for this?
Treadwell? Morrison? Eddington?
No, mate.
It's gotta be Dominic Rose.
Dominic Rose?
Is he back from the UK?
Yeah, almost a year now.
Dominic Rose. Jesus, Barnyard.
Some excruciatingly boring people
are almost interesting for being that,
but Dominic Rose is like the...
..he's like the distilled
essence of boredom.
He's tedium in its purest form.
Yeah, you told him that once.
Shit, did 1?
Yeah, at a bar and bench party
about 15 years ago.
Oh, fuck. Oh, yeah.
Oh, well, he wouldn't remember that.
Listen, I have got to beat
this Hole prick.
Can you dig up whatever you can find
on the little worm, please?
Of course, Cleave. I've got
nothing else to do with my time.
Come on, mate.
Send Dominic a decent bottle
of plonk, hmm?
That's the way to his heart.
Hey.
Nicole!
Hey, you didn't text me back.
Yeah. Just got caught up.
Sorry.
Alright, no problem. Friend.
We are friends, right?
We are, I promise.
I've just been flat out.
Mmm. Sure.
You know. I'll...I'll see ya.
Alright, yep.
See you.
Nicole!
I need you to get in touch with the
7:30 Evening Tomorrow Project'.
What? What are you talking about?
The...the current affairs show.
And hook me up a little chat with
the hot one, Polly something.
Not the sanctimonious drone
with the eyebrows...
What am I, your pimp?
- I'll see you Saturday.
- Thank you for that.
Perfect. You've got my number?
Yes.
http://hiqve.com/
Dominic Rose!
As I live and breathe.
How bloody wonderful to see you.
Hello, Cleaver.
How long has it been, mate?
Bar and bench Christmas party,
about 15 years ago.
That's too long. Too long.
You told me I was the San Andreas
Fault line of boredom,
any less interesting
and you'd disappear into a coma.
Oh, mate.
I-'m so sorry about that.
The medication,
lashing out. Bleak period.
I don't know how many close friends
I hurt through that time.
How can I...how can I make it right?
Goodbye, Cleaver.
It's actually
an incredible coincidence,
because I was...I was just
thinking about you the other day.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
Because I've got a mate who gave me
a bottle of '71 Grange for my birthday.
The '71, you say?
Yeah.
And I was thinking,
who on earth do I know
who...who would really appreciate
a wine like this?
And I thought of you.
Ah, there you are.
Dominic, uh...
It's, uh...lovely of you to have me.
Come in, come in.
Ah.
Oh, no! I can't...
I grabbed the wrong bottle.
Miriam.
Cleaver, how lovely to see you.
He didn't bring it.
Told you.
The trouble with a lot of your
more erotic women's underwear
is it doesn't allow for the male hip —
it's constantly sagging.
For some time now I have been
buying my women's underwear
online from France.
Ooh.
Ah.
Shall I be mother?
Yes, darling.
It's just a simple chateaubriand.
But the sauce is an authentic
Napoleonic recipe.
Ah.
The meat — Tenterfield, grass-fed.
Ah, Tenterfield, grass.
And the tiniest hit
of Armagnac in the butter.
Mmmm.
Oh, it looks like
a vision of heaven, mate.
Uh, I came across a case
the other day that'd interest you.
It's this, uh...it's this Lance...
Oh, what? Oh, no, wait — Lane Hole.
I'm familiar with him.
Makes a big living dicing up
the elderly and infirm.
Sails close but technically
never breaks the law.
Really?
Mmm.
ASIC have prosecuted him
half a dozen times under 183
but failed every time.
183?
Potato?
Interesting.
Oh!
Shit. Shit.
God, it's a Janet Brown original.
God, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, mate.
Get a cloth. Get a cloth.
We need some salt.
I know, salt.
No, not salt. You'll stain it.
It's silk.
Polly Nesbitt's in your office.
Who?
You know,
that hack reporter you fancy.
Oh, great.
Uh, can you get me a copy
of Section 183
of the Corporations Act, please.
How do I look?
Like someone who's
spent their life in rehab?
Tim, I know you think I have
a diverse practice, mate,
but I cannot get over
to the Congo again.
And I cannot keep putting out these
political bushfires for you, mate.
Let...let me just
deal with Burma first, OK,
and then I'll try
and come over and join you.
Alright, see ya.
Polly, how are you?
The Congo, huh?
Yep.
Been there?
Yeah, I was Africa correspondent
with CNN for two years.
Where do you stay
when you're in Kinshasa?
Kinshasa Hilton.
I'm very time-poor, Mr Greene,
so is this a laughable attempt
at seduction,
or are you prepared
to make a deal?
Well, that's actually
quite a complex question.
I wouldn't have thought so.
Is Melissa prepared to go on camera?
She might be.
But she's a very skittish
sort of a person,
and you need to win her trust.
And how do I do that?
Well, the thing is, Melissa
was very fond of my father.
Mr Hole, if you have
nothing to hide,
then why can't you answer
a couple of simple questions?
Did you try and coerce a dying man
into giving over his life savings
just weeks before his death?
Mr Hole, why won't you answer?
Mr Hole. Oh! Fuck!
- Fuck, my foot.
- You right?
Oh, shit.
When my Ken died, this man came
and I signed some document,
but I didn't know what I was doing.
I lost my home and everything that
Ken and me had worked so hard for.
I have devoted my life
to seeking justice.
Here, the Congo, it doesn't matter.
Injustice, wherever it happens,
IS unacceptable to me.
Oh, God, I'm gonna throw up.
When the hell did he
ever go to Africa?
I have done this to the detriment
of my own career,
and sometimes, sadly,
to the detriment of my own family.
Dad's saving the world again.
Oh, shit, he's not, is he?
..I missed a great injustice
in my own home.
My father prided himself
on being an ordinary, decent man
who worked daily to put food
on the table for us kids
and to teach us the worth
of human values.
You stole that straight
from Keith Nankervis's funeral.
No!
Yes, you did.
..scum like Lane Hole
must not be allowed to sully it.
The question is,
can Cleaver Greene —
a man known for defending
lost causes —
find justice for his family?
Mahatma Gandhi said once,
“The human voice can never reach
the distance that is covered
“by the still, small voice
of conscience.”
Well, there sits a man
who has no such small voice —
his is a loud blare
of deceit and duplicity.
Lane Hole has faced no fewer
than 14 similar charges.
Prior to my father,
he succeeded in conning
some 23 pensioners and invalids
out of their income
and out of their family homes.
He robbed my father, on his deathbed,
of a lifetime of diligent saving
and wise investment.
But I speak today not only
on behalf of my family,
but on behalf of all those people
who have been injured
by this cruel and indifferent man.
It is time to put an end
to Lane Hole's relentless pursuit
of the weak and the vulnerable.
Mr Hole?
Your Honour, this matter
falls within the provisions
of Section 183
of the relevant legislation.
Yes.
Mr Greene?
Your Honour,
Section 183 of the act
clearly provides for remedies
for those who have been injured
by such malfeasance or neglect.
Mr Greene, are you
seriously suggesting
that Section 183
contemplates remedy?
Your Honour, I am holding the act
as we speak.
Mr Greene, you appear to be
holding the Corporations Act.
Indeed I am, Your Honour.
The Section 183
to which Mr Hole refers
is the Commercial
and Financial Trading,
Act
of 1998.
And I am aware of that,
Your Honour...
..but in a broader context...
There is no broader context,
Mr Greene.
The High Court has
made it abundantly clear.
Your Honour, this is a case
where justice itself is on trial.
No, the only thing on trial here is
whether 183 applies, and it does.
Your Honour, I have witnesses,
I have people whose lives
have been destroyed.
You may well have those,
but you don't have 183.
Anything else before
I find for the defendant
and award costs against you,
Mr Greene?
I could have done that.
And don't even think
of hitting us up for costs.
Lily.
That was a pretty short
crusade in all.
Must have been all that time
you spent in the Congo.
But I did love the Gandhi.
Do me here.
Someone will come.
Oh, good.
Ooh.
Justin?
Jesus Christ.
You slut.
You bloody little whore,
bastard, bitch!
Get out, Justin.
What?
Is this piece of shit gonna make me?
Listen...
Oh, it's Justin what's-his-name,
from your show.
Don't make me call the police.
You broke my heart, Pol.
You just tore it from my chest
and you trampled on it.
Please?
Please, I beg you, come back.
No, no, no. Come on, mate.
Oh, shit.
Shit! That's my favourite.
Don't ask.
We were sort of engaged and
I had this fling with his best friend.
You know how it is.
Uh-huh.
But he will not move on.
I need a drink.
I have met some walking sink hair
in my time, but Lane Hole...
Oh, boo-hoo.
A man who defends rapists
and cannibals now cries foul?
There's a moral dimension
to everything, you know.
There's no such thing as morality,
only personal choice.
Read Sartre and then read Camus.
Oh, fuck Camus.
The world is full of creeps.
What are you gonna do?
You gonna knock off
all the Lane Holes in the world?
Yes, I might just do that.
Get rid of Lane Hole,
then you and me, we're out of work.
The Lane Holes are our lifeblood.
Well, I have to find a way of dealing
with this particular Lane Hole.
I just haven't
figured out how yet.
Been to the court of public opinion,
been to the court of Section 183.
I know the law's an ass.
So just plug him.
You know anyone?
Plug him?
Mmm.
Oh, are you Bogart now?
It's Lauren Bacall, actually.
‘Big Sleep'.
Nice reference.
Oh, what the hell?
You owe me, Col.
If it wasn't for me...
Go home to bloody bed, Cleave.
Listen.. listen, Col,
You...you're happy, right?
Yes!
Yes? Yes?
State of bliss? Pigs in shit? Alright.
Well, this is the name of the guy
who stole my father's money, right?
Lane Hole.
That's his name, number, address,
everything you need to know.
You sort him out and
all of our problems will go away.
What, you want me to whack this guy?
No! No.
Not whack. Do not whack
under any circumstances.
Just, you know, ruffle his feathers
a little bit,
give him a little pinch on the arse,
let him know that nobody steals
from me, except for my secretary.
- But I know all about that.
- Collie Wobbles.
Who the fuck is it?
Mate, he stole from my father.
Alright?
OK, Cleave.
Do you get it?
Yeah.
You tell Lane Hole from me, mate,
that Cleaver Greene is every bit
as good as Keith Nankervis,
even if my dad never thought so.
I take it you've not read this.
No.
Mrs Dunstan said
Adam read it out for Show and Tell.
Oh, sorry I'm late.
I'm just trying
to set the record straight.
You should see the way
that they look at me.
The way who looks at you?
The mothers at the gate.
Friends of yours, are they?
No, not really.
Then why on earth
do you care what they think?
Oh!
Oh...
Col, if you're there, pick up.
Come on, pick up.
I've got a vague memory.
Look, just...f-forget
what I asked for, OK?
Don't touch Lane Hole, alright?
It was the booze talking.
I want nothing done to him.
Oh, just there.
Call off your dogs.
OK? I was barking, yes?
Ooh!
I crossed the line, almost.
Last night, for one horrible, insane
moment, I lost control of my life.
You don't honestly think there's only
been one moment, do you?
I sought revenge.
Can you believe it?
God, thank...thank God I saw reason.
You mean you sobered up?
The fact I was pissed
doesn't make it intrinsically wrong.
I've often been pissed
and made excellent choices.
Again, another dazzling moment
of self-awareness.
Christ, it's all so tenuous,
isn't it?
Fuzz really wants you to go with him
to a prayer meeting.
They're singing
Christian Socialists.
I'd rather have a tetanus shot.
Why do I have to go?
Because, Cleaver, this is
not my department, OK?
This is father-son stuff and...
What do you mean, father-son stuff?
It's about sex.
What do you mean, it's about sex?
She's a virgin.
She won't have sex with him
until they're married.
Well, that's not gonna happen
any time soon.
Of course it is. That's her power.
Have you seen
her pert little bottom?
Mmm.
Can you imagine
how frustrated he is?
Mmm.
Ask me how old her parents are.
How old are...
36 years old.
Much younger
and we could have had them.
They got married at 18.
That's what faith does to people.
They marry young
because they're sex-starved.
Just show him that you have
an open mind and he'll listen to you.
Alright, alright. OK. I'll...I'll go.
I'll invoke Satan's name,
do a 360 head-spin.
Thank you.
How are things with Roget?
Pretty good.
Ooh, pretty good.
How's Missy doing?
Missy wants to get married.
To you?
Yeah.
Oh, now I think she needs
to be hospitalised.
Did you read that flyer?
Don't mind me.
I don't mean to interrupt.
Bronwyn was just telling us
that she and Malcolm have
bought a house at Pearl Beach.
Lovely. Congratulations.
Yes, well, you know, it's always been
a bit of a dream.
Of course the next nine months
are gonna be a nightmare.
Will they? How so?
We're doing a bit of a reno.
Because it's just a shack right now,
doesn't even have internet.
So we're gonna have to
furnish and decorate,
and Malcolm's got
his heart set on Hockneys.
I don't know what that's about,
for a beach house.
We had the most awful fight
about it last night.
You poor thing.
Yeah, you poor thing.
That sounds like a real nightmare.
Mmm.
A real fucking nightmare.
Have you all got beach houses?
This is like a cancer cluster.
I never realised
how lucky my family was
to have been spared
a nightmare like that.
Oh, my grandmother was in Belsen
for a couple of months
when she was a young girl.
Sans Hockneys, by the way.
Are you quite done, Scarlet?
You know...I think I am.
Residents of Sydney's
southern suburbs are reeling
with the brutal murder
of a pensioner.
Albert Platt had lived among these
shady trees and streets for 50 years
till a senseless act of violence
brought his life to an end.
What an angry and frightened community
wants to know...
Oh, Jesus.
..Is what sort of monster...
..Is out there preying on...
Oh, no.
..on the elderly and infirm.
What?
Oh, please, tell me
it's a coincidence.
A police spokesman said
they were pursuing
several lines of inquiry...
- Tell me you got my message.
- Your message?
Oh, right, the one
cancelling the hit?
It was never a hit.
It was a pinch, remember?
Yeah, yeah, I got the message.
So you didn't go?
No.
Oh, thank God.
I subbed it out.
You what?
I was, you know, busy
so I subbed it out.
You...you subbed what out?
You mean you told somebody else
to visit Lane Hole?
Mate, we sub out
a lot of work in our game.
Is...is there any...any possibility
that your friend may have visited
the wrong friend?
Dunno. Never had him
visit friends before.
Oh, fuck. Oh, Jesus.
Oh, my God.
Oh.
Mate, why are you so stressed?
Oh, apart from the fact that
a lovely old leaf-raking man living in
the flat below our friend is dead,
you mean, ignoring that, Col?
I'm a little concerned that
I was filmed on national television
threatening the man who lives
in the flat above him.
Do you understand?
And I'm a little worried that
your work experience pal
might be so FUCKING THICK
that he went to the wrong flat!
Oh, shit.
- Is Mr Greene in?
- Yes.
Mr Greene, I'm so sorry.
It was a breakdown in communication,
partly me, partly him.
Who are you?
I'm a friend of Col
and Kirsty's, you know.
Oh. Please tell me what I think
happened didn't happen.
It won't happen again, you have
my absolute assurance on that.
Can I ask you not to make
a big deal of this?
What?
I'm trying to set myself up in a new
town, make the right connections.
A mistake like this
could set me right back.
So what say no charge,
and we'll forget it.
No charge.
Oh, Jesus Christ!
It's the Rapture.
When I was, like, 14,
I was a real mess, just like you,
and I fought Jesus all the way,
I mean, I wouldn't let him in.
Here was this guy who'd lived
this sinless life full of love,
and, you know,
he died on a cross for us,
and I just thought, “How do
I compete with that,” you know?
But then he came
and he spoke into my heart,
“I forgive you everything, Tara.
“Leave your sins behind
and come and walk with me.”
And I fell to my knees and I said,
“I am yours, Lord. Take me to you.”
And I was reborn.
Praise the Lord.
You alright, Dad?
Oh, great.
J Can you hear us?
♪ Can you hear us?
♪ Can you feel him?
♪ I can feel him
♪ Can you feeeeeel him?
♪ Jesus, we are here tonight
♪ Can you feel him? ♪
Oh, Jesus.
Oh, God.
Dad?
Oh-ho-ho, Jesus!
Dad, stop making a dick of yourself.
Oh, God!
Dad!
God.
Cleaver Greene?
We're here to arrest you
on a charge of manslaughter.
♪ Oh, can you feel him? ♪
Oh, Jesus!
♪ Yes, I can feel him... ♪
♪ Yes, I can feel him.... ♪
♪ Yes, I feeeeeel
♪ Jesus, we are here tonight
♪ Oooh. ♪
http://hiqve.com/