For any new inmate,
the first day in our small hell
is usually the worst,
but for Cleaver Greene,
every day was worse than the last,
and that's how we wanted it.
Cleaver had no shortage of enemies -
former attorney general Cal McGregor,
close mate of the Justice Minister
and therefore untouchable.
My right-hand man, Colin Mancusi
and me, Mick Corella,
who would never forgive that fucking dog
for tooling my wife, Kirsty.
And then there was my brother.
Georgie had already done 12 years
of a 160-year stretch
when I was put away - quadruple murder.
What he did to those fellas
even makes me turn white,
and I cut a bloke
into a dozen little pieces
and had him buried under asphalt.
All the other blokes thought
we'd be as thick as,
but my first day inside was the first
day we'd seen each other for 20 years.
It was the first time we'd met
since I stole his fiancée,
Kirsty Fitzgibbon, from him.
The power of love should never
be underestimated.
I figured, after 20 years,
Georgie might have got over Kirsty,
but I couldn't have been more wrong.
I'm not going to tell you
how he killed me,
‘cause I'm sensitive like that.
Welcome to the end of days,
and abandon all fucking hope,
ye who enter here.
It is the unanimous finding
of this court
that the guilty verdict in the case
of the Crown and Greene was unsafe.
The trial itself was riddled with
untrustworthy witnesses,
three of whom have been convicted
of perjury as a result.
We find that His Honour erred
in both allowing and disallowing
certain crucial pieces of evidence
to be put and not put before the jury.
Given the totality of these egregious
miscarriages in the passage of time,
we did not find that a fair
and transparent trial could be held.
The conviction is therefore quashed,
and the appellant is free to go.
Yes.
I've built up a bit of a hunger
and a bit of a thirst.
A man's not a camel.
Harry!
I wasn't expecting to see you here.
I just wanted
to be one of the first to say
that I knew you'd eventually
beat this thing, Cleaver.
Oh, mate. That's very decent of you.
‘Cause you always manage
to slime your way out of things.
- David!
- Always.
A sweet old man is dead because of you,
but it's time to party,
isn't it, Cleaver?
I told you I'd put an end to you
one day.
Malcolm!
For the love of Judith Christ, mate,
do we have to have this conversation
again?
Look, it's not that I don't like you.
I do, as a friend, OK?
But I'm telling you,
for the five billionth time,
it's not going to happen.
- This is more than just a prison thing.
- So you keep saying.
You're my rock. You're my port
in a storm. You're my soulmate.
I can't be your rock
and your port in a storm, mate,
‘cause that's just a shipwreck.
I can't help feeling this way.
And I can't help not feeling that way.
I can't help not being
sexually attracted to you.
It's nothing personal, mate,
it's just the way I was built.
I get out in six weeks.
We don't have much time together.
Look, you're tired.
We're all tired.
I can't remember
the last good night's sleep I had.
Sorry.
Oh, for the love of perpetual motion,
will you stop it?
Mate, I've been in here 11 months
and I can't think of a single thing
worth having a go at myself over.
You've been in here 17 years.
It's only possible because of you.
That's it!
I wish I was on laundry detail.
How do you get on laundry detail?
Kitchen's not that bad.
I've known fine dining.
I've known eggs
that didn't come in powdered form.
I've known meat
that came from actual cows.
So Georgie's got his stuff
for breakfast, right?
Yes.
Georgie's got his stuff for breakfast.
'l have met them, close of day,
coming with vivid faces
from counter or desk among grey,
18th-century houses.'
Oh, Patrice!
You look...
..happy with yourself today.
Got a new arrival coming.
Oh, yeah?
Kirsty's nephew, Connor.
Got done for extortion.
Lovely boy. Kirsty dotes on him.
Figured I might take him under my wing,
look after him.
Kirsty would appreciate that,
don't you think?
'Course, mate.
She'll come. I know she will.
She'll come...
..see us, see her boys.
'Course she will.
Fuck! Why are you telling me that
over breakfast?
Where are you going to stay
when you get out?
I don't know. My sister's?
You'll be a free man. You've got your
whole life waiting for you out there.
I've been in here since I was 18,
Cleave.
- I've got no life outside.
- You're going to have to start one.
Who's going to give me a job?
I murdered my dad.
Who beat your mum to death. Yeah?
- That's not the way the judge saw it.
- Oh, I remember old Fitzie.
Crazy old fucker.
Can we get a bit of volume?
Justice Kieran Webster was sentenced
to six years for perjury
- and corruption...
- Fuck!
..In relation to the now infamous
Cadamaya land deal.
- Another one.
- The former judge was a friend
of former Labor Party power broker
and Planning Minister, Vince McCarthy.
Vincie!
..and former Gaming Minister,
Paul Fennely...
Hey, Pauly!
..who are both serving eight years
for their role in the Cadamaya scandal.
Sentences are expected to be passed
on five others later this week.
No, no, it's OK.
Oh, really?
What about Stein? He's a bloody silk.
I thought he was...
Shit!
All rise.
Be seated.
This is a very serious matter
that could affect the cohesion
of our community.
I'd like to thank my fellow judges
for making themselves available
at such short notice.
The court would also like to send
its best wishes for a speedy recovery
to Mr Stein QC, who somehow
lost a fucking ear last night.
Mr Greene will appear in his place.
Let's hear the charges.
Today,
Your Lordship and Your Honours sit
to oversee a charge against our friend
Tonto here,
of, quote, "Trying to slip one up Paddo
while they were on laundry detail,
unquote.
My friends of the jury,
you all know Tonto.
This is his fourth stretch for B and E.
Never copped a plea.
Never took a lesser charge,
never, ever grassed -
a thief whose honour is beyond dispute.
What happened in the laundry
was an easily explained accident.
Gentlemen, there is no way that I will
dispute the honour of a good thief.
I am many things
but I am not a hypocrite.
This case is not about B and E,
my friends, it is about B and D.
Objection.
It's a fucking good line.
I'm going to allow it.
Despite my friend's submission,
Your Lordship cannot possibly accept
a slipped-in-the-shower defence
for the simple reason
the offence did not occur in the shower,
it occurred in the laundry.
Your Lordship, the slipped-in-the-shower
defence is honoured in every wing
of every jurisdiction in the land,
not just literally
but in its clearly intended spirit.
I find that a very broad interpretation,
Mr Greene.
Absolutely, yes - fucking broad.
My Lord, we all know what is meant by
‘slipped in the shower.'
It means that
the incident was an accident.
It's an allegory, a conceit.
Your Lordship, whatever the currency or
plausibility of the expression may be,
it derived from the fact that when
people in showers slip, they are naked.
People on laundry detail are not naked.
This was an attack on Paddo.
I am reliably instructed
that Paddo, in what may have been
an innocent bout of rambunctiousness,
flung a bucket of water over my client
and himself, rendering them both sodden.
My client was the sodden one, Cleaver.
My client and Paddo,
in this brutal winter period,
were forced to remove
their moistened clothes
in order to put on dry ones.
The floor in the meantime,
having become moist and slippery,
was a water trap.
My client slipped, instinctively
grabbing Paddo's shoulders
to break his fall.
My client has absolutely no form
in this area,
whereas we all know Paddo's reputation
for receiving swollen goods.
Yes. Well, I reckon he's got you there.
My brethren?
Jury?
Fair enough. Case dismissed.
Out you get, son.
And you, Your Honour.
Oh, fuck.
- What?
- It's Kirsty's nephew, Connor.
That's his sister's boy.
You met him, yeah?
Oh, yeah. He's an annoying little shit.
Oh, Jesus.
Jesus!
- Kirsty adores him, Cleave.
- So what?
So? So he knows about me and Kirsty.
He used to come around the house all
the time. He had a key, for fuck's sake.
- There was one night when we were...
- What?
Col, you're not still
in contact with Kirsty, are you?
- Oh, mate.
- Wouldn't you be,
if she was the love of your life?
You don't know what it's been like
for this last year,
not being able to see her face,
her smile.
She can't even visit.
If Georgie finds out...
- Well, they didn't kill me.
- Why would they? You were just a root.
Just a root, was 1?
I think if you ask Kirsty,
you'll get a different opinion.
Everyone knows you were just a root,
mate.
I was intimate with her.
I won her heart.
When Connor busted us,
I was painting her toenails.
- Oh, fuck.
-'Oh, fuck' is right, mate.
Our Lord said, 'Let he who is
without sin cast the first stone.'
No-one here is without sin,
nor is anyone, for that matter,
on God's great earth.
Our salvation will come
from acknowledging that sin.
So when was the last time
you saw your aunty?
In court.
She was there
pretty much the whole trial.
She was wearing a blue dress... low cut.
Hungry, are you, my boy?
Wouldn't mind a burger.
Burger it is, then. Patrice!
Alright there, Kieran?
First shower is a real chuckle,
isn't it?
You'll be right, Kieran.
You'll be right.
We're all friends in here,
Your Honour!
Knock it off, you pricks!
- Look at the size of that!
- He's pissed himself!
Oh, come on, fellas.
Give the poor bastard a break.
I said, knock it off!
Kieran!
Audition time on Aussies Gotta Sing.
Your spirits will fly.
They may touch your heart.
Hey, pretty boy!
But which one has what it takes
fo make it to the next round
of Aussies Gotta Sing?
What's up, mate?
Slipped in the shower.
You what?
I slipped in the shower.
You slipped in the shower
with someone else?
What?
I knew you'd find someone
better than me.
No! I didn't slip in the shower,
I slipped in the shower on some soap.
Not fucking funny!
Oh, mate. Mate, come here.
- Come here.
- What? What are you doing?
- Here.
- Malcolm!
Watch your head.
I told you,
this is not going to happen.
Relax, Cleave! I know what I'm doing.
Oh, my God. Malcolm!
Just relax.
There may be a problem here.
L5, S1. This could be a prolapse.
Oh, God!
How does that feel, Cleave?
Is itin?
Shut up, you fucking dogs!
Just relax.
Just breathe in and breathe out.
How's that? Is that better, mate?
Where did you learn to do that?
I spent the first seven years
in this cell with an osteopath.
- Wow.
- Walter Bell.
He strangled his wife to death
with a necktie,
which was strange,
‘cause he had such big, strong hands.
Maybe this is what you should be doing
when you get out - massage.
I've been thinking, Cleave -
maybe I should stay.
It's the only way that makes any sense
for us.
What do you mean, 'us'?
And what are you talking about -
extend your stay?
It's not a hotel, mate.
Not a good one.
Average at best, by Sydney standards.
Come on, mate. You should never have
been in here in the first place.
You wouldn't have been
if I'd defended you.
I know, mate. I know.
Mal. You've got every right to think of
the world beyond these walls
as a stinking pit of despair
and injustice,
and to a certain extent, it is.
But there is also happiness
out there, mate.
I've spotted it on at least three
separate occasions.
You will find it, but you're going to
need to have a little faith in yourself,
and you're going to have to have
some courage.
Oh, fuck!
I want to sing, Cleave.
That's what I want to do.
Oh, Jesus.
I've never told another living soul,
but I want to sing.
Why didn't you just burst into song
instead of shoving your tongue
down my throat?
I never thought anyone
would ever listen.
Mate...
I'll listen.
People will listen, as long as
you make the effort to be heard.
OK? Live the dream.
Live the dream, my friend.
Visitor, Cleave.
Are you carrying, Fergie?
- Chocky, nuts?
- Sorry, Cleave.
Aunty Kirsty sends her love.
Are you seeing her today?
Nah. There's been a bit of a mix-up.
You and me should talk, son.
- Who are you seeing?
- Don't know.
- You don't know?
- Kirsty's coming.
She's bringing some bloke who's
going to pretend to be my mate,
- s0 Georgie doesn't find out.
- Oh, mate.
Cleave, I get to see her, mate!
Do me a favour -
wait here, let me go in first.
I don't want her freaking out.
George.
So good to see you, Kirsty.
Please, have a seat.
Yeah. Well,
I'm actually just here to see Connor.
You look wonderful.
The years have been very kind.
Connor sends his love.
- He's OK?
- Oh, he's fine, yeah.
He just got his times mixed up.
- Asked me to see you instead.
- Yeah, well...
Shame about Mick, but, well,
given he's no longer with us...
George, it's been 20 years.
Love is neither boarded
nor bound by time, Kirsty.
George, please.
- Where are you going?
- You don't really expect...
I've been waiting for this day
for 20 years.
You're wasting your fucking time.
I want to see Connor.
- There's someone else again!
- Goodbye, George.
Is there someone else?
It's not still him, is it?
It can't still be him!
No, Georgie, it's not still me.
Is it, Kirsty?
No, it's not still him.
Then who is it?
Talk to me, mate.
His blood will be mine!
Jesus!
Oh, yes. It's all good panto in here.
Why are you limping?
I slipped in the shower.
Oh, Cleaver!
What is wrong with everybody?
I slipped in the shower, OK?
On some soap.
So, ah, I read the appeal books.
That looks pretty good.
Yeah, but we still don't have a date.
I thought they're supposed to know
by the end of the month?
There's been some backlog, apparently.
Barney and I are worried that they might
be waiting for the right combination.
- Of what?
- Of judges.
So by 'the right combination'
you mean, 'the wrong combination.'
Hartford, Styles and Menzies
is what I'm hearing.
Hartford, Styles and Menzies? Oh, Jesus.
That's not a fucking appeal,
that's an inquisition.
We're not sure yet. OK?
What about Bill Dempsey? He'd be fair.
I set him up
with a couple of weathergirls one time.
He's suddenly on sabbatical
in Cambridge.
You're joking?
And I believe that Charlotte Georges
is in the frame
for the vacancy on the High Court.
They'd put Charlotte Georges
on the High Court to keep me in prison?
They'd make her queen if it kept you
in prison for another 13 years.
Oh, my God.
I brought you in some food.
Did you get the duck?
I've been dreaming about duck.
I can't bring you in meat,
you know that.
Just bring it in, goddammit!
Georgie gets lobsters flown in
from Fiji.
He's got Patrice from La Belle Epoque
working as his personal chef.
- The arsonist?
- He's not an...
Well, it was his own restaurant,
and it's the only bloody thing
he's burned in his life.
Come on - what did you get?
Rice, muesli,
Vegemite and water crackers.
So nothing that had parents?
http://hiqve.com/
What?!
Hey, Georgie.
I believe it's your birthday.
Many happy returns, mate.
You know when you're having
a really fucking crook day
and then you get a blinding headache,
but there's a part of you
that's sort of grateful for the pain
because you can't worry about
anything else?
Strangely liberating.
Well, I was at that point of liberation,
you walking sack of shit,
when you knocked on my door.
You've got to know I've wanted
to kill you since the day you got here.
Funny thing, I've enjoyed
the anticipation of killing you so much,
I haven't been able
to get around to doing it.
There's something
I think you should know about Kirsty.
You know I've spent a lot of time
with her over the years.
So, you know, we got to be pretty close.
The truth is, and she's mentioned this
to me more than once,
she's always regretted leaving you
for Mick.
Biggest mistake of her life,
she calls it.
Oh, bullshit!
Mate, she's just so fucking terrified
of hurting you again, mate.
That's why she seems so,
I don't know, distant.
She could never hurt me!
I think... I might be able
to put in a word,
get her to visit again.
I'm having a bit of a birthday dinner
tonight.
You might want to join us.
Yeah. That'd be great.
Nice work.
I think I might have
underestimated you, Col.
Maybe we should
start talking about a deal, hey?
What are you doing, mate?
It's fine.
They just needed a little trimming.
- Are you serious?
- It may have got a bit out of control.
But I was just...
You've got to understand,
I'm going insane with hunger here.
I just trimmed off a little sliver,
just for a taste,
then it looked kind of weird
against the other ones,
so I sort of evened them up.
Then the knife slipped on the third one.
Fuck, he's got four anyway.
Yeah, but he ordered 200z rumps.
It's his birthday!
I don't know.
Tell him they're eye fillets.
It's a better cut anyway.
He'll never know.
I didn't order eye fillet,
I ordered rump.
This is disfigured rump, which is
exactly what you're about to be.
We just delivered what we got, mate.
Bullshit!
Patrice, is that what you ordered?
No.
I've already given you one life,
Cleaver.
I don't recall giving anyone a second.
This is my birthday.
- Many happy returns.
- And someone has swiped my dinner.
Mate, it wasn't me, honestly!
I swear,
I'm basically a vegan these days.
I'm treating this whole prison thing
as a state-sanctioned detox.
It was on your watch.
If it wasn't you, then who was it?
No idea, mate, yeah.
There's only one prick
who'd have the balls,
because he knows I can't touch him,
because the fucking Justice Minister
is his daughter's godfather.
Was it Cal?
You know Cal. Was it him?
Yeah. Yeah, it could be.
All I can say is, that's how they were
when we found them.
Do you want me to sort him out for you,
Georgie?
Yes.
You up for it, Col?
You are with me, aren't you, mate?
Yeah, of course, Georgie.
Oh, no. No!
So you think you can
put one over on Georgie?
- No!
- Fucking dog!
And on his fucking birthday too, eh?
What do you want, Connor?
Georgie said
I should come join the party.
Cleaver, get out.
Get the fuck out, you dog.
Hold on, mate.
I've been thinking about your offer,
and I think you might need
to make it a little better now, eh?
Cleaver!
Cleaver, good to see you.
Roachie?
The music's a little bit too loud.
I love a good fugue.
They can be a little baroque sometimes,
don't you reckon?
After you.
Thank you, Watto.
Just wait outside for me, please.
Mm.
So, how're you travelling?
Well, it's a long and winding road, Cal.
That has led you to my door.
I hear Georgie gave you
a bit of a skinning.
What can I do for you, mate?
Past few days, Georgie's been giving me
a bit of the stink eye.
- How can you tell?
- I can tell.
The man's a rageoholic.
Now, as you will have observed,
over the course of last year,
Georgie and I have reached
a gentlemen's agreement,
and managed to leave each other in peace
and get on managing our own affairs.
I am aware.
I wouldn't want to see anything
threaten that agreement.
It wouldn't be
in anyone's best interest,
not with my parole hearing coming up.
The Parole Board does love
a little bit of repentance.
Good thing I wrote that
in the guidelines, eh?
So, what I want to hear from you is
if that psycho is
making some sort of move on me.
I wouldn't know, Cal.
Your appeal is coming up soon, isn't it?
I could get in touch with
my former colleague
and very, very, good mate, the Justice
Minister, and see what he could do.
I could call him
and make sure you get royally screwed,
maybe even an extended sentence,
get you sent to Goulburn.
Supermax! The rest of your sentence
would crawl by then.
Why would Georgie tell me anything?
I don't know, mate. That's your problem.
Oh, Cleaver...
..I have two porterhouses
in the freezer.
If they are so much as
slightly seasoned,
you will never see the light of day
again,
I swear to my maker.
Gents.
God bless.
Is he OK?
Couldn't be better, mate.
Oh, yes. Swimming in stink eye.
Kieran!
Mate, what did you do?
- What do you mean?
- Georgie Corella.
Georgie Corella?
Don't look him in the eyes!
No, don't look down. Just act normal.
Normal.
Normal! Yeah.
Word is he's got
the serious shits with you.
You must have said or done something.
Cleaver, I don't have a clue
what you're talking about.
I never speak to the man.
Once Georgie gets an idea in his head,
that's it.
You must have seen the way he was
giving you the stink eye then.
Me?
- Good luck, mate.
- Cleaver!
Help me! Please, I beg you.
Alright. Just...
I tell you what I'm going to do.
I'm going to talk to Georgie for you.
He and I go back.
- Thank you, Cleaver.
- Watch your back, mate.
What was all that about?
What was all what about?
You and His Holiness.
A man with an appeal coming up
would do just about anything
to make sure that appeal
goes the right way, won't he?
Cal's going to make a move against me
with the Minister.
What's he offering you?
Nothing. I don't think he's going to
make a move against you, Georgie.
You're not going to make a move
against him, are you?
You're a funny bugger sometimes.
I'll give you that, Cleave.
Listen. Mal, now, whatever I say,
just back me up, OK?
Always. You know that.
OK. Don't touch! Don't do that.
So, Kieran,
I think I've managed
to talk Georgie down for the time being.
The problem with Georgie is
he has wild mood swings.
- Did he say what it was I did?
- That you gave him the stink eye.
- How could I give him the stink eye?
- I don't know.
I haven't stopped crying
since I came here.
I don't know.
Now listen. This is Malcolm.
He's a mate of mine.
He's been in here 17 years.
Nobody fucks with Malcolm, OK?
He's going to be your shadow for
a while when we're out of the cells.
I'll have your back, mate.
So to speak.
If Georgie does
have one of his mood swings,
he'll think twice
if you've got Malcolm by your side.
Thank you, Cleaver. Thank you, Malcolm.
No, that's fine, mate. That's fine.
You two are going to get on
like a house on fire.
The conversations!
You do both like a show tune.
You're partial to a bit of Puccini,
aren't you, Kieran?
I don't know what to say.
If there's anything I can do...
No, it's fine. Fine.
Actually, now that you mention it...
Could we just have a moment?
Thanks, Mal.
Um...
..my appeal is coming up
in a couple of months
and I did hear that they were thinking
about Hartford, Styles and Menzies.
- Oh, Christ.
- Yes. That was my reaction.
What could I do from in here?
Well, you're thick with the Chief,
aren't you?
Yes, but maybe not so much now.
Yes. It's going to be his choice
who's sitting, isn't it?
Come on.
Come on, mate.
Don't get all doe-eyed on me.
You were done for perjury
and corruption.
OK, fine. If you don't want to help...
No, no. Cleaver!
How can I get a message to him?
I can't call him.
Well, is Margaret coming to visit
any time soon?
Yes, tomorrow.
Well, there we are.
Trust me, mate,
this is how things get done in here.
We look after each other, OK?
So have you been to the actual opera?
How's uni?
Fine.
And Tara, all good there?
Yeah, yeah.
- We're thinking of going away together.
- Just to Bali.
- Ah, beautiful.
Remember when we went to Bali?
Of course.
Yes. Your mother told me
she could ride a moped.
She lied.
How's Roger?
- He's fine.
- Is he?
Yeah. He sends his best.
Does he? Send him mine.
Come on, mate.
Something must have happened out there.
It's been two months. You know,
have you had your first bong yet?
Are you doing any nude work with Tara
that I need to know about?
- Nope.
- No?
Just studying, then off to Bali.
Right. Look, guys - I get it.
It's awkward.
I have mentioned previously,
I don't want you coming here if you're
doing it out of a sense of obligation.
- It doesn't do any of us...
- We like coming.
I used to have to visit clients here.
Nobody likes coming here, alright?
I'm settled and I'm coping.
Let's just skip the next visit
and I'll see you at the appeal.
Are you sure you think the appeal
is a good idea?
What do you mean?
I've read these studies,
and a lot of people in your situation
can find the loss of an appeal more
devastating than the initial conviction
because they get a fresh taste
of freedom,
then they have to learn
to forget it again.
Look, I'm feeling very bullish
about the appeal.
You saw what a joke my trial was.
Scarlet thinks there's a problem.
Scarlet always thinks
there's a fucking problem!
- It's the curse of her people.
- Cleave...
Look, the appeal will be fine.
Just a little finessing of the bench
and off we go.
Finessing of the bench?
What I do best.
Come on, team!
A bit of faith, please.
I'll see you at the appeal.
I've got to go to the loo.
Why are you telling me that?
I don't want you to worry.
- Night, Kieran.
- Thank you, Cleaver.
Night, mate. Sleep tight.
He seems like a good bloke.
- Yeah.
- It's funny, isn't it?
He's scared to be here,
I'm scared to be leaving.
You won't know yourself, Mal.
That's just it, Cleave -
I won't know myself.
I don't know what the fuck
I'm going to do.
Grow up and stop being
this whiny little fucking child!
You're getting the one thing every man
in here wants - your freedom.
The way it looks at the moment,
I'm going to be in here
for another 13 years.
I'm sorry, mate.
Get out of the way!
Move!
I have no idea what happened in there.
I barely knew Connor.
There was no interaction between us.
It was movie night,
but you don't have to watch it.
You can come and go as you please.
It's not like Supermax.
- Did the watch the whole movie?
- Fuck, yeah. It was a ripper.
Indeed. I sat through the whole thing.
Poor Connor. He was a good boy.
Lord, let us commend the spirit
of our friend, Connor Fitzgibbon,
into your loving embrace.
May you hold him and keep him.
So you went for a piss
about halfway through?
- Yeah.
- And then?
Then I saw the stairs
going up to the court,
at least that's what we call
Georgie's compound.
Then I saw a shadow.
I thought it must be Connor.
It was. I climbed up the stairs
and I picked up whatever I could find -
a chair.
I just ran at him with it.
- So you're saying you killed him?
- Yeah.
Why?
He was rude.
I don't like rude people.
You did not kill Connor.
I know you didn't.
- Yeah, I did.
- No, you didn't.
- Why?
- I told you, he was rude.
- No, mate. You're not a killer.
- You know I am, Cleave.
Malcolm, this is just about you
trying to find a way
to stay in this cesspit, isn't it?
I'm prepared to do whatever time
the state sees fit.
Have you given any thought to the fact
that the state, in its infinite wisdom,
might not want to send you back
to our cosy little hacienda?
They might want to send you off
to Supermax. Did that occur to you?
Yeah. Why would they do that?
It's just another murder.
No, it's not.
You have confessed to the brutal killing
of someone.
They're going to decide that
you're too dangerous for this place,
and they're going to send you
to fucking Goulburn,
if you make it to trial alive.
Maybe I made a mistake.
Do you reckon?
What have you come as?
Did you think it was fancy dress today?
Yeah? Come on, baby!
Put some skin on me, baby.
What kind of a mid-life crisis
are we looking at here?
It's not like you're about to appear
on the cover of Harper's any time soon.
- Really?
- And I can go home and get changed.
Can you? Maybe you should,
before you come in here.
It was Sports Day at the school, mate.
So you decided to wear a shirt saying,
'fo' yo mama'
to your children's Sports Day
at that school? How did that go down?
What's wrong?
It's not like it's 'mofo.'
- It is basically ‘mofo.'
- No, no.
- It's "fo yo mama' - ‘for your mother.'
- 'For your mother?'
It's sweet, isn't it?
I don't know, baby.
You'd better ask your homies.
Mate, Malcolm bashed his father to death
with a phone.
Yeah, but he didn't kill Connor.
I'm not saying he did or didn't.
I'm just saying, he's currently serving
a sentence for a violent murder.
He's admitted to committing
another violent murder,
and he's given the police
a credible motive.
He's just shit-scared
about getting out of here.
He's never known any other life.
Come on, Barnyard.
Hello!
Is there a lawyer in there somewhere?
I'm talking about the evidence.
He's screwed, mate.
Mr Greene will no doubt tell you
what a good bloke Mal is.
We all like him.
That's what makes this case so hard.
If we are to let brutal murderers off
just because they're good blokes,
my friends,
that is the first step towards anarchy.
Make no mistake,
the defendant in this case
is already a convicted murderer.
A convicted murderer.
The truth is, Malcolm did what he did
because he watched his father
torture his mother for 18 years.
He did what he did
because his father beat his mother
to death with a lamp.
His father was acquitted.
Malcolm had no representation
when he spoke to the cops,
and he met his counsel
15 minutes before the trial kicked off.
So my friend's attempt to characterise
the murders of the deceased
and Malcolm's father as identical
in nature is patently absurd.
Malcolm had no quarrel with Connor,
none whatsoever.
There is someone, though, who did.
You're calling me?
You're not that fucking stupid.
You call me, you're a dead man.
What happened, Col?
Come on, the truth.
Mal doesn't deserve to be cut
and he doesn't deserve to spend
the rest of his life in Goulburn.
- What happened?
- I had to move fast.
I had no choice. He was going to
sell me down the river, mate.
So who did it?
Griffo.
Griffo. Double lifer.
Yeah, so it's no skin off his nose.
They've been giving him mum 25 grand
for the rest of her life
just to keep him sweet,
50 grand if he takes the rap.
- Will he take the rap?
- Yeah, if I give him the word.
I'd like to call Griffo, Your Lordship.
Griffo.
Cleave.
Did you do it, mate?
- Yeah.
- Prepared to tell the cops?
Yeah.
Well, I reckon that just about
does it, eh?
If only the wheels of justice would turn
this efficiently in the outside world.
Get off me. Not in front of the boys.
- You came.
- Yeah.
A girl can only withstand so much.
Sorry about Connor.
Oh, well, yeah. It's a tragedy,
but at least you've got a friend in here
in Col.
Col?
Georgie?
You'll never know loyalty like his.
Trust me.
Of course I do.
Yeah, fine. I understand. Right.
Sorry, Cleave.
The Chief said it was a no-go. Too hot.
How can it be too hot?
They're all judges, aren't they?
It's not like I'm asking them
to put a crack dealer on the bench,
I just want it to be fair.
Hartford by himself, fine.
But Hartford, Menzies and Styles,
are you fucking kidding me?
Styles gave evidence against me.
Yeah, there you go.
Fucking hypocrite.
Hello, stranger.
I thought you weren't going to be back
for a couple of months.
Just a quick press junket.
Oh, yeah. So is it all done now?
Almost.
- Potsy happy?
- Richie.
Richie.
What was the budget again?
70 million.
So how's the appeal coming?
You know I can
afford a truckload of silks.
No, Barney and Scarlet are handling it.
That's as it should be.
I had a drink with your archenemy
last night.
I've gathered so many over recent years.
- David.
- David, of the Harry-sorry clan?
- Mm.
- Sad family.
A bit of inbreeding there, I think.
Have you noticed how his eyes
don't quite line up?
Do you want to have a conversation
or deflect one?
At least you seem free to talk,
so that's a good thing.
Everybody else is so fucking stilted.
I did a quick mental calculation
the other day.
I added up all the crimes I actually
have committed,
as opposed to this one,
that I didn't commit.
In terms of sentencing, it sort
of balances out, you know what I mean?
So what I was thinking was,
if the appeal doesn't get up,
I really don't want you coming here.
Yeah. Yeah, right.
I'm serious.
What? You don't want visitors?
No, I don't want you visiting me.
You remind me of freedom,
and I don't want to have to
learn to forget it every time I see you.
Do you understand what I mean?
Come on, mate.
I thought you had to be married
to get one of these.
I have friends.
Anyway, in my heart,
we've always been married.
Your trial was a bloody travesty,
Cleaver.
I know.
I'd be having the DPP look into this
if it wasn't one of the main culprits.
I'm still screwed, aren't I?
It's basically Styles.
Whatever way he goes,
he's going to bully the other two.
That's how it usually happens.
Why did you call him a hypocrite?
- What?
- The other day.
You said Styles was a hypocrite.
There may be a way around this.
What?
You know this Cadamaya bullshit?
It's bullshit because you got busted.
- It's nothing.
- What do you mean, it's nothing?
There's another deal.
It's out there as we speak,
and it's about fifty times bigger
and more rotten than Cadamaya.
- What is it?
- Bearbung, Cleaver.
Bearbung.
Bearbung?
Talk to me, Kieran.
http://hiqve.com/