Kerri, the chapel
was overflowing with mourners
here to farewell Joshua Floyd,
slain founder of the leaks site
good _plumbing.com.
Chief amongst them, of course,
was Floyd's fiancée,
author and ex-prostitute
JM Doolan,
who is out on bail, having been charged
with Floyd's murder.
She refuses
to speak to media herself
but her barrister,
human rights advocate Cleaver Greene,
did speak to assembled media.
Nothing has been laid to rest today,
not by a long stretch.
Josh's work will continue.
Those who sought to end
his quest for justice,
truth and democracy,
the despots who murdered him,
who literally
stabbed him in the back,
those bastards who now point their
fingers at the woman who loved him,
they will be brought to justice.
This I promise you.
Mr Greene.
One more question, Mr Greene.
Oh, Mum. You can't be serious?
He's milking it for everything
it's bloody worth.
What are you saying?
I'm saying
Dad's finally in the papers
without the word ‘allegedly'
near his name
and he wants to keep it that way.
Fuzz, I haven't seen your father
like this...for 15 years.
I mean, he might have finally
found a cause
that's actually worth fighting for.
You're not thinking
what I think you're thinking?
Well, it's the dream of every child
from a broken home that, one day,
that home be rebuilt.
Yeah, when I was four, maybe.
Five at a stretch. But by the time
I reached six, all I felt was relief.
I beg your pardon?
You and Dad don't function together,
Mum. It's like a law of science.
The quality of your relationship
is in inverse proportion
to its geographic proximity.
Meaning?
The further you are
physically apart,
the better you function together.
Don't be absurd.
You know, Josh could have
been a little less cryptic.
“There's this German.”
Yes, there's actually
82 million of the fuckers.
“There's this password.”
Yes, well, which German
does it belong to?
Did he introduce you
to any Germans?
Missy?
Miss?
OK, you're absolutely sure
that no-one saw you?
I told you. I was doing laps.
I mean, who'd notice?
From the time you left the hotel room
until the time you got back,
you didn't speak to a single soul?
I was doing laps.
OK.
Want something to eat?
Drink? Ho
Why not? Drink drink?
Without something to eat?
Listen, sweetheart,
if you don't eat something soon,
your stomach's gonna start
eating itself, alright?
It's kill or be killed down there.
I know these things.
I once defended a gastroenterologist
on Medicare fraud.
Oh, no.
What?
An old client of mine.
“The coroner dismissed
earlier reports
“that Dr Chambers had died
as a result of natural causes
“and found that the well-respected
oncologist had committed suicide.”
He was a chapter
in my book, Cleave.
Are you OK?
Yeah.
Argh!
Oh, fuck! FUCK! Scarlet.
Dr Robinson to
Intensive Care, please. Dr Robinson?
Scarlet?
How is he?
Oh, he'll be fine.
It was a clean break.
OK.
Oh, baby.
Oh. I can take you home
in a couple of hours.
You're gonna be fine.
The doctor said it's a clean break.
Clean break, you say?
Yeah.
OK.
If that's what you want.
No, Barney. Your arm.
It's a clean break.
You know, I wanted us to work.
For us.
For the kids.
Oh, darling.
Hey, don't worry about me.
Hm. I've met someone.
Did you just say you've met someone?
Whoa!
Barney?
Oh, private numbers shit me.
Hello.
Cleaver Greene?
Yes. Who's this?
We need to talk.
Look, if this is in relation to
a so-called personal banking matter,
this is bordering on harassment, mate.
I need to talk to you
about Joshua Floyd.
But not over the phone.
Is this for real?
I mean, ‘cause if itis...
Having trouble finding the German,
Mr Greene?
You're close, Mr Greene.
Closer than you think.
The girl is innocent.
She's been set up.
Yeah, I know that much.
We want to help you.
But we have to be careful.
You'll be dealing with
many, many interested parties.
Including your own government.
ASIO?
They'll block you at every turn.
Josh said, um,
that he had enough information
to bring down three governments
and Wall Street.
As they say in the classics,
just follow the money.
How do I get in touch with you?
You don't.
I'll be in touch with you.
Of course. Silly me.
Be careful.
Don't trust your email
or your phones from now on.
They're compromised.
Do you understand?
What's the matter?
Yeah, no, it's fine.
I just thought you might not be here.
Yeah, yep.
With him now. I gotta go.
And I'll get back to you. Yep, OK.
New numbers are in.
Oh, yeah? Don't tell me we've made it
to double digits at last?
Ha! The party hasn't, but you have.
What?
Well into double digits, mate.
Bloody streets ahead of our beloved
leader, Captain Capitulate.
Shit.
Yeah, Bruce was wondering
if you wanted to have a chat.
What about?
About duck hunting, you dick.
About becoming the next
leader of the opposition.
It's too soon.
He's not talking tomorrow,
he's talking deep, strategic,
long-term political planning.
Yeah, so probably
nothing before next week.
This is unbelievable.
I mean, who isn't involved?
How does someone subpoena
the CIA?
Buggered if I know.
Where do you reckon
it's gonna land?
What do you mean?
Well, this is all
very, very sexy stuff,
but there's nothing I've seen yet
that will actually help Missy.
Oh, it will. Just keep looking.
Follow the money.
Hey, have you hurt your arm?
Morning.
Nicole.
Now, listen, could you scare us up
a couple of coffees
and a whiteboard, please?
A white...a whiteboard? You want
a whiteboard? What's going on?
Oh, nothing.
Just trying to save the world.
Hi, mate.
Yes.
I... Yes. Yes!
OK.
Fuck! Nicole?
OK, I have a conference.
Could you please print this out for me?
Before coffees
and saving the world?
You don't get to save the world.
No, of course not.
How could I without a whiteboard?
What happened to your arm?
Just a fall. You OK?
Yeah. Yep, yep. You?
I'm fine.
Good.
So we're good then?
Yep.
Good.
Did you wanna talk about...?
Nope.
Col.
What's up?
Kirsty's not happy, Cleave.
Oh, fuck. Is that what
you called me here for?
You haven't seen her in almost a week.
You barely return half her calls.
Mate, I am up to my bottom lip
in it right now.
You know that. So does she.
Yeah, be that as it may,
she's not happy, mate.
Well...
Welcome to the wonderful world
of interpersonal relationships, Col.
I mean seriously fucking
not happy, Cleave.
I'm worried about her.
I think she might be depressed.
She needs you, Cleave.
Mate, she doesn't need me.
You know that.
Yeah. Yeah, I do,
and it makes me want to puke.
Col?
Oh. Fuck.
Me, please.
Max, you drink too much.
You take that very slowly, alright?
Two. Two. Two.
One is enough.
Two, two, two, two.
One.
Three, three, three.
One, one, one, one.
You alright?
When we were at the hospital, you...
Yeah?
You told me
that you'd met someone.
I what?
You said that you'd met someone.
And you were out of it but...
..somehow it rang true so...
..I was wondering...
..have you met someone?
It was a one-off.
It won't come to anything.
You've slept with her?
Yeah.
Mm.
Oh, look, Steve, I'd be interested
in knowing the Opposition's view
on extending licensed
brothel facilities in Sydney,
particularly David Potter's view,
given the fact he was engaged
fo a prostitute.
I'd welcome his expertise.
What the fuck was that about?
Oh, David...
He wants to throw that sort of shit?
Because if he wants
to make it personal,
I will rain a shit storm
down on you guys.
Are you OK?
I don't have much on this afternoon.
How about you?
Scarlet, what's wrong?
I don't wanna talk about it.
Is it Cal?
‘Cause, you know,
I've been thinking...
Oh, have you really?
This may sound a little crazy
but, um...
Why don't you come and work for me?
You're not in government, Dave,
and you won't be for a thousand years.
And I'm where the power is.
You're just drifting
on the sidelines.
Political flotsam and jetsam.
We'll be back.
Hm. Booked the exorcist, have you?
This isn't a very good idea, is it?
No. It isn't.
Your Honour, the US State
and Justice Department,
the CIA, MI6, ASIO,
even the German Secret Service.
This is the biggest fishing expedition
that I have ever seen.
Your Honour,
this is purely a domestic matter
in every sense of the word.
And, Your Honour,
we renew our strong objection
to the defendant's motion
to subpoena all or any
of these parties.
Mr Greene?
Ah, Your Honour,
a raft of conservative
politicians and commentators
have gone on the record
stating that Joshua Floyd
should be put to death
for releasing classified information.
This is not just some wild conspiracy
theory I'm proffering here.
There are very serious and legitimate
questions being raised
about the murder of which
my client stands accused.
Surely she has the right to have
any credible alternative theory
properly ventilated before a jury.
Mr Greene,
I know you've already danced
around this maypole a few times,
so you'd be more than aware
that if I were to grant leave,
this court has no coercive powers
over any US government agency.
They may simply just refuse.
In which case, Your Honour,
we would then be able to take
the matter up on appeal
at the International Court of Justice
in the calamitous event
that my client were to be found guilty
in this jurisdiction.
Very well. I'll reserve my decision.
What gives? Must be 15 years
since you dropped in on me at work.
Well, it's probably 15 years since
you had a case that I cared about.
You must be working crazy hours.
I don't mind.
If you ever need a break or, you know,
some sustenance or anything,
you can always come to us, you know.
I mean, I'd love to help if I could.
Or if it's easier,
I could meet you somewhere.
I mean...
That might be easier.
OK.
Let me know.
I will.
Oh, jeez. Oh. I've gotta go.
Um...
See you, Cleave.
See you, Doc.
Are you home, darling?
In here.
How was your day?
An unrelenting stream
of pointlessness.
How was yours?
Yeah, it was fine. I just, um,
met Audrey in town for lunch.
Town, huh?
Yeah, town. It's a place
where people congregate.
It's got a couple of malls,
so you'd probably like it.
You didn't happen to
bump into Dad by any chance?
Uh, funny you should mention that,
because I was actually
passing by the Supreme Court...
Oh, you didn't.
It was on my way to the car.
Mum, you're unbelievable.
Could you get that, please?
Finnegan.
Roger. Roger, I'm sorry, please.
I didn't mean anything by it.
Finnegan, just...
Please. Mum!
I'm sorry, Roger. Mum.
Roger, Roger. He's just a boy.
Please, he did not understand
what he was doing with Sally.
He wanted to do the right thing.
He got carried...
Wendy. It's OK. Yeah?
It's OK.
Oh, I'm just here
to look after the boys.
Sally is gonna stay
in Byron for a while.
Oh.
I promise,
I didn't mean to scare him.
Oh, that's fine. The little bugger
could use the occasional fright.
Nothing I say seems to make
any difference.
How is Sally?
Oh, she's finding herself.
Oh.
Notice how people never go looking
for themselves in cold climates?
You know, I...
I owe you an apology.
Really?
Sally told me that you were the one
who was having the affair,
and I believed her.
You don't know me that well,
so why wouldn't you believe her?
Oh, I'm supposed to be a shrink.
I can't believe I sat there
for hours on end
listening to her carry on,
and it was all bullshit.
Well, she has a few issues, our Sal.
Did you ever suspect?
She was having an affair?
Mm.
Wasn't the first time.
Really?
But I had no idea
that it was Finnegan.
Oh.
For a while there,
I thought it was Cleaver.
Cleaver, you know,
he was always a bit flirty with her.
That's just his default setting.
http://hiqve.com/
Barnyard.
Yeah, I just finished reading
the prosecution's report.
And?
It's not good.
What is it?
Not over the phone, mate.
OK. Look, I'm starving.
I'll see you at the Pic.
Yeah, OK.
This just came for you.
And I've got that dinner at eight.
Ah, yes. Bevan's mum's birthday.
Yes.
And you called him Bevan. Hm.
Yeah. Give him my very best, alright?
Alright. I will.
We should get together sometime.
You wanna get together with Bevan?
Yeah. Well, you know,
big day's coming.
Getting excited about the frocks.
Seriously, though,
I gotta take my hat off to you.
To the both of you, really.
Why?
Well, I know I've given you
some stick along the way
about being a one-guy gal
since you were 15
but, here you are,
seconds from wedlock,
and you are looking sexier
and more womanly than ever.
Really?
Yeah.
I can see the tiger in your tank
all of a sudden.
The tiger in my tank? Since when?
I don't know.
Just like the last week or something.
It's fantastic.
It's a lesson for
all the romantics out there.
You can tell all the old cynics like me
to bugger off,
because you have maintained
your faith
not only in your relationship
but also in yourself.
And you're clearly
more in love than ever.
What?
What is it?
What did I...?
What did I say?
Fuck.
Taxi. Taxi.
Hey.
Oh, don't get up.
How are you doing?
Oh. You know...
Cleaver says I have to eat.
You should.
Melissa.
Do you mind if I join you?
No, no. Not at all.
Um, can I get you anything?
Some food?
So, any developments?
Nothing all that earth-shattering.
What's in the report?
Which report?
The one next to you marked ‘Floyd'.
Barney.
You're late.
Yeah, well, this is not exactly
the most convenient meeting place
in the world, is it, mate?
I mean, I realise you're angling
for a certain aesthetic here...
Mr Greene.
Christ knows
how I'm gonna get a cab.
My associates are keen
to know if you're making progress.
Well... I'm following
the money, alright?
But it's not exactly
leading me anywhere.
You do realise this is
probably the only opportunity
we'll have
to get them in a courtroom?
Are you really up to this,
Mr Greene?
Yeah, course I'm up to it.
Well, then.
There seems to be evidence of
government fraud on a massive scale.
Slush funds, illegal arms deals.
Isn't that enough
to be getting on with?
Look, Mr...Smoking Guy,
my client is up
on murder charges, alright,
and so far we haven't
actually found anything
that can meaningfully
help us with our defence.
Do I have to paint you a picture?
Well, maybe not an oil painting
but, yeah, a line drawing?
The killer works for ASIO.
Is that sufficient detail for you?
Right. Do you have a name?
I can't give you a name.
Can't or won't?
This goes to the very top
of the organisation, Mr Greene.
You get the director of ASIO
in the box
and you ask him about
the information I've supplied you.
You embarrass him
and his friends sufficiently
and I guarantee he'll sacrifice
the agent involved
to put a halt to proceedings.
Handled properly,
you can both save the girl
and bring the whole rotting edifice
crashing down.
Some recent dispatches
from the front.
They should help you fill in
some of the details.
Yeah.
Cleave.
Oh.
Mate, your timing
could not be worse.
Hi, Kirsty.
How are you, Cleaver?
Yeah, good. Just, uh, flat out
like a lizard drinking.
Yeah.
We're both busy people, aren't we?
Oh. I know. It's just how do you
find the hours in the day?
Listen, the reason I came here
was because I wanted to work out
where we...where we stand, you know?
‘Cause I've been getting these...
these mixed messages from you.
Have my messages been mixed?
How's this for size? I come here
and I sit waiting for you.
And I look across the road
and I see your...your client
coming out of that cafe
and going straight into the apartment.
Is she living with you now, is she?
Yes, she is, but it's not
what you're thinking.
Isn't it?
No, it's not.
She's an old friend.
I've read her book.
Ancient history, Kirsty.
Look, the way I see it, Cleaver,
we've got two choices, right?
I mean, our relationship
can either be based on pleasure
or it can be based on business.
And I'm sure you're aware
of the differences.
OK. Now, here's the thing...
If you opt for the pleasure option,
she has to be out of
your apartment by tonight.
OK, here's the thing...
I will not be made a fool of!
OK.
My client is up on murder charges
right now.
Now, nothing is happening between us,
but she does need me at the moment
and I'm not gonna kick her out,
alright?
I won't.
OK.
Great.
Great. We're back in business, then.
Goodnight, Cleaver.
Um, Col will have a word to you
about your new repayment plan.
I'm sure you understand
there will be penalties.
Yep. Yes.
Yes.
See you, Kirsty.
Mate, I have got a big trial
about to kick off.
You really don't know a good thing
when you see it, do you, mate?
You've been offered
a dream come true.
How is that exactly?
A life with Kirsty.
You just can't see it, can ya?
Not with any great sense of clarity,
mate.
Nah, you just think
she's some low rent moll.
Well, she would fuckin' buy and sell you
any day of the week.
Mate. Are you back on the gear?
I've seen a lot, Cleave.
I have seen a lot in my time, mate.
I've seen some of the shit
that Mick put her through
and she is still the most beautiful,
most loving human being
I've ever met.
Mate, I could be
right out of line here,
but have you got a bit
of a soft spot for Kirsty?
She lives for love, mate.
She lives for bloody love.
And the likes of you, you just...
Mate.
Why don't you tell her how you feel?
Nah, nah, I'm no good
when it comes to the romance, mate.
Oh, come on.
I dream about taking her hand.
I open my mouth
but I can't say anything.
Well, why not?
What is someone like me
gonna say to a goddess, mate?
“Kirsty, from the day I met you,
“you have filled my heart
with joy and light and song.
“Lo these many years
I have tried to hide my passion
“but now I can hide it no longer.
“My heart is fit to bust a nut.”
No. “To burst.”
Lose the ‘nut'. Lose the ‘nut'.
Never said ‘nut'.
“My heart is fit to burst.”
‘Burst'. Gotcha.
“l am a man who knows
and understands your heart,
“and who wants to devote
his life to your song,
“unlike poor Cleaver Greene,
who is incapable of feeling love,
‘owing to personal tragedies
he suffered during his childhood.
“I will give you that love,
“the love that Cleaver Greene
so desperately wanted to give you.
‘I want to make you happy
beyond your wildest dreams.
“I want to make you mine.”
You reckon that will
do the trick, mate?
Putty in your hands, mate.
Hey.
This is the background report on Josh
prepared by the prosecution.
Ah, yes. You saw Barney?
There's a woman who says
that she slept with Josh
on three separate occasions in Sydney
since we've returned.
She could be lying.
Yeah, she could be.
But in Josh's wallet,
the cops found a couple of receipts
from the hotel that she named.
Doesn't mean he didn't love you.
He has a child.
OK. I didn't know that.
No, neither did I.
A 2-year-old from a former temp
at good plumbing in London.
You know what this means, Cleave?
It means they finally have
a motive, Cleave.
I mean, before, I was just
a lying whore, right?
And now I'm a lying, jilted whore.
Don't do this. There's no point.
Why not? I mean, what have you got?
What have you even got
that can help me?
It was an ASIO agent.
Oh, well, how do you know
that it was an ASIO agent?
Because I just saw the Smoking Guy.
The Smoking Guy? Oh, of course!
Well, I mean, that makes me feel
a whole lot better, Agent Mulder!
Cleaver, I'm looking at
a life sentence
and you're off playing boys' games!
The first thing you said to me
when I saw you in the lockup was,
“They've killed him. They said
they were gonna kill him and they have.”
You were right.
Well, what if I wasn't?
You think you could eat two?
Um, with some maple syrup.
Pancakes!
Yes, please.
Where's Maxy?
Oh, he's still...
Get your own. Mum.
I'll get him.
There's enough to go around.
You just finish the eggs.
Give me those ones there.
Just wait.
Where's your tie?
In my bag.
Hard or soft, mate?
Breakfast. Max?
Argh!
MAX! Oh!
You should get an X-ray.
No, it's just a sprain.
I'm not sure that
we're gonna make it, baby.
And it's not just because of me
this time, is it?
This woman that you've slept with.
I don't wanna know any details.
But...is it an option
that you're contemplating?
‘Cause you know you're not the kind of
guy who has a one-night stand.
So for you to have done
something like this,
it must be sort of serious.
I know.
And that sort of scares me.
Ah. Ah.
Missy's losing it, mate.
She thinks I'm putting all her eggs
in the ASIO basket.
It is the only basket in town
at the moment, isn't it?
I can't think of any others.
Alright, let's go back
to first principles.
Well, he didn't have any money.
So it's not that.
He was a root rat.
Maybe there's a jealous lover?
I'm sure there is, mate,
but he's been living in New York
for the last 10 years,
so where do we start?
What about the ex-wife?
Yeah.
Can you get your angels onto it, eh?
Has Missy looked at all
the CCTV footage from the hotel?
Yeah. Once more with feeling,
you reckon?
Yes, please.
Get her out of the bloody flat!
I've seen this movie before and
I wanted to walk out the first time.
Take a break if you have to.
It's getting us nowhere.
There's gotta be witnesses, DNA.
There's gotta be something
instead of you just hanging around
in car parks.
Alright. OK.
You want the DNA report? There it is.
It's a fuckin' hotel room, Miss.
How many different sets of DNA
do you think they found in there,
including yours on the knife?
You tell me what we've missed.
What if you can't get ASIO
into the box?
We'll get 'em.
They'll fight the subpoenas.
Then we'll fight back.
What if we lose that fight?
Missy. Missy.
Oi.
We need to talk.
Can you just let go of me, please?
For a woman about to marry
the man of her dreams,
she's got a hell of a case
of the marriage jitters.
What the fuck would you know?
Oh, has everybody gone barking mad?
Hello.
I'm just ringing
to make sure you're OK.
Hm. Couldn't be better.
I'm sorry about yesterday.
It wasn't your fault.
Anyway, we both came to our senses.
Listen, I've gotta go.
I'll call you later.
What happened to you?
Hit and run.
Ought to be a law.
But what can you do?
Listen, I need
a highly rated favour.
Oh, yeah?
If anyone asks, we had
a working lunch yesterday.
What?
I blew off a meeting
with the Premier,
principally because my head
would have exploded
with boredom had I attended it.
Told him we were working on
the Proceeds of Crime legislation.
Now, he's more than
a little paranoid at the moment,
so if you could diarise us
between 12:00 and 2:30.
Oh, really?
You already got something
in your diary for lunch yesterday?
No.
Nope. So what's the problem?
Thanks, Engels. I owe you one.
Melissa, how do you
feel about the charges?
Did you do it?
Missy, tell us about
your book sales.
Thanks, guys.
We're going straight in.
My learned friend Mr Greene
will doubtlessly tell a tale
of an elaborate conspiracy
to assassinate Joshua Floyd,
that he was a threat
and a menace to governments,
security agencies,
financial institutions, you name it.
But, ladies and gentlemen,
let us look at the actual legacy
of Joshua Floyd.
The guns are still being fired
in the Middle East
but no-one on Wall Street has been.
No governments have been toppled,
no leaders have been forced
from office.
At the worst,
he has caused embarrassment
to a handful of minor officials.
Tragically for Mr Greene,
this is simply
a garden-variety murder,
motivated by jealousy,
a jealousy so extreme
that it caused the accused
to plunge a knife
into her fiancé's back,
not once, not twice,
but three times.
It's easy to mock
conspiracy theories, isn't it?
In 1963, the theory
that there was a conspiracy
to assassinate President Kennedy
of the United States
was dismissed as absurd.
In 1973,
the theory that Nixon's henchmen
broke into the Democrat headquarters
in the Watergate building
was dismissed as absurd.
Why on earth would they bother?
Why would they risk everything?
Ladies and gentlemen,
history has perpetually taught us
that power corrupts.
And the threat of the exposure
of that corruption generates fear.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Joshua Floyd was murdered
not necessarily because of
anything he'd already said or done,
but because of the fear
of what he might do.
Now, my client loved Joshua Floyd.
My client...is a patsy.
Um, I chatted to Joshua briefly
and he gave me his card.
Then I called him the next day and
he told me to meet him at a hotel.
Where you proceeded
to have sexual intercourse?
Yes.
And how many times
did you meet him for this purpose?
Um, three times in all.
Thank you.
Mr Greene?
Uh, no questions,
thank you, Your Honour.
So you didn't think
I had a good opening, Miss?
You've made me
Australia's Lee Harvey Oswald.
I couldn't be happier.
Between that and
your rigorous cross-examination
of Miss ‘No Questions, Your Honour',
I'm in legal heaven.
What do you think pushing that girl
would have added?
She has a solid alibi.
Well, it could have been
any one of his tarts.
What about Therese?
She's in there every day.
You know, she never misses a minute
with nothing but fucking hate
in her eyes.
Maybe she just couldn't stand
the idea of Josh marrying again.
She was in Melbourne.
Hey, guess what?
ASIO aren't gonna fight
the subpoenas.
They just put out a press release
stating they're going
to fully cooperate.
Yes. I knew it!
I knew they'd cave.
They couldn't possibly say no publicly.
Dead, dead, dead mouse.
Nicole, dead mouse!
Dead mouse!
Hey, Nicole.
Sorry.
Ah, yes. Yep. Give me those.
It was here 10 seconds ago,
I saved it,
and now it's fucking gone
off the screen.
That's it, three hours work.
I think you'll find that's it,
isn't it?
Thank you.
Wakey, wakey! Hands off snakey!
It's showtime, folks.
Mate, the prosecution's gonna howl
when they get this so late.
I know, I know.
Not to mention the judge.
I know. Nicole. NICOLE!
Yes?
We've got to get these over to judgey
and Greg at warp speed.
By warp speed, you mean
you want me to carry them?
I don't need your special brand
of insight today, OK?
Nicole.
OK.
But someone's gotta check
the agreed time codes
on the DVD of the hotel footage.
I can do that.
Yeah, sure you can.
Oh, this is... It's broken.
It's fucked.
Give it to me.
That's her.
Who?
There's this woman.
She comes to court every day.
That's her. I'm sure that's her.
Who is she?
I'll go get an ID.
You better be bloody quick, mate.
You're gonna have to stall.
Yeah, well,
I can only stall so long.
Are you sure?
Mr Greene?
Your Honour?
Are you not ready to commence?
Indeed, Your Honour.
Uh...
Mr Lonsdale, you are the director
of the...Australian Security
and Intelligence...Organisation...
..otherwise known as ASIO.
Is that, uh, correct?
I am.
Now, Mr Lonsdale, I noticed
that you chose to affirm your oath
rather than swear to God.
Is that, uh, a fair comment?
I did.
So you don't believe in a god at all?
I'm an atheist, Mr Greene.
I see.
Are your parents religious folk,
Mr Lonsdale?
Mr Greene, what on earth
are you playing at?
This case, uh, uh,
as Your Honour very kindly pointed out,
does have certain elements
of the conspiracy theory to it, uh...
Very much like ‘The Da Vinci Code'.
Mr Greene.
You're a wanker, Cleaver.
Uh, may I have one moment,
Your Honour, to take instructions?
Mr Greene, my patience
is wearing wafer thin.
Thank you, Your Honour.
It's her, mate.
Please tell me she's with ASIO.
Her husband was the doctor
in Missy's book that topped himself.
So ASIO's...?
Got nothing to do with it.
No, but what was
the Smoking Man...?
Oh, shit.
Yeah.
Mr Greene.
Oh, shit.
Yes, I know.
Oh...
No further questions, thank you.
No further questions?
As if you've asked one.
So I take it you're no longer
pursuing this line of attack?
I'm afraid not.
Do you have any idea
the amount of time
you've wasted
on this goose chase, Cleaver?
This is bordering on contempt.
I was set up, Ben.
Oh, set up? By whom?
By ASIO.
All those smoking guns in all
those files were leaked to me
by someone who claimed
to be a friend of Josh's,
but, on reflection,
I'm sure it was all bullshit.
I'm sure there's not
a single truth amongst them.
Why would ASIO leak you bullshit,
Cleaver?
So that I'd get up and spout at Greg
and be made to look like a tit
by the director of ASIO,
which would then be vindicated
in open court.
Who's going to trust
good plumbing after that?
And how do you know this?
Because we know who really did it.
Your Honour, I'd like to call
Mrs Faye Chambers, please?
Do you know why you've been called
to give evidence, Mrs Chambers?
Yes.
Mrs Chambers, your husband
was the noted oncologist
Graham Chambers, is that right?
He was.
He devoted himself
to saving people's lives.
He passed away recently, did he not?
He did.
I'm so sorry.
Mrs Chambers,
could you tell the court
how your husband died, please?
He took an overdose.
I see.
Do you know why he took an overdose?
He killed himself
because of that filthy book.
That vile, evil book.
The book you're referring to,
Mrs Chambers,
is ‘A Thousand Lies I Have Told'
by the accused, is that right?
I am.
He showed me the book
and told me what had happened
in that brothel.
I didn't care. I loved him.
I could cope because
99% of him was pure good.
He wasn't mentioned
by name in the book.
No, but he was terrified
people would find out somehow.
She had betrayed his confidence.
She destroyed him.
And I wanted that whore
to find out what it felt like
to suffer the sort of loss I had.
Yep.
Come in.
Ms Engels.
Premier.
Oh, dear. What happened to you?
Oh, just a little accident at home.
Please, have a seat.
Thanks.
Delighted to meet you, at last.
You too.
So I need to ask you
a very delicate question, if I may.
My understanding
is that on the 17th of this month,
you had a working lunch
with Cal McGregor.
17th? Um...
Uh...
Ah, yes, we were finalising
the amendments
to the Proceeds of Crime legislation,
I believe.
Thank God.
I'm sure this won't be
a secret much longer,
so I should tell you the reason
I'm asking you this question
is because a woman has alleged
Cal sexually assaulted her
at that time.
Now, I, for one,
never doubted his innocence
but the fact that he has
an ironclad alibi
comes as an enormous relief.
Now, some detectives
are in my conference room.
They'll want to ask you
some questions
and get a signed statement.
I assume that won't be a problem?
No. No problem.
Right here. Thank you.
Oh.
I'll be right back with the menus
and some water for the table.
Enjoy your evening. Thank you.
Doc.
Mwah!
How's it hanging?
We got a bottle?
I've just ordered a glass.
Let's get a bottle. Hey-ho!
Um...
Ah. So I was thinking
on the way here...
If you ever met royalty,
would you bow or curtsy?
Because I don't think...
I wouldn't even nod.
Hello. Can I get...? Oh, fuck.
I mean, I'd give them my paw.
I'm not being
deliberately disrespectful.
It's just... Fuck, what did
they ever do to earn it?
Hello. Oh, yes. Gargon?
If we have to bow to the unworthy,
why don't we bow to supermodels?
At least they're cute. Hm?
I'm gonna bow to Gisele Blindchen.
Hello? Who do you have to fuck
to get a drop of something around here?
Hello? Yes, mate. Yes, you.
Yeah. Come on, mate.
Yeah. Come on.
Ping. Bingo!
Yes. Nobody likes a snitch.
Oh.
Come on. Thirsty human in the room.
“O for a beaker of the warm South.”
Can you see me now? Huh?
Can you...? What are you doing?
We're better when
there's distance between us.
Oh, come on, sweetheart.
Just a little joke.
Come on. You've had enough.
Oh, come on, mate. I haven't had any.
I haven't had a single thing.
A man is not a camel.
Hey, Roger. How you going?
Hey. Yeah. Yeah, good, Wen.
Good. You?
Do you feel like a drink?
Oh, shit. Col.
It worked, mate.
It fuckin' worked.
I can't believe it. We're in love, mate.
Me and Kirsty.
Oh, mate.
I couldn't be happier for you.
I can't thank you enough, mate.
We are over the moon.
Oh, well, you know,
I'm heartbroken, of course,
but what are mates for?
Makes this so hard, Cleave.
What's that?
Naturally, Kirsty
is very grateful too, of course,
but, like she says,
business is business,
and I'm not about to upset
my little dumpling now, am I, mate?
Matter of fact,
this is a special request from her.
Ooooh!
http://hiqve.com/