What's up, Dad?
What do you mean?
You're smiling.
Yeah.
Weird, isn't it?
Attorney-General Joe Sandilands
has confirmed that he is
one of 14 state MPs
who has regularly attended
the exclusive Darlinghurst brothel
known as Club Jules.
Footage of Mr Sandilands
leaving the brothel
was released via YouTube last night.
In a statement released
this morning,
the Attorney-General expressed
“deep regret'...
Oh, Joe. You poor bastard.
..and his colleagues.
The Premier is yet
to make a statement.
No luck, I'm afraid.
You're kidding me.
No-one on this floor
has a single Panadol?
Panamax? Disprin? Aspirin? Codeine,
Nurofen in one form or another?
I'll take it anally, if required.
What can I say?
This floor is loaded with
booze, coke, sex toys, debt...
I don't need my résumé
shouted back at me, woman.
I just need something to kill
the bastard behind my eyes.
You right?
I'm right.
Gun?
Check.
Knife?
Stockings?
You're in charge of
the stockings, Tones.
Bullshit I was!
Good evening.
Uh... Oh...
I have the stepmother
of all headaches.
A headache, you say.
Yes.
I'd like something strong for it,
if possible.
I'll be with you in a moment.
Put your fucking
hands in the air now! Do as you're told.
Open the fucking till.
Hurry up here!
Fellas, what are you doing?
Open it!
Boys, you're on ‘Candid Camera'.
Shut up! Hurry up, mate.
I'd just cut my losses
and bolt if I were you.
I won't say a word.
Put your hands in the air.
Is that branch loaded, mate?
Shut up, smart arse.
I know a thing or two about the law —
not much, granted —
but if you just bolt now...
Oh!
Hurry up!
It won't come out!
What are you doing?
I can't get it open.
Leave it. Let's go. Come on!
Stay down.
Hurry up, Tones. Hurry up!
Let's go. Come on!
Aargh!
Oh, fuck! Tones, get up!
Tones, come on!
Tones! Tones! Come on, man!
You're in luck.
This should do the trick.
Fucking hell. Oh, fuck. Fu...
Where's my parade?
I beg your pardon?
He gets called a hero, he gets a safe
seat in Parliament, he gets my girl.
Ow!
What do I get?
Hello?
Barn?
So are you gonna die?
Well, I've been thinking a bit
about it lately.
Barn!
Don't ever pull this stunt again.
I'm not your next of kin.
In fact, I couldn't imagine
a worse fate.
I had a mental blank.
You just don't get it, do you?
We don't exist any longer, Cleaver.
I'm not gonna bail you out
or loan you any more money
or listen to you rationalise
your pathetic self-indulgences.
Alright. If you can't get over
a little grudge...
A little grudge?!
He screwed my wife.
Barn, it's you and me, mate.
Come on, we can get over this.
I'm already over it, ‘mate'.
I'm over it.
I'm over Scarlet and I'm over you.
Ta-ta.
Sorry, this might be
a little... .tight.
Oh! Fuck!
Until I'm informed otherwise,
this is OUR house
and they are OUR children.
OK.
Have you seen this?
“Glebe woman bashed and robbed.”
No, below that.
“Barista assaul...
“Barista assaulted
in Kings Cross chemist.”
Pretty funny.
You haven't made a cup of coffee for
yourself since I've known you.
How come Glebe woman
gets a bigger story than me?
I mean, she's...Glebe woman.
Her only significant achievement's
having an address.
I at least have a profession.
Ah! I'd kill for a skinny latte right now,
thanks.
And how come Glebe woman
gets ‘bashed' and I get ‘assaulted'?
I mean, ‘bashed'
sounds so much worse.
Oh, it's a blessing in disguise.
It's a bloody good disguise.
You're briefed to appear for
Travis Simon Tanner,
who is alleged to have
assaulted and robbed...
Glebe woman.
I'm gonna get the bugger off.
She's gonna find out who's boss.
Show Glebe woman what it's like
to be below the fold.
Yes, you do that.
Oh, by the way,
can I have a muffin to go?
He's 19. He has two priors
as a juvenile for...
Violent assault and robbery.
Excellent.
Just got out of Grafton. This is
his first charge as an adult.
I'm not even gonna try and hide
my disappointment, Simone.
I was hoping our Mr Tanner
might be innocent.
See, I have a score to settle.
Well, before you fall into
a deep despond,
it seems very possible that
the police may have jumped the gun
and picked up an easy target.
How so?
Because, whilst our Mr Tanner
does fit the description
given by Ms...Jah...Jajou?
Jajou, Jajou.
Yep, yep, Glebe woman.
Quite.
..we have a witness who says
she saw him in the city
at precisely the time the attack was
alleged to have taken place
in Glebe on...
Glebe woman.
Really?
Yes.
And this, you see,
is how you came to get this brief.
How?
Apparently, the witness
is a friend of yours.
Who?
It was about 8:00.
I was late to meet David,
so I bolted out onto Phillip Street.
And — wham! — we collided.
I dropped everything.
He was very apologetic
and helped me pick up my stuff.
And we chatted for a minute
and introduced ourselves.
He told you his name?
Yeah.
Travis. Travis Tanner.
Next morning,
I'm listening to the radio.
And after all that bullshit
about the election,
I hear this story about
this woman from Glebe...
Glebe woman.
Yeah.
..who was assaulted about 8:00
and that a Travis Tanner
had been charged.
Right, nothing on the radio about
a barista from Kings Cross?
No.
Anyway, I thought, “There can't be that
many Travis Tanners.”
So I give the Crown defender's
office a call
and I get his solicitor's name
and I tell her what I saw.
And?
And Simone and I got chatting
and I mentioned your name and...
Uh, any distinguishing features?
Yeah, a barbed wire tatt
on his shoulder. His left, I think.
I gotta get back.
OK.
You know this is proof, don't you?
Proof of what?
Proof of our spiritual connection.
We both withessed assaults
on the same night.
In some cultures,
we'd be forced to marry.
Well, I guess we're lucky
we live in a city
where the spiritual
doesn't count for much.
What were you doing
in Phillip Street, Travis?
Um, staying in some shit hole
near Central.
The halfway house?
Yep.
I went down to see the harbour
and the bridge and that.
Right, were you gonna meet
some mates down there?
Nuh. Just...wanted to see the blue.
The colour blue?
Yeah.
But it wasn't sunny that day,
was it?
Night before,
the forecast was sweet.
Fine and sunny all day, but...
they're all just full of shit.
Oh, don't get me started on
weathermen, mate.
How long did you stay
down by the harbour?
Probably...most of the day.
Despite the absence of
the colour blue.
Blue would've been nice, but...
I've just gotta walk around
like a regular bloke.
Hmm.
The sun went down
and I just stared at the lights.
It was good.
And then you, uh, just walked back
to the old halfway house.
Yep.
Past the law school.
Why did you go that way?
I don't know Sydney
that well. I'm from Taree.
But it was outside the law school
you bumped into Miss Partridge.
Well, they tell me it was
a law school.
I wouldn't know
what the fuck it was.
Yeah. It's a law school.
http://hiqve.com/
Mick. Col.
Can we have a private word?
We heard what happened
the other night at the chemist's.
Oh, yeah, you read the papers.
Yep. Couldn't grab us a short black,
could you, mate?
One of the boys just happens to be
the son of good friend of mine.
Ah!
The one who clobbered you.
Ah.
Ah, indeed.
Not me for a change, hey, Cleave?
Yeah, that's right.
So do I get a credit?
The thing is, mate,
the other kid, Tony, he's dead.
Turns out he had some sort of
congenital brain defect.
Shit.
No shit.
Well, I didn't need a neurosurgeon
to tell me that.
They're both fucking idiots.
And, you know, the pair of them
have always been embarrassments
to their families.
Fuckin' pot heads.
But Josh, fair fuckin' dinkum,
even before he started on the weed,
he was just plain dumb.
His father's a very, very good friend
of mine.
Best break-and-enter man
in the business.
So I need to know
what really happened, Cleave.
Oh, well, look,
I was still a bit woozy,
but, um...but I vaguely remember
one of them clobbering
the security camera with
a lump of wood
and hitting the other one...
Tony.
..Tony, in the follow-through.
He didn't mean to do it.
It's manslaughter at worst.
Good.
His father thinks a stretch
for manslaughter will sort him out.
Teach him the trade.
Yeah.
But murder? No.
His mother couldn't handle that.
Barney's missus has been briefed
for the prosecution.
Will that be a problem?
Well, not for me, mate.
Golden rule —
you can't cross-examine a friend.
How are you?
Thanks for coming.
Oh! That's alright.
Can't really trust the phones
at the moment.
How are you going?
Sal's given me two weeks
to find a new place.
Taken the kids to Bowral
until I move out.
She didn't know?
She knew. Course she knew.
It's not what I did. It's the humiliation
that she can't handle.
Spoken to Jules?
Yeah, yeah.
I tried calling her, but...
Well, she's lying understandably low.
There's a lot of
pretty pissed-off people.
What happened?
Someone hacked into the system.
You know, got the client list,
recognised a few names.
If they got the client list,
then they...
No, no, it's alright.
You don't need to worry.
It's not the girls they're interested in.
It's the celebs.
You know, and the chances of anyone
putting two and two together
are a million to one.
I don't like those odds
in this town.
Have you thought of telling David?
We're too far down the track, Joe.
You OK?
Sick of the bullshit.
Hmm.
Tell me, what... When we were, um...
..together at the club,
did you ever enjoy it?
We had a lot of laughs.
Yeah, I know we had a lot of laughs,
but...the whole thing —
did you ever...
Joe, let's not dwell on...
Didn't think so.
That's not what I meant.
That's exactly what you meant.
Ah, Cleaver was always
the one for you, wasn't he?
Oh, don't be stupid.
No, I...
I remember Jules's drinks parties.
Your face would light up
when Cleaver came in.
Hey? Off his tree.
As he invariably was.
And then I'd go and look for you
a little later on
and you'd both be gone.
Did you fall in love with him?
Once or twice.
But to use an expression
Cleaver's fond of,
he's a hopeless case.
Hmm, another expression
that he's fond of —
hopeless cases are the only ones
worth fighting for.
You ever tell him what you felt?
Hmm!
“For all sad words of tongue and pen,
“the saddest are these —
“it might have been.”
You've already made
a joint decision to divorce.
What is it you seek to achieve
by coming to therapy?
It's for the children, primarily.
We've moved on from each other.
So we...we thought it would be a good
idea to see if someone could help us.
- Hmm, help them.
- Yeah, help the children.
That's who I meant by ‘them'.
I was just trying to be clear.
I think it was already pretty clear.
You could've been clearer.
Alright. I'm sorry.
Alright, what were you playing at?
What do you mean?
Well, this Zen facade
is a little wearing.
It's not a facade.
Oh, bullshit.
I feel OK, Scarlet.
It's as much a surprise to me.
I just...I feel OK.
The fog has lifted.
No pain, no anger.
Just a desire and a need to move on.
So...?
So we move on.
It's what you want, right?
Yeah.
OK.
Ah, yes. I told you the patches
wouldn't work, Darver.
The only way the patches
are gonna work, mate,
is if you want to quit smoking.
And you don't want to quit smoking.
You're a committed smoker. So be it.
You're also one of the nation's
top silks,
so you shouldn't be reduced
to hanging around
in fucking toilet cubicles,
puffing away like
some adolescent boy.
So come on, mate. Be a man.
Out and proud.
Jesus Christ. Give it
a fucking rest, will you?
You pricks are all the same.
You can't even have a piss
without talking shit.
Yes. Uh, sorry,
I mistook you for somebody else.
I'm meeting some prick
called Greene. Where's he at?
Uh, yes.
The prick Greene is, uh, down
the corridor to the left, left again,
then straight ahead.
Look for a door marked ‘Tolga Urdan'.
Now, where was I?
Ms Tanner, did you visit Travis
when he was in Grafton?
Once or twice.
Look, he know what he done.
If you can't do the time,
then don't do the fucking crime.
Yeah, it's just that this is your son's first
charge as an adult.
If it goes badly, it's gonna
have a really big impact
on the rest of his life.
We're here, aren't we?
Just tell us what you want us to say.
It doesn't work that way,
Mrs Tanner.
Oh, doesn't it?
You must be new at this, love.
♪ When I, good friends, was call'd to the bar
♪ I'd an appetite fresh and hearty...
♪ But I was,
as many young barristers are
♪ An impecunious party
♪ I'd a swallow-tail coat
of a beautiful blue
♪ And a brief which I bought
from a booby
♪ A couple of shirts
and a collar or two
♪ And a ring that looked like a ruby
♪ He'd a couple of shirts and a collar or two
♪ And a ring that look'd like
aruby... ♪
A statement issued by
the family this afternoon, Sandra,
stated that Mr Sandilands
was under considerable pressure
following revelations about
his regular attendance
at a now infamous Sydney brothel.
His suicide was met with shock
in Macquarie Street,
where the Premier...
♪ Of all the money that e'er I had
♪ I spent it in good company
♪ And all the harm that ever I'd done
♪ Alas it was to none but me
♪ And all I've done for want of wit
♪ To memory now I can't recall
♪ So fill to me the parting glass
♪ Goodnight
and joy be with you all. ♪
To Joe.
Joe.
Hey.
Hi.
I don't think I've got another tear
left in me, Barn.
I know how you feel, Sal.
You don't see how
it could ever not hurt.
You resign yourself to
living with the pain.
But then one day you wake up
and it's gone. Hmm?
And you begin again.
I'm having dinner for Fuzz's birthday
at my place if you're free.
Yeah, great.
She's coming.
Who? Your mother?
Vampira.
Ah.
I've been thinking about my epitaph.
And?
I think I'm going to go with
American Typewriter.
I'm sorry?
The font.
I've got no idea what it's gonna say,
but it'll look nice.
I was watching you
chatting to Scarlet.
I had a sort of Proustian rush.
It was like it was 15 years ago
and we were all
at some party together.
I'd be acting the fool
and you two and Barney
would be rolling your eyes.
Fuck, I miss it.
Lost you all.
Two of the most important things
a man can have —
a loving wife and dear friends —
I've somehow managed
to lose all of you.
I fucking love you all.
Most of all, you.
Hmm.
What are you doing?
Just making a bad situation worse.
Get out of the car.
Wendy...
Get out of the car, please.
Did you see the list of so-called
celebrities from the club
they put in the paper?
It's a bloody outrage. 30 names.
Did I get a mention?
I'm only a founding member.
I'm surprised Glebe woman
didn't get a guernsey.
I don't know what's going on.
I feel like a victim of identity theft.
Who'd wanna be me?
Eh? Some money, eh?
Here you go.
That's for you.
I'll have a Scotch, mate.
Joe was just sick of the bullshit,
I think.
I'll drink to that.
I saw him the morning he jumped,
Cleave.
Oh.
Don't flatter yourself, babe.
There was nothing you could've done.
Wasn't there?
No, there wasn't.
He sounded so lost.
He was sick of the bullshit —
that's what it was.
Well, I'm tired of it too.
Ugh! Fuck, Cleave!
I'm not even 30 and I'm tired of it.
Every day with David, at some point,
I have to pretend
to be someone I'm not.
I've lied to him about you,
about Joe, about the club.
I mean, it's exhausting.
Well, then, tell him the truth. Fuck!
See how he takes it.
If you can't be real with him,
what's the fucking point?
You're real with me.
Yeah. Yeah, right.
What? I'm serious.
You're real with me.
Who do you feel more real with,
him or me?
It's not that simple.
Isn't it?
You know the rules, baby.
Nah, it's my first time, actually.
Really?
Mmm. So how much for a kiss?
You got cash?
Yeah. How much?
200.
You always carry
that much cash with you?
I've been at a funeral.
Yeah...
♪ Your eyes
are full of hesitation
♪ Which makes me wonder
♪ If you know what you're looking for
♪ Baby
♪ I wanna keep my reputation... ♪
Wow.
Are you OK?
Fantastic.
Could not be better!
♪ Oh, yes, sir
I can boogie
♪ But I need a certain song
♪ I can boogie
♪ Boogie, boogie
♪ All night long
♪ Yes, sir
I can boogie
♪ If you stay, you can't go wrong
Jl..J
Excuse me, sir.
I need you out of the fountain.
Gentlemen.
Sir, out of the fountain, please.
Barney, you bloody idiot!
Cleave?
Yeah. Vince. How are you, mate?
Good to see you.
- Listen, Barn, get out. Get out, mate.
- I don't know him.
You know Mr Meagher, don't you?
We do, Cleave.
Yeah.
We need him out of the fountain.
- I don't know him.
- Get out of there!
He's alright. We've just been
to Joe Sandilands's wake.
So he's a bit tired and emotional.
Yeah, he'll be alright.
He'll come with me.
Get out of there, Barney!
You need to sober up, Mr Meagher.
Listen to your friend.
He's not my mate.
Come on, you bloody idiot...
He's alright.
I'll look aft... I'll get him out.
He's right.
Come on, Barney. You bloody idiot.
Get out of there.
Oh, you... Barney!
Come here, you bloody fool.
Get out, you bloody idiot.
You are gonna owe me big-time.
What time do you call this?
Where have you been?
Mourning a friend.
You only met Joe
a few months ago, Mel.
How drunk do you get
when someone you actually know dies?
I'm sick of this crap.
This self-indulgent,
Paris Hilton crap.
Paris Hilton?!
You're comparing me
with Paris Hilton?
You disappear, Mel, all the time.
You fucking disappear.
Dinners, lunches.
I take a nap,
you're gone three hours.
At first, I thought
it was this charming idiosyncrasy,
a sort of Audrey Hepburn
in ‘Breakfast at Tiffany's.
But it's no longer charming,
nor is it idiosyncratic.
It is childish, self-indulgent,
thoughtless bullshit.
Not only are we getting married,
but I'm running for Parliament.
So I'm sorry, but I really
need to know where you were.
You said that your political career
wouldn't interfere with my choices,
that I could do my own thing.
Where were you last night?!
And don't try and get out of it
by giving me another fucking story
about your dead parents.
Come on, mate. Come on. Drink up.
Oh!
That's it. Bit more.
Oh, no.
I tried being you tonight.
And?
Christ, it must be awful.
Yeah, tell me about it.
I ended up in one of those bars,
the sort of places you go to.
And I paid this woman 200 bucks
to kiss me.
I've been feeling fine.
Here I was in this dark room,
strange woman, kissing her.
And it all came back to me.
Like a flood.
What did?
The pain, the anger, the fear.
I burst into tears
and then I threw up on her.
Oh, Jesus, Barnyard.
200 bucks.
Why on earth, Minister,
would you deny the fact
that you can speak French?
Were you scared that
if this sensational news got out,
it might make you look un-Australian?
Well, it doesn't make you look
un-Australian, mate.
But I'll tell you what,
lying about it makes you look
like an imbecile.
It's this sort of dumbing down,
constantly patronis...
Out we get. Home, James.
Home, James. Good boy.
Hey, just wait there for a sec.
Make yourself nice.
What have you done to him?
Me? Nothing. Absolutely nothing.
The last time I saw him like this
was when you took him out
for his buck's night.
You're welcome, Red.
How could you let him get like this?!
It's nothing to do with me.
He did it all by himself.
It's never your fault, is it?
I've been worried sick.
It's a little late to play the concerned
wife, don't you think, Red?
How dare you? How dare you?
We buried a good friend yesterday
and I was worried about
how Barney would handle it.
Or is there something wrong
with that?
Just go, will you?
And leave my family alone.
For what it's worth, Red,
it looks like he handled it quite well.
Fuck off!
I think we should ask him
to redraft this.
Parts of it aren't even coherent,
let alone accurate.
Mm-hm. Yeah, that's fine.
Look, I've changed my mind —
I'm going to do Cleaver Greene's cross.
But you said he was an old friend.
You can't cross-examine a friend.
I know what I'm doing.
But you could get into
a lot of trouble.
Mr Greene,
you visited the pharmacy
for what purpose?
I had...
I had a headache.
According to your statement,
the defendant
and his now-deceased accomplice,
they entered the pharmacy
approximately two minutes after you.
The two of them
then attempted to rob the pharmacy.
Yes, that's right.
The accused beat you over the head
with a log, did he not?
He did.
Severely enough to see you off
to Emergency at St Vincent's.
Yes.
But you claim to have
remained conscious.
Enough to see the accused
beat his friend with the log.
Yes, well, he didn't
beat him with the log.
He was trying to take out
the CCTV camera
and he hit...it was an accident.
Oh, an accident? Ah.
How can you be sure?
It... I'm sure.
Had you been drinking?
No.
Had you been taking any illicit
substances? Cocaine, for example.
Ms Engels?
Credit, Your Honour.
Short leash.
Thank you, Your Honour.
Do you need me
to repeat the question?
No.
And the answer is no.
Mr Greene, have you ever been
to rehab for cocaine addiction?
Yes.
And when was that?
Two years ago.
Have you taken cocaine
since you were discharged from rehab?
Oh, are you gonna object
at some point, Rumpole?
Uh, objection, Your Honour.
Sustained.
Mr Greene, you're a known associate of
Mr Michael Corella, are you not?
Yes, I defended him.
And Mr Corella is...is a friend
of the accused's father, isn't he?
Yes.
Mr Greene, do you currently
owe Mr Corella any money?
Gambling debts, perhaps.
Your Honour, I have had
sexual relations with that woman.
She is my best friend's wife
and she should not be
cross-examining me.
Your Honour, this is intolerable.
I completely agree with
my co-copulator, Your Honour.
And plus, I've got another trial
kicking off...
Enough!
..SiX minutes.
Ms Engels, my chambers. Now.
Delighted you could make it...
Your Honour.
..Mr Greene.
Only you and Beyoncé
have the pulling power.
Shall we, then?
Let's.
So after the assault,
this so-called Glebe woman
called the police
and you attended the scene.
Mrs Jejora's from Annandale, actually.
I beg your pardon?
The attack was in Glebe.
She's from Annandale.
Are you sure?
I mean, the press was most insistent
that she was a Glebe woman.
Well, as I say, the attack
was in Glebe, so I guess...
Mr Greene, is this at all relevant?
I'll move on, Your Honour.
So, uh, the pensioner
formerly known as Glebe woman
was able to give you a description
of her assailant, was she?
Mr Greene, the victim's name
is Mrs Jejora.
Please answer the question, Constable.
Yes.
Constable, how did the assailant attack
Mrs, uh, Jejora?
If that's her name.
I'm sorry, Mr Greene?
Nothing, Your Honour.
Constable? Please.
She said he attacked her
from behind.
Oh, so 71-year-old Mrs Jejora
was able to give you a description
of the man who attacked her
from BEHIND?
Amongst other things,
she was able to describe a tattoo
on her assailant's left arm.
Yes, the barbed wire.
Yes.
Yes. A barbed wire tattoo.
Have you ever seen
one of those before
in your entire career, Constable?
Yes.
How many times would you estimate
you might've seen
a barbed wire tattoo in your career?
I don't know.
More than once?
I suppose.
Yes, twice? Uh, three times?
300...times?
A lot. I don't know.
Yes.
They're as common as muck,
aren't they, Constable?
Constable, how long was the interval
between Mrs Ja...jora's reporting
of the incident and the arrest?
I'd have to check the charge sheet,
but I'd say...
..an hour and a half.
Well, that's extraordinary!
Doesn't it make you feel
safe, ladies and gentlemen,
in a town of over 4 million people,
the constabulary can pin down
a bent needle in a haystack
in less than two hours?!
Mr Greene, you are testing
the limits of my patience.
Constable, I put it to you
that there was no real
investigation of this matter.
There couldn't possibly have been,
in the time frame.
I reject that.
I further put it to you, Constable,
that conscious of the fact that
this assault took place
in the vicinity of a well-known state-run
halfway house,
you merely cross-referenced
your information
with the list of current known occupants
of that halfway house
and, bingo, there was Mr Tanner,
two-time loser
with a barbed wire tattoo.
Had to be him!
I reject that.
So are you pissed at Vampira
or are you pissed at Fuzz?
Both. And I'm also pissed at you.
Why?
You know perfectly well why.
Because we kissed?
I don't want to talk about it.
Did it unsettle you a little?
Listen, tonight's gonna
be difficult enough, OK?
Can we just...?
Oh. Alright, darling.
We'll keep it together.
It's his special birthday.
I know. She can screw him
legally after tonight.
We should've had her charged
when we had the chance.
Who did you want charged?
No-one, Mum.
Vampira?
Mum, please.
It's a disgrace.
We keep it down a little, Prue.
Or what, Cleave?
You'll ask me for a loan?
Did you ever get those pamphlets
I sent you on euthanasia?
And so, um,
how's the new school, Fiona?
Vent Fine.
Hmm.
Got some, uh, bright students?
Some.
I must say, I think
it's a wonderful thing.
In my day, I couldn't have had a
relationship with MY French teacher.
Fiona teaches English, Carm,
and she's no longer
Finnegan's teacher.
You remember we talked
about that earlier?
I'm just saying
that Finn is a very lucky boy.
I am, Aunty Carm.
Fiona, you're such
a pretty young thing.
Carm...
Oh, here we go. She's off.
I bet there are
some hearts aflutter.
Indeed there are.
How old are you,
if you don't mind my...
Anyone for some more chicken?
You don't look a day over 21.
Got any breasts?
I'm actually 28.
Excuse me.
- Funny — you don't look 28.
- Or act it.
I beg your pardon, Mum?
Nothing, darling.
Mum, when are you going to get it?
Fiand I are in love.
That's not going to change.
If anything changes,
it's gonna be between you...
Fuzz, it's alright. Your mum's
a little stressed. Yeah?
I mean, you both...
have to understand
that this has been a kind of
tricky thing to adjust to.
Um, so let's just try
and start from scratch, shall we?
I'd like to, on this
your 16th birthday,
propose a little toast!
Which will go on till your 17th.
Fuzz, I've never seen you
looking so happy, mate.
And, um...and so I'd like to thank Fiona
for bringing us this joy.
Sorry.
Fi!
Fi, what's wrong?
What happened there?
It will be alright, darling.
I promise.
Your mum's right, mate.
It's gonna hurt like a bastard
for a while, but it'll get better.
No, it won't.
She was the one, Dad.
She's the only one.
Nah, she isn't.
It's better that
she came to her senses now
rather than in a year's time.
What do you mean,
“came to her senses”?
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have said that.
You've been undermining this
relationship from the start,
the pair of you!
It's no wonder she left me!
Settle down, mate.
Your mum just meant that
it was always gonna be tough.
You know, at some point
she was probably gonna meet
a man her own age.
He's not of her own age, Dad!
He's even younger than I am!
He's at that new school
that you guys fucking drove her to.
Fuck!
What's the technical term
for someone like Fiona?
Oh! Nut job.
Yeah, that's it.
We've gotta let
that new school know.
Yeah.
Oh! I'll call them in the morning.
No, I'll do it.
Really?
Oh, yes. I must shoulder
some of the load.
Got something on?
Witness.
Ah, yes, that assault.
The Glebe woman.
Yes, the Glebe woman.
I'd say good luck with that, but...
Oh, it'll be fine.
Be interesting to see
what it's like from the other side.
We're good, yeah?
Yeah, we're good.
Excuse me for a moment.
Oil
Miss, open the door.
I just need a minute.
Come on, open the door
or I'm gonna bust it down.
He said that
they wouldn't be here.
He promised me they wouldn't
be here! Fucking little shit!
What's going on? What is it?
That's my family, Cleave.
That's my mum and my dad.
Those people...
..are your...parents?
Unbe-fucking-lievable.
You are fucking kidding me!
Right.
So Dad wasn't a diplomat.
There was no being chased
by bandits in Honduras.
Those people are your parents.
I don't care if I never
see them again.
I don't want to ever see them again.
But Travis is my little brother, Cleave.
I mean, he's had a shit life
and it's all gonna be over
if he goes inside again.
Right, so he did it.
Yeah.
You know, if you get
in the witness box
and you lie
and it's found out,
you will not only never practise law
but you'll go to fucking jail.
Now, you might be fine with that,
you might think that's OK, it's cool.
I'm on a professional
fucking tightrope, Missy.
You know my reputation.
If I get the slightest gust of wind,
that's it for me — I'm over, done.
My name is Jane.
It's Jane Tanner.
Is it, Jane?
Well, real... Well, I've got
a couple of questions for you, Jane.
What did I ever do to make you think
that I would give a flying fuck
about where you came from, Jane?
Surely, Christ,
you know me well enough
to know that
that would make no difference.
Or do you really think
that I'm so fucking superficial
I deserve five years of bullshit?
I started the bullshit
long before I met you, Cleave.
I can't remember a time in my life
when it hasn't been bullshit.
Well, that's some consolation, Jane.
Mr Greene?
Do you recall the precise time
of your collision with Mr Tanner,
Miss Partridge?
Yes.
It was a little after 8:00.
I'd just finished a lecture.
I see.
And are you absolutely convinced that it
was the defendant, Travis Tanner?
Yes, I'm sure.
Thank you.
No further questions, Your Honour.
Really?
Yeah.
What is this incident?
The chemist's shop?
Oh, well, you want the whole story
or the abridged?
I'll give you the whole story.
No, the whole story.
It's a good story.
Mr Greene.
Thank you.
Whatever for, Miss Partridge?
A drink's in order,
don't you think, Simone?
Yes, I do. So where do we start?
Oh, well, the chemist's shop
or the drink?
http://hiqve.com/