Oh, you like it rough, don't you?
Say it!
I like it rough!
Say it.
I like it rough.
You're so dirty.
Oh, you're filthy, you know that?
Oh...
Oh, shit.
Oh...what could possibly
be so important at this hour?
I don't know.
That's why I'm checking.
Oh, fuck.
Skiddy?
Worse than Skiddy.
When did texting take pre-eminence
over actual live human
intercourse, I wonder.
It doesn't matter
where you are these days —
in a meeting, dinner with friends,
the back of a limo
rooting another man's wife —
if someone gets a text, that's it.
Everything on the planet
has to stop and give way.
Ohh, yes?
Yes.
Oh, yes, reply to the reply.
Oh, just be quiet.
Marvellous.
One second. Push me over.
I can't reach. Ooh!
I'll just be one second.
I mean, I bet if this fuckwit
had have phoned instead of texting
you would've said, “Oh, bugger it.
He can wait until morning.”
But, oh, no, no, no, he texted,
just as surely as God
would have to Moses
had Moses been able to get good
reception up there on Mount Sinai.
Let it be known
and proclaimed throughout the land
that in this brave, new,
broadly-banded world,
conversation is now officially
a second-class citizen.
Mmm.
Are you sure we can trust him?
Yeah, Claude, it's cool. He's a mate.
Remember the bloke
who was busted desecrating
Rookwood Cemetery last year?
The one who pissed
on all those graves?
Oh, come on. The poor man had
a terrible urinary tract infection.
Anyway, he owes me big-time.
Oil
You forgot something.
What?
Your lifeline.
Hmm.
Mate, I'm busting for a pee.
You must know somewhere.
The man seen here
passionately kissing
the New South Wales Premier...
Oh, Jesus.
..has been identified as
criminal barrister Cleaver Greene.
Why do they always say it like that?
“Criminal BARRISTER”?
For God's sake,
I'm not a criminal barrister.
Get the em-PHA-sis right,
for God's sake.
Your Honour, what sort
of madness is this
that here and now in the 21st century
in this palazzo of justice
we call Court 11-C,
we three men are debating the right of
a woman to choose her own clothes?
The tyranny of misogyny, Your Honour,
must be consigned
to the waste basket...
Mr Greene, are you daring
to suggest that wearing a burga
is somehow an expression
of your client's feminism?
With due respect, Your Honour,
my client doesn't wear a burqa.
She wears a nigab.
The difference being...?
The former is, to all intents
and purposes, a body bag,
the latter a simple veil.
Be that as it may, Mr Greene,
the jury and the court
both have a right
to be able to scrutinise
the disposition of any witness.
Mr Forsythe, is there anything else?
Yes, Your Honour. There was
the matter of the video confession.
Yeah, well, that appears
to be pretty straightforward so...
Mr Greene?
Your Honour, I would submit
that this video footage
is full of unsubstantiated
and uncorroborated assertions
by my client's husband
who, sadly, is unavailable
for cross-examination,
having blown himself
to kingdom come.
Your Honour, the video clearly
implicates Mrs Mohammed
in a conspiracy to blow up
Parliament House.
Alright, let's take a look.
By our actions,
the people of Australia
will know the power of our faith.
Your Parliament is no more,
having been...razed from the ground.
And the dogs within —
your prime minister,
your foreign minister —
they're gone too.
Such is the consequence
of joining the infidels of America
and other enemies of Islam
and killing of the brothers
and sisters of Iran...
..Iraq, sorry, and Afghanistan.
I go to paradise a martyr
where adorned virgins will meet me.
Jesus. What a dickhead!
If I was the Mufti
responsible for his conversion
I'd be hanging my head in shame.
If I was the Mufti
responsible for his conversion
I'd have told him
to give Scientology a crack.
Where's he hail from, Ken?
He's an Albany boy.
Born Michael Francis Coorey,
Irish Catholic mother,
Lebanese Catholic father,
the full Marist Brothers catastrophe,
odd jobs, a brief stint panelbeating,
found Islam somewhere along the line
and ended up in Yemen
where he became Yousef Mohammed
and met Zuharah,
now known either
as Mrs Mohammed or the accused.
He didn't even have
the right fucking parliament!
It looks like your girlfriend
dodged a bullet there, Cleave.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, tell us, Cleave, the premier —
is she a moaner or a screamer?
Oh, ha-ha.
Order! Order!
Order!
The Leader of the Opposition
will resume his seat!
The Premier has the call.
Thank you, Mr Speaker.
As I was saying,
I deeply and sincerely
regret the pain...
..this indiscretion has caused.
I ask that at this difficult time
my family's privacy be respected.
Hear, hear!
The task at hand
is to rebuild this state, Mr Speaker.
is to rise again from the ashes
left by those opposite,
who seem to have nothing to offer
the people of this great state
than gossip and debasement.
Order!
The Shadow Attorney-General
and the Shadow Minister
for Police, Transport,
Infrastructure, Racing, Gaming,
Climate Change, Environment
and Ethnic Affairs.
The Premier calls it
an indiscretion, Mr Speaker.
She calls it a mere indiscretion.
Well, I wonder what her husband,
the Attorney-General
and Police Minister,
thinks about that.
Do you think it was
just an indiscretion, Cal?
Order!
Order! ORDER!
You see, Mr Speaker...
..Mr Speaker, it's not just a matter of
the Premier betraying her family.
It's not just a question of her lack
of decency and integrity.
The fact that the Premier
would have an extramarital affair
with someone like Cleaver Greene
is something else altogether.
Order!
Cleaver Greene
is a dishonest low-life...
..who spends his days
defending society's scum
and his nights carousing with them!
As we speak, Greene
is defending a terrorist...
ALLEGED! Alleged terrorist. Hello!
Shh!
His story, Mr Speaker,
is a disgraceful and tawdry tale
of dishonour and deceit,
as is the Premier's!
Shut up!
Hm, he's got a lovely
speaking voice, hasn't he?
Sue. I'll sue. I will
sue the bastard for defamation.
You can't, mate.
Parliamentary privilege.
It's an abuse of the privilege,
is what it is.
So what can you do about that?
- Well, I'm going to...
- I'm...
Nicole!
Sorry you had to go through that.
Just politics.
You think I should resign?
Well, I wouldn't
be Robinson Crusoe if I did.
They're not going to make you leader,
if that's what you're thinking, Cal.
You know how you poll.
If I resign now,
it's either Stevie or Bill.
Well, it could be Karen.
Oh, long shot.
If it is Stevie or Bill
you're rooted too, you know?
So...you need me
and I need you.
It's like we're
reaffirming our vows.
Come.
Premier. Attorney.
Yep, so how bad is it?
We're fine with the blokes if the focus
groups are anything to go by.
Get a little bounce if anything.
And women?
Well, that depends. If it was
for love, you're fine — 71%.
And if it was purely sexual?
You're a skank — 90%.
And I should be...?
Standing by your woman, Cal — 76%.
Hm. OK, so I guess
it's genuine love, then.
And forgiveness.
OK, love and forgiveness it is.
Thank you, gentlemen.
So you utterly reject
the Shadow Attorney-General's
characterisation of you
as a low-life,
do you, Cleaver Greene?
I do.
I refute it in its entirety.
The Shadow Minister for Toasters,
Lobotomies and Nasal Hair,
Harry-sorry-David Potter,
hid like the coward he is under
the cloak of parliamentary privilege
when he made those obscene
remarks about me this morning.
Now, if Mr Potter really had the courage
of his so-called convictions,
if he had any intestinal
fortitude whatsoever,
he would repeat that scurrilous filth
outside the protection of Parliament.
“Cleaver Greene
is a dishonest low-life
‘who spends his days
defending society's scum
“and his nights carousing with them.
“His story, Mr Speaker,
“is a disgraceful and tawdry tale
of dishonour and deceit,
“as is the Premier's.”
Oh, itis on! It is on, mofo!
I am taking you down
for Queen and country
and maybe a little beach house
down the South Coast.
What? Oh, Jesus Christ.
Well, I mean... For God's sake, Cleaver.
Don't be such a dickhead.
You sue him, you play
right into his hands.
What are you talking about?
Your life and character
under a microscope
in a defamation case.
Come on, that's exactly
what he wants —
a chance to flail you alive.
You'll lose and end up
having to pay his costs.
Get that.
Cleaver Greene's chambers.
And it's ‘flay', not ‘flail'.
Oh, just one moment.
Flay.
Oh! “Sorry”? “Sorry”?!
I have had it with your ‘sorry's!
From day one,
this whole fucking relationship
has just been
one long series of ‘sorry's!
I want you out of this house.
I want you out of this house and
I never, ever want to see you again!
Do you hear me?!
Oh.
I need a safe haven.
I'm not sure this is the place
right now, Cleave.
What's the matter? Is it Todd?
He's been screwing some waitress.
Her husband was waiting for me
when I got home.
Jesus. How long has this...
Since before we even met,
it would seem.
Really? The whole time?
No, no, no.
If you even give me so much as an
“I told you so,” I swear to God...
Hey, Todd.
Hey, Cleave.
I want you to leave now, Todd.
No, you don't want me to do that.
Yeah, I do, I do.
I made a mistake, Wends, OK?
I am sorry.
No, no, no, stop saying sorry
like it means something.
I tried to end it
with the other girl! Cleave.
Don't...
I really... I did.
Mate, there's no point.
She's heard it all before.
Yeah, but I swear it's the truth!
The thing is she...
..she kept threatening
to hurt herself.
So what? So you're the real
victim in this situation, are you?
Well...yes, yes, I believe I am.
Where the fuck is your imagination?!
Mate, no, no.
I mean, at least Cleaver
respected me enough
to make some effort
with his bullshit.
That's right. I really put in.
He once told me that two Asian girls
I found him comforting
were Aung San Suu Kyi's cousins.
Somehow she saw
straight through it.
At least we had
a few good years.
Is that the benchmark
for a happy marriage these days,
a few good years?
What was I thinking?
I meet another lawyer
who loves to party.
Do I run a mile?
No, no. No, that would...
I marry the bastard
three months later.
“Those who do not learn from history
are doomed to repeat it.”
Oh, correct.
Oh, don't tell me
you've become one of them.
One of who?
Oh, one of those smug arseholes
who says, “Correct,”
because they're so up themselves
they think they can own a conver...
Oh, darling.
Oh...I see you've been
rooting the premier.
Political protest, darling.
At heart, I'm really an activist.
Oh.
Mmm.
Um... Oh. Is that you, darling?
Mum? Dad?
Hi, mate.
What's going on?
Oh, it's not what it looks like.
Your mum just lost her hearing aid
down the back of the sofa.
The thing is, darling, um...
Uh, it turns out that Todd's been...
Yeah, he's been busted.
There's a shock.
Zuharah. Kids.
Sorry we're so late.
Please come in, come in.
Sounds like someone's having fun.
That is where I conduct
my business.
Please, please.
They can't make me take my veil off.
Yes, they can, Zuharah.
You...you're the accused.
They'll do it forcibly if necessary.
One, two, three.
Don't say anything.
It is God's will
I wear it in public.
Well, unless you can
call God as a witness...
I'm not sure he'd have standing
as an expert in this state.
You two think you're so clever
and superior, don't you?
No. We mean no offence, Zuharah.
Please don't patronise me.
You are nothing
but a couple of hypocrites.
Oh, really?
Especially you, Mr Greene.
Tell me, what will you
be wearing at my trial?
You will be prancing
around the court
in a black gown and a white wig,
will you not?
And you think my veil is silly.
At least it serves a purpose.
Look, I take your point,
but the judge is gonna want to see
your face and so will the jury.
And so do I, to be perfectly frank.
I mean, I'm defending you
on a very, very serious charge
and if I'm gonna sell you to a jury
I need to get to know you, Zuharah.
The whole point
of the veil, Mr Greene,
is so that men like you
can't get to know me.
Men like me?
Men who seduce married women
in limousines.
Tell me, Mr Greene,
do you think you and the premier
would be in this ugly mess
if she had been dressed
as a married woman ought?
You are charged with conspiracy
to commit a terrorist act.
If you're found guilty
you're gonna go to jail
for the rest of your life
and you'll see your daughters
for a couple of hours a year.
You have to help me
to help you.
You understand?
http://hiqve.com/
I am a good Muslim.
You support jihad?
Do you know what the word
‘jihad' actually means?
‘Struggle'.
We all struggle spiritually,
gentlemen.
Violent jihad, on the other hand,
is the work of the devil, not God.
Islam preaches peace.
I do not want my daughters
to grow up in a world
where they are taught to hate.
OK, so maybe you can tell us why
large quantities of hydrogen peroxide,
propanone and ammonia
were delivered
to your house in your name?
How does someone like her
end up marrying such a tool?
The man got lost on the way
to the wrong parliament.
Mm, and she's smart.
She's kind of hot.
Am I allowed to say that
without getting fatwahed?
Maybe it was a spiritual thing.
Or maybe he was
her ticket out of Yemen.
You know how Ken's gonna play it.
‘Terrorist - the Musical'.
Uh-huh.
It'll run for a decade
and Zuharah's the star.
‘Zuharah Mohammed'. Christ, there's
four guilty votes just in her name.
Hey, have you spoken to Scarlet
again about Maxy's birthday?
And...? Yep
Still a no.
Christ, your wife's a ball-buster.
What does she want from me?
Have you told her I've already...
Already bought the present. Yeah.
More?
He's gonna go nuts.
Where's it all gonna fit? There's gotta
be some room for the guests.
No, this morning I mapped it
all out. We're fine.
Vino?
Oh, no. I'm good, thanks.
Now, I've culled the audition tapes
for the clowns down to five,
but we need to look at them tonight
because we're cutting that
way too fine.
Darling, this is
a seven-year-old's birthday party.
You've done nothing else
for three weeks.
It's like you're planning
the invasion of Afghanistan.
Huh, if only I had!
Don't you think it might be
just a little over the top?
I wanna make it perfect for him, OK?
OK.
So...
Cleaver asked me to ask again.
Feel free to ask,
but risk disappointment.
OK, I won't.
Honey, don't be like that.
Well, it's not easy for me.
We're teetering
on the edge of tranquillity
and you want to bring
Cleaver back into our lives?
He's had some bad luck.
Bad luck?
Darling,
slipping down the stairs
and breaking your leg is bad luck,
not getting busted
having sex with the premier
in the back of a limo
owned by a guy who gets his kicks
out of pissing
on the graves of dead nuns.
After everything that's happened,
if 'm prepared to forgive him,
to forgive and forget?
OK, don't do it for him.
Do it for me.
Please.
He'll be on his best behaviour.
I promise.
- There he is.
- Here he comes.
- How about a photo?
- Oh, yes, here we go.
You seen the premier again?
Stay in the middle, alright?
On the premier,
are you in love with her?
Oh, I...
Mr Greene,
are you a love rat?
Love rat? A love rat? Huh.
Ladies and gentlemen,
my client, Mrs Mohammed,
looks like a terrorist, doesn't she?
She sounds like a terrorist.
Even her name is the sort of name
you might reasonably expect
a terrorist to have —
Zuharah Mohammed.
Now, I know that you are all
good, decent, fair-minded folk,
but over the last decade or so
our suspicion of Islamic people has
blossomed, for want of a better word,
into an irrational but genuine fear.
Now, during the course of this trial
you are duty-bound
to ignore that fear —
ignore her clothes,
ignore her skin colour,
ignore her name.
And I would ask you instead
to focus on the facts.
My client is a loving mother
of two beautiful young girls,
she is a devoted sister and aunt,
she's a deeply spiritual woman
and she is a small business person of
some repute in south-western Sydney.
Mrs Mohammed,
what sort of individuals
attend your Essential Oils
and Beauty Treatment Salon?
It is a service
exclusively for Muslim women.
I should say it is not so much a salon
as a room in our house.
Sounds very discreet
and innocuous.
That's because it is, Mr Forsythe.
And what prompted you
to start up this business?
My husband was unable to find work.
We needed the money.
Mrs Mohammed, I put it to you
that in conjunction
with your husband,
you set up your business
as a means to obtain,
without raising suspicion,
the chemicals required to make
lethal explosive devices.
I deny that.
You had regular deliveries
of hydrogen peroxide,
ammonia and propanone
made to your house in your name.
That is correct.
Large quantities sometimes.
It is more economical
to buy in bulk.
And where were the chemicals kept?
In a padlocked steel cabinet inside
a locked room. We have children.
The chemicals were
for all intents and purposes
your property, were they not?
Yes.
You were the one
who made the bomb.
That's not true!
I reject violence, as does God.
Mrs Mohammed, you've seen
the video your husband made
before he set out on his journey
of mass destruction?
Objection.
Apologies, Your Honour.
Mrs Mohammed?
I've seen the video.
It was taken in your house,
was it not?
It was. You can tell by the tapestry
hanging on our living room wall.
You were behind the camera,
were you not?
No.
Then who was?
We have a tripod, Mr Forsythe.
Mrs Mohammed, propanone is also
known as acetone, is it not?
Itis.
Now, why in the devil would you need
acetone in a beauty salon?
Acetone is nail polish remover.
Oh, I see. Oh, oh.
And what about ammonia?
Surely that can't
be good for the skin.
Ammonia is a common
and highly effective cleaning agent.
And I imagine a reputable
salon proprietor such as yourself
would be keen on trying to maintain
quite a pristine working environment?
Yes, yes, I do.
And what about hydrogen peroxide?
Hair bleach. A lot of my clients
are very self-conscious.
According to Exhibit B-17,
33 litres of hydrogen peroxide
were dispensed over
one 2-week period.
That would suggest a lot of heads
in need of bleaching, Mrs Mohammed.
Yes, Your Honour, it's not
just their heads, you see.
What do you mean,
“It's not just their heads”?
Well, there are...other body parts
that may perhaps be transformed
by the use of hydrogen peroxide.
Really? What parts, Mr Greene?
Uh, well, one doesn't want
to be indelicate, Your Honour.
Indelicate? Would you please
speak frankly to the court?
Very well.
Uh, I am reliably informed,
Your Honour,
that there is currently available
a very popular procedure
called anal bleaching.
Yes, well, um...
Thank you, Mr Bleach...
Mr Brown... Mr Greene.
I think this might
be an appropriate time.
All rise.
Red,
the house looks lovely.
The house looks
lovely...
Red...
Red,
the house looks love... Oh.
I could blame
our respective workloads for this,
but the truth is...
..I have been emotionally absent
from our marriage for some time...
..and I must take my share
of the responsibility.
/ felt alone.
Um...
I am a woman
who has always loved to love
and then this strange man,
Cleaver Greene, came into my life
and I felt a need, a longing.
Oh, the only thing you ever
longed for was a nasty shag.
..Spun a web of words.
l...1 fell deeply
in love with him...
Bring me a bucket!
..though it was torture
emotionally.
I was full of guilt and remorse
and when I told Cleaver
I had to break it off
he threatened to go public
about it...
Oh, yes?
He put me in an impossible position.
Oh, you f... What?
Oh, I was blackmailing you?
Oh, right. Yeah, yeah, I was
blackmailing you. Jesus Christ.
..brought us closer
than we've been in many years.
Up, around...
Red.
House looks lovely.
Cleaver.
You look great.
Thank you.
The present table's outside.
Drinks are out there too.
Hey, uh, I was wondering
if we could have a little chat.
Oh?
Well, it's been a while.
Today's not the best day.
Of course.
Before entering the castle,
you must be wearing one of these.
Now, there can be no more
than two persons
in the castle at any one time...
What I care about, Cleaver,
is what kind of job the premier's doing,
not who she's screwing.
Yeah, but there still remains
a question about her judgement.
You know, it's a bit like
Clinton and Monica Lewinsky.
Ah, I guess.
Yeah, and you're Monica, Cleaver.
Yes, yes, I got that one.
Yeah, you're the girl underneath
the president's desk, right?
I imagine that it was
a thrill at the time,
but has it not left
a stain on your soul?
Oh...
People are entitled
to their own private lives.
Correct.
I'm not about to judge you.
I'm not about to judge the premier.
I say live and let live.
But you do know there's
a spiritual dimension to all this.
Infidelity's a mortal sin.
Correct.
Put the two together, we're gonna
shake them about, shake it about.
The birthday boy's
gonna give it a blow.
And then a one and a two
and a... Whoa!
You guys have been wonderful.
You've been so good. Happy birthday.
Time for
pirate fairy bread.
That was terrific, mate.
Thanks. Well done.
Oh, cheers. Yeah, yeah. Well,
they're a lovely bunch of kids.
You fancy a beer?
Uh... Oh, I shouldn't.
But, uh...
Oh, what the hell? Yeah, yeah.
You wouldn't happen to have
any vodka, would you, mate?
Yeah, sure.
Great.
Won't be long.
I mean... mean, sometimes
they don't give you anything.
And I'm not just
talking about a tip, right?
And it's not like I'm charging
a fortune, am I, Bernie?
No, you're not. No.
And it was a really great show.
And...and I'm not just another idiot
actor trying to make ends meet.
I give these kids the best two hours
they've ever had in their lives...
..in their entire fucking lives...
Hey!
Hey, mate, mind your language.
Whoa, no.
There's kids.
You should hear the way
some of the parents talk to me.
Wait for it.
“I would've thought
that you brought your own water.”
My own water, mate! Hey?
Mate, do I...I know you?
Uh, I don't know.
Have we met at the circus?
You're that bloke that's
been rooting the premier.
Oh, mate, hey.
Aren't ya, hey?
Language, mate.
Are you a Tory, mate?
Not since I had
my haemorrhoids attended to.
Cleaver!
How can you fucking look yourself
in the mirror?
Mate, mate, the language.
What?
After what she's done to this state...
She's raped it!
Hey, knock it off!
Your language, mate.
Be that as it may...
Be what as it may, mate?
Alright, you want the truth?
Yeah.
Leave it.
Yes? Right-wing chicks are hot.
Don't.
I beg your pardon?
Much hotter than left-wing chicks.
You know why that is?
Because right-wing chicks
are aggressively carnivorous,
self-reliant, Ayn Rand acolytes
who understand
the value of the moment.
Hey, Cleave...
They get that sex
is something in and of itself,
beholden to nothing and no-one
and as a consequence
of that understanding
they're less inhibited
and therefore hornier.
Left-wing chicks, on the other hand,
they're vegans who want
a holistic experience,
they're all about context,
they talk about an orgasm
like it's a pet spaniel
and so consequently
the moment's ruined.
And this, Mr Clown, is the real reason
why the left has carked it —
because the right
is constantly procreating
while the left
is grooming a dead dog.
My mother was a communist.
Oh, so you're adopted.
You fuck!
Just go.
The clown was drunk.
..though
it was torture emotionally.
I was full of guilt and remorse
and when I told Cleaver
I had to break it off
he threatened to go public about it
and ruin my career.
He put me in
an impossible position...
Oh, God.
It was fantastic dirty sex,
pure and simple.
That's how she wanted it.
No infatuation,
no longing, no love.
I mean, it just seems
incredible to me
that people are buying her crap.
The press has done nothing
but call the premier
on all of her broken promises.
Every day in the papers
you guys have got a list of them.
And yet now because of a couple
of Academy Award-worthy performances
from the premier and Mr Streep
suddenly she's Abraham Lincoln.
Well, here's the real scoop, Richard.
The premier and her husband
can barely stand being
in the same parliament together,
let alone the same bed.
Do you have any proof of that?
Well, you know, the premier is a big fan
of the text message. BIG fan.
As am I, I have to say.
And I'm just scrolling through
my messages as we speak.
OK, here's one from
the 4th of this month.
Quote — “Skiddy boring punters
to death at dinner in Newcastle.
“Hook up? Urgent need
to get down and dirty.”
Then she signs off, “XXX-rated.”
Shit!
Do you know who ‘Skiddy' is, Richard?
Shut up!
Skiddy is the premier's husband,
the Attorney-General
and Police Minister of this state.
She calls him ‘the Skidmark' behind
his back, or ‘Skiddy' for short.
How's that for terms of endearment?
Cleaver Greene, are you saying
that is a text message
to you from the premier?
Yes, I am absolutely saying that
and I am saying that
I have got dozens like it.
You sent him dirty texts?
Jesus fucking Christ!
Has Shane Warne
taught you nothing, Claudia?
Claude?!
Claude, I'm not sure
there's a way around this.
Oh, of course there's
a fucking way around this!
There's always a fucking way
around everything
because that's what we do,
don't we, Cal?
That's how we spend our time,
consume our careers and lives
finding ways round things!
Do you remember when
you told me to run, Cal?
You were groping my arse
at Nick's birthday.
I thought it was all about
the ideas back then.
Fuck.
It seemed so obvious how to make
other people's lives better.
The next day I said,
“Yeah, sure, I'll run.”
Then you left Grace
and we got married.
But that's the last time
we talked about ideas
and from that day on
it's just been running
and winning and running and...
Well, you gotta be invited
to the dance, darling...
I've been invited
to the fucking dance, Cal!
I'm queen of the fucking prom
and I haven't had a chance
to do a single move of my own.
I've just been running
and winning and...
What happened to the ideas?
It's too late for ideas.
I know.
I'll deal with Greene.
Hm, good.
I never attempted
to blackmail the premier.
I never threatened to go
public about our relationship, OK?
I never threatened her
in any way at all. She's lying.
She never tried to break it off
and I never said I would
go public if she did.
You don't have a case for blackmail.
Cleave, like I said,
no-one's charging you
with anything at this point.
These are simply
preliminary enquiries.
Well, you know what? I actually
wouldn't mind being charged, Murph.
I actually would like to see
this whole fucking nightmare
played out in court.
You know why? I'd win
because I have the texts.
OK, this is not my phone.
What do you mean?
It's not my phone.
Sure you picked up the right one
after you came through security?
It was pretty crowded down there.
You're fucking kidding me.
Hey, relax, Cleave. If your phone
is here, we'll find it.
You're sure that's your phone?
Yes!
And the texts?
What do you reckon, Barn?
All gone, every one of them wiped.
Pricks! This is Cal McGregor.
Alright, mate, calm down.
Fuck!
Mate!
You're gonna have to write me
an affidavit in support.
In support of what?
You're the only other person
who's seen the texts.
I haven't seen them.
You told me about them.
Yes, I read them out to you.
You read out two. I didn't see them.
I can't say I saw them, Cleave.
What? You don't believe me?
It's not about that.
Look, mate, I've got a conference.
Barney, I'm being attacked by every
level of the system right now.
I will happily put in an affidavit
saying what you told me,
but I cannot and will not
perjure myself, OK?
You know the texts exist!
I'm not asking you to lie.
Yes, you are, Cleaver!
You just don't get it, do you?
I've got a conference.
Come.
This just came for you.
Oh, ta.
Latte?
Uh, no, no. I'm good.
My father never came
to any sports days.
He never showed any emotions...
let alone affection.
He was like this iceberg...
Barney, um, I'm sorry to interrupt,
but do you really think this has
something to do with your father?
Sorry?
‘Cause let me tell you, it has nothing
to do with your father.
Doesn't it?
No.
Nor does it have anything
to do with Scarlet's mother.
They're sideshows, Barney.
Really?
These are my notes on you guys,
all our sessions,
couples and one-on-one.
I did an audit this morning.
And...?
Well...
Barney, I've never said this
before in my life
to a patient, a colleague, anyone.
In fact, I could be deregistered
for what I'm about to say.
But forget Mummy and Daddy, OK?
The problem you and Scarlet
are confronting —
both as individuals
and in terms of your marriage —
is so absurdly obvious
I don't know what else to say.
Go on.
It's Cleaver Greene.
Jesus Christ.
She's in free fall, mate.
I've never seen anything like it.
57% of the New South Wales public
think that Cleaver Greene is
more trustworthy than the premier?
I mean, that can't
possibly be right.
Not only that.
69% think the blackmail allegations
are politically motivated.
So what are my options?
Dump Claude and you'll get
an eight-point bounce.
When you say dump her,
do you mean politically
or personally?
Both.
Which I could only do if...
..I was shocked to find out
that Cleaver's side of the story
was the truth.
Shocking
though that would be.
Shocking.
It's not enough
to get you the leadership,
but it's enough to give you some
wiggle room with Stevie or Bill
if you wanna hang on
to AGs and Police.
Hmm.
Oh, it's a pity...
..about not pursuing
the charges against Greene.
It was the one thing I was
looking forward to this week.
Yeah, g'day, Stevie.
How are you, mate?
Look, I've just happened upon a file
of text messages between Claude
and Cleaver Greene and, uh...
Well, quite frankly, I'm...I'm at a loss
as to what to do with them.
Well, I'd be grateful
for your advice, mate,
because there's every possibility
that tomorrow you could be premier.
So, Dr Fisher, how would you describe
this mixture of materials?
Lethal as a combination, obviously.
And what can you tell us about the
mechanical components of the bomb?
Uh, pretty standard, really.
Basic shrapnel — nails primarily.
It's not usual in such a case
to find evidence of remote detonation,
but that's always a possibility.
I'm sorry. You found evidence
of potential remote detonation?
Yes.
Is that usual in such a bomb?
I mean, my understanding
is that in cases like this
the bombs are usually self-detonated.
Well, sometimes
there's a fail-safe —
if the bomber is incapacitated,
then the detonator can still
be triggered by somebody else.
So, Dr Fisher,
could this remote detonation
have been triggered
by a mobile phone call?
That's a common method, yes.
Get Zuharah's mobile bills.
Dr Fisher, if the objective was
to blow up Parliament House,
this was an amateurish joke
of an attempt, wasn't it?
I would never describe such intentions
as jokes, Mr Greene.
How big was the bomb, Dr Fisher?
For anyone else to have been
seriously injured or killed
they would've had to be standing
shoulder-to-shoulder
with Mr Mohammed.
Really? So then the damage to
Parliament itself would have been...?
Negligible.
Mr Greene?
Uh, one moment, Your Honour.
Very well.
Uh, no further questions,
Your Honour,
but at this point
I would like to tender
my client's mobile phone records
for the relevant period.
You'll note that my client sent
no text messages on that morning
and made only one phone call,
which was apparently to her dentist
to make an appointment
for one of her daughters.
This doesn't preclude
the possibility
that Mrs Mohammed purchased
another SIM card
in order to detonate the bomb.
Well, then, Your Honour,
we would be keen to see
evidence of such a purchase.
Your Honour, I seek an adjournment
so we can make proper inquiries.
Your Honour,
what inquiries?
You can get a SIM card
with any packet of breakfast cereal
these days.
The things are a dime a dozen.
And you will recall, Your Honour,
that my client's home was raided.
Her computer and documents
have been seized.
The Crown has had ample opportunity
to furnish us with such evidence
if indeed it did exist.
It clearly does not.
I agree, Mr Greene.
There are no witnesses,
ladies and gentlemen.
My client's only possible
substantive connection with this crime
is that she purchased some chemicals
which MAY have been
used to make the bomb —
chemicals, I might add,
which any of us could
purchase this very afternoon.
But do you know what the worst thing is
about the prosecution's case?
It is a case
that is rooted in prejudice.
Had Mr Mohammed
not converted to Islam,
but had it have been old Mike Coorey
who'd blown himself up on that day,
this case would never be being tried
as an act of terrorism.
This would be a case
about a sad, mentally ill guy
who'd gone postal.
The forensic evidence
proves beyond reasonable doubt
that had Mr Mohammed walked down
Macquarie Street with a cricket bat,
he would have been
better placed to take life.
The device
in Mr Mohammed's backpack
was only ever going
to kill one person...
Uh, Mr Greene?
Yes, Your Honour.
I was merely restating the point
that the device that
Mr Mohammed was carrying
was...was patently inadequate
for its alleged purpose.
This just arrived,
marked ‘Private and Confidential'.
And we've just heard —
Greene got the terrorist off.
Of course he did. Thanks.
We're very pleased for you.
Excuse me.
Hi, mate. Yeah, yeah.
It must be
a gratifying and rare experience
to have a genuinely
innocent client acquitted.
Yes, well, you're no terrorist.
That's for sure.
This was just plain
old-fashioned murder, wasn't it?
I beg your pardon?
You sent your husband
out on a mission
that could only ever have one result.
Not only was there barely enough
explosive to kill him,
but you were able to detonate it
before he hit Macquarie Street.
Whatever he believed
he was doing,
there was only ever one target
and that was your husband.
The genius of it, the bit I love,
is the gall of it —
playing to our prejudices,
hiding a big crime
inside a much bigger crime,
knowing you'd be
labelled a terrorist
instead of a husband killer.
An absurd fiction, Mr Greene.
Here you were,
stuck with this moron who wanted
to go out and blow people up,
who was filling your daughters' heads
full of ideas that you despised,
an insufferable fool
who you couldn't divorce.
I had a great-uncle
who used to say
there was only ever one way
to truly end a marriage.
But I'm sure Western society
has come to a much more sophisticated
and happy means
of settling such matters.
Thank you, Mr Greene.
Please send your account
to the house.
My best wishes to your family.
Mr Speaker, I have here transcripts
of text messages between
the premier and Mr Cleaver Greene.
They are dated and timed.
I seek leave to table
these transcripts
so that the premier may respond.
Might I add that these are every bit as
shabby as one might have expected.
Every bit as shabby, Mr Speaker!
Have a look, Premier!
They're right here.
They're in your own words.
No? No?
She won't even have a look.
Won't even have a look!
- Order! Order!
- Resign, resign, resign!
Order! Order!
Beer?
I'm pulling the plug, mate.
On what?
You and me.
What did I do this... Oh, come on.
Mate, the clown got pissed.
Cleave, it's...it's too hard, mate.
This is Scarlet, isn't it?
Yes, in part, but it's me too.
I've come to a fork in the road.
Yeah, or a knife in the back, mate.
Or a runcible spoon
up the arse maybe.
Getting theatrical's not gonna help.
If I have to choose between you
and my family, I'll choose my family...
I don't see why
there has to be a choice.
Alright, we've had
our ups and downs, but...
Is that some sort of joke?
Cleave, it has to be this way.
Cal.
Hey, Cleave. It's been a while.
Oh, it doesn't feel that long.
Jesus, you're a slippery bastard.
Every time I thought I...
What can I do for you, Skiddy?
The Drug Squad's received a tip-off
suggesting there may be
a trafficable amount
of a proscribed substance
somewhere in this vicinity.
And by ‘vicinity',
I mean this apartment.
And by ‘prescribed substance',
I mean the 50 bags of coke
I've just hidden here.
Yeah, they should be here
in about 10... Oh, maybe 9 minutes.
So if I were you...
..I'd probably do
the first few bags I found
‘cause they're gonna be your last.
Oh...
http://hiqve.com/