For the love of Judith Christ, mate.
Do we have to have
this conversation again?
Hartford, Styles and Menzies?
That's not a fucking appeal,
but that's an inquisition.
A lot of people in your situation
can find the loss of an appeal
more devastating than
the initial conviction.
Not with my parole hearing coming up.
The Parole Board
does love a little bit of repentance.
Good thing I wrote that
in the guidelines, eh?
Arrgh! Fuck. Oh...
I want to sing, Cleave.
That's what I want to do.
You're thick with the...
the Chief, aren't you?
Yes, but maybe not so much now.
Live the dream.
Live the dream, my friend.
There may be a way around this.
- What is it?
- Bearbung, Cleaver.
- Bearbung.
- Talk to me, Kieran.
Good luck with the appeal, Cleaver.
- See you on the outside, fellas.
- Give 'em hell, Cleave.
Kick him in the nuts for me,
mate.
Thanks, fellas.
I almost miss him.
Always good for a laugh.
No, not even in jest.
The man is a coke-addled sexual deviant.
It was you who caught him humping
Beck Nissel in the loo, wasn't it?
No, Mandy, the sister.
Beck was later, in the lift.
Prison is where the man belongs.
Oh, heavens, we all agree about that.
Oh, God, yes. The only place for him.
Hi.
No grandstanding in there.
Just look humble. Don't be a smart-arse.
I'm... I am St Francis of Assisi.
I am a father unto my flock.
Just ordinary, decent.
I'll channel Harry 'Sorry' David.
You know what? I don't need this.
I am frantically busy.
If you want to defend yourself,
here are my notes.
Best thing that's going to happen today
is maybe we get a retrial.
- There's certainly grounds...
- Hey, Red. What's wrong?
OK, I'm sorry. OK.
I'm sorry. Please. Come on, please.
I cannot spend any more time in this
fucking shithole waiting for a retrial.
Well, what are you expecting today?
My old life. I want it back.
I want everything.
I want the bar, I want the bars.
I want Barney.
I want Sundays with Wendy and Fuzz.
I want my fucking life back.
Given the bench,
I wouldn't hope for too much.
- Mention Bearbung.
- Bearbung?
I'm not citing a case
I know nothing about.
Just say it.
All rise.
In all, there were,
in Judge Walter's summations,
some eight clear breaches of law
in his instruction to the jury.
Bored, Miss Engels.
You have made this point three times.
- And each time, it failed to land.
- Move on.
On six occasions, there was a failure...
By the appellant's counsel to present
anything interesting to this court.
..to allow admissible evidence.
It's difficult to look
at the transcript of this trial
and not query whether there was
some sort of set against the appellant.
Miss Engels, if you are
imputing any bias by this bench,
you may find yourself
joining the appellant.
No, Your Honour.
But the appellant
was a prominent Sydney barrister
who has now languished in prison
for 11 months
when any single one of these
13 instances
create clear grounds for a mistrial.
Rubbish.
Rubbish, rubbish, rubbish.
Could I add, rubbish?
- Bearbung.
Bearbung.
Can you instruct your client
to stop that?
- Has the man Tourette's or something?
- Bearbung.
Excuse me, Your Honour.
A slight case thereof.
Under stress,
I cough and say the word 'Bearbung.'
I have no... Bearbung.
I have no idea why,
just a thing since childhood.
Excuse me. Bearbung.
- I think I've had quite enough.
- Quite agree.
Ah, yes.
But before we completely dismiss this,
I think I did see something of merit
in one of Miss Engel's points.
Fuck!
- What just happened in there?
- Fucking Kieran Webster.
- He must have told Greene.
- Told him what?
I believe it has something to do with
Eddie's retirement plans.
What the hell happened in there?
Who or what is Bearbung?
Well, 'bearbung' is an Aboriginal word
meaning ‘an illegally obtained lease
between an appellant judge
and a mining company.'
It's a beautiful word.
- Are you happy with today's result?
- Innocent, boys and girls.
Completely innocent.
Three judges with one voice
declared what happened to me
an egregious miscarriage of justice.
One of them seemed very close to tears.
Will you be seeking compensation?
Look, that's all for the future.
I just want to spend some quality time
with my family and loved ones,
my friends.
Thank you. That'll be all.
I do have family and friends, don't I?
You and me!
Mates on the inside,
then mates on the out!
Who would have thought it?
Yes. How are you, mate?
Thanks for coming.
I wouldn't have missed it for nothing.
You should go and be with your family.
- Give me a call when you can, hey?
- Alright, mate. Thank you for that.
How are you, are you alright?
Yeah, I'm good. It's just...
No, I'm good. I love you, mate.
Great, great.
- I love you, mate.
- Thanks for coming, Mal.
Look after yourself, yeah?
Oi!
Isn't there some sort of
celebratory something?
Where's Barnyard?
Quite a bit has happened
since you went inside.
Oh, yeah?
Barney...
Barney has cancer.
What do you mean?
What sort of cancer?
Bad cancer?
Fuck.
Red...
Red?
Fuck! Why didn't somebody tell me?
He must be a mess.
Looking marvellous, everybody.
And turn.
Fantastic, Barney. One more.
Barnyard.
Hey.
You've put on some weight.
Prison must suit you, mate.
Forget about me. You!
Scarlet told me - cancer.
- Fuck, mate!
- Yeah, of the cods.
- Barney!
- One of them, anyway.
- I don't know what to say.
- You know what, mate?
It's the greatest thing
that has ever happened to me.
Every day is a blessing.
I breathe in life, exhale joy.
I can't get enough of my kids.
Jilly, tell me you've got one of those
fantastic cream doughnuts.
I saved one especially for you.
- You have to try one of these.
- Right.
So what did the doctors say?
Ah, 50/50. I've got some secondaries
in the old lymphs.
Actually, I'm already a 50.
They've taken one off.
OK, now, slowly.
Feel the way the cream
oozes into the mouth.
Don't rush it.
Savour!
Hm?
- What's that?
- That's it - my cancerous testicle.
- Oh, Barn!
- Hard to believe all life starts here.
- Oh, mate!
- Children come from this.
They don't come from a bloody key ring.
It's just an organ!
We eat stuff like this.
Nobody wants to look at a ball in aspic.
I've been in prison for 11 months
without a woman.
In a single moment,
you've put me off sex for another 11.
- Come on.
- Jesus.
So, come on -
what stage of the treatment are you at?
One more hit of chemo to go.
I'm thinking I may not
go back to work, mate, ever.
Ever?
Well, sure.
You know, whatever you think.
You more than anyone I know
need mental stimulation, don't you?
It would be a shame if
you pulled yourself through all of this
and then there was nothing there.
Terrible.
But take your time.
Whatever you need.
I'm fine. I'll be alright.
So don't worry about that.
I'm, you know,
I'm right back in the game.
- You sure the game still wants you?
- They found me innocent.
- Acquitted or innocent?
- Yes, yes.
So, are you up for a walk?
I cycle everywhere now -
fitness and freedom
in the one light-alloy machine.
- You can't be serious?
- Never give in to it.
- Oh, Barn.
- The trick is, embrace the beast.
Trick. It's also a trick
to piss-spell your name in snow.
You just end up with yellow slime
on your boots.
Trust me - I'm good, Cleave.
It was great to see you.
I'll call you tomorrow.
Barn!
Thank you.
You heard the news, I suppose?
Cal McGregor's out
and Cleaver Greene just got acquitted.
I heard. Two arseholes released
to make way for most of my front bench.
The big positive
about Les getting jailed
is that it weakens the Right's grip
on the party.
So, if we woo Bryce,
we've got the centre alliance
and we own Sussex Street.
How can there still be factions?
There are 12 of us.
There are still 12 of us, aren't there,
Clayton?
Geoff and Alsop are giving their
statements now to the Commission.
Both gave me their word
they're not involved.
Both made public statements
to that effect.
- So all good?
- Alsop should be fine.
And Geoff?
Jesus! Is there anyone in this party
not involved in graft?
- That's not rhetorical, by the way.
- You're holding the reins, mate.
You've got a 21% approval rating,
which is not bad,
given the state of the party.
I wonder how that 21% decided they
like me. I haven't done anything yet.
Plus,
the whole gay question's gone away.
They think I'm gay
because I support same-sex marriage?
Well, you're not married. Well-groomed.
Nice bloke.
And that celebrity prostitute
you were engaged to
described you as ‘honourable'
and 'decent' - all code words.
What are you doing here?
- I live here.
- No, you live in prison.
Oh, sorry.
Oh, how great!
The appeal, they actually let you out.
Well, good. That's...
Oh, it's good to see you.
Sorry, I wasn't...
The general feeling was,
they wouldn't...
You remember my mother, Maria?
Hey, Cleave.
I could have dinked ya.
There's a very small, bald person.
lain Vargas Meagher,
meet Cleaver Greene.
Barney, can you... stop that?
That is disgusting.
Just reminding the lad
where he came from.
New life, eh, Cleave?
I've got to fly. I'm helping out
at the school this arvo.
- Oh, sorry.
- That's alright.
Right.
So, um...
You can sleep on the couch tonight.
Mum's a bit of a snorer.
You had Barney's baby.
You had a baby with Barney.
With Barney! A b-b-baby.
That's the situa...
Is that what has happened here?
The paperwork would indicate
that is the case.
OK, so he's lost a ball
and he's fathered a baby?
- Yep.
- And you called the baby 'lan'?
It's spelled I-A-I-N.
Oh, that makes all the difference -
'Ee-ayn.'
I've got to go, so...
So, what? You're off
working for another barrister now?
I am living the dream.
Of all the things I've heard so far
today, that would surprise me the least.
OK. I've got to get a cash flow going.
I've got to get some clients on the go.
I've got to get a little space
somewhere else.
Like I said, I'm on my way.
That's been cut off,
so you'll need to use your mobile.
I don't have a mobile!
Until a couple of minutes ago,
I was a murderer.
Beautiful.
Malcolm Finnane?
Where's Malcolm Finnane?
- I'm Finnane.
- Look at you.
Straight out of deepest, darkest prison.
How long inside, Malcolm?
- 17 years.
- Wonderful.
- And now on parole?
- Yep.
I know I'm being a gay cliché,
but at 3:20am in my cold, little flat,
do you know what I thought?
- No.
-'I'm listening to the next Susan Boyle
except in prison.'
You are not to go through that door.
I am exercising a super veto card.
No audition - straight to air.
The first time our judges hear you
will be on Monday 7th July
when all of Australia does.
Tuesday, the name
'Malcolm Finnane' will be viral.
So I'm on the show?
You'll be singing Valjean.
Of course you know the song?
Yes, I've heard it, but I was
going to sing the aria from Tosca.
Valjean, Les Mis - One Day More.
And you and I are friends for eternity.
Bye-bye.
Fuzz, this is your old dad.
I am a free man, mate.
I am cleared of all charges,
and I'm hanging out to see you, pal.
Can't wait.
I'm going to swing by the house
later on, OK? See ya.
Harley, mate!
Harley!
Cleave! I thought you were in the nick.
The court saw the error of its ways.
What are you up for?
- Bit of murder.
- Fantastic.
I'm here for you. Give us a call.
Actually, don't call me!
- I'm going to write down my address.
- Mate, I'm seeing someone. Sorry.
Tadpole! What are you up for?
Arson. Bye, Cleave.
Oh, yes.
Ah!
My client, my secretary,
my best friend's wife.
You were in prison.
So you decided to steal my secretary
and my entire client base?
Your client base?
A rag-bag cluster of low-life sink hair?
Not you, Harley.
Barney referred them to me.
Nobody thought to ask me?
Why would we need to ask you?
These guys need a counsel who could
physically attend a courtroom.
I'm sorry - you two, together, in the...
This woman,
she has had your husband's love child.
Yes. She and her are well aware of that.
What do you want me to do, demonise her?
We've worked through the issues.
We sat down and we talked it out.
Maybe you should try it some time.
Yeah. We cried and laughed.
The fact Barney has cancer
brings us even closer together.
We realised we actually like each other.
Best buds, aren't we, Nic?
I've died. I'm in hell.
It's a never-ending chick flick.
And you!
You and I are family.
I've watched you grow over the years.
Three assaults,
one possession of an illegal firearm.
Who was there by your side every time?
- You were, mate.
- Me.
Who talked a judge down
from a three-year
to a nine-month suspended sentence?
- You did.
- Me.
Who was there for your brother's
first GBH
and your cousin's assault
with a deadly weapon?
Me, me, me. And now that you get
a decent murder, where are you?
Off with somebody else. Well, that's
loyalty, that's friendship for you.
Cleaver, your world is different now.
Harley is completely free
to choose whomever he likes.
If he wants to walk back to a man
who has no chambers...
No phone.
..no standing in the legal world,
then please do so, Harley.
But otherwise,
I've got a meeting to go to.
Alright, well, fuck you all very much.
And I'll...
I'll be OK to find my own way out.
And I do have a phone, by the way.
Gareth, my old friend.
Cleaver. Cleaver Greene.
Yes. No, out.
Out, cleared, innocent.
Yeah, OK - quashed.
I'm out, I'm available for work.
Cindy, baby. Cleaver Greene.
How are you?
Listen, ah, just to say that
if you needed...
OK, well, there are other barristers
than her, and I am one of them.
Arrgh!
- Shit!
- Damn! Are you alright?
Yeah. I just got attacked
by some battleship cruiser.
Do you think, just for once,
we could do this in a hotel?
This is the only secure place.
Mother doesn't mind, I promise.
I mind. This has got to stop.
This is wrong on so many levels.
He had a baby with somebody else.
You were going to leave him, then...
Yes, then.
Until he's either better or...
not, I can't do this anymore,
not with Simon Le Bon looking down on me
and the TV blaring in the next room.
I know. Babe, please.
I can't live without you. I just...
There's someone outside.
I think it's a journo.
Not everyone in the world is a journo.
Why would he be interested in
tailing the leader of the world's
smallest opposition party?
Have you been talking to Greene
about this?
Yeah. I thought he should know,
and I showed him photos.
No, please. Just stick around,
just until I've gone.
Mum really likes you.
I love you.
Lincoln!
Lincoln, Lincoln!
Mate!
I have missed you.
- You're out!
- I'm out.
I went to visit you
about half a dozen times.
They said you said, Piss off."
And you believed them?
Mate! I was in solitary for four months.
I couldn't get a note out.
I'm writing a book about it.
Wow. So... are you out on parole?
No, no. I'm free, innocent.
Acquitted or quashed?
Yeah. So, free for work, huh? Old times.
Oh, no. I've got nothing worthy of you.
I've got tiny stuff.
I've got a DUI. The guy wanted
to fight it but I said it's probably...
Oh, come on. If four months in solitary
has taught me anything,
it's that every man must stand
and fight for his rights.
Mr McGregor!
Let me not keep you good folk
out here in this winter chill.
I am genuinely grateful
for my time here.
It gave me a chance to reflect
and to ask some pretty serious questions
of myself,
I now realise that in my zealousness to
protect the great people of this State,
I lost my own moral compass.
Mr McGregor,
one more question before you go.
Cal, Cal? So what now?
What for the future?
Well, apart from a life of service,
I really haven't given it any thought.
- God bless.
- Thank you, Mr McGregor.
http://hiqve.com/
God bless you, Mick.
Get me the fuck out of this shithole,
will you?
Oh, yeah!
Ah, no.
No speak Polish.
No Polish. No.
Sorry. Bye-bye now.
Oh, my God!
Cleave! Oh, your appeal!
- You're out!
- Yes. Yes, I'm out.
There's a big for-sale sign.
Yes, you can't stay. As soon as
the bread has finished baking,
we've got to go.
We're open for inspection.
- Are we?
- Come and have a quick glass of wine.
- Roger's here?
- Yeah, Roger lives here now.
Oh, Roger lives here now.
Where's Fuzz?
Why wasn't he at my bloody appeal?
You could have at least sent him.
He might have forgotten.
He's doing this intensive study course.
- He's going to work in Africa.
- Hello, Cleaver.
Welcome back to the land of the living.
How was it in there?
- Work in Africa?
- He and Tara are going to the Congo
to build hospitals and schools
and sing happy hymns.
- He's very committed to it.
- Bloody Congo?
No son of mine
is going to do good works.
What happened to university?
- His father went to prison.
- How long have I been asleep?
What happened to the world while I was
inside? I feel like Rumpelstiltskin.
- We sat down as a family and decided...
- What family was this?
Fuzz and myself and Roger and Tara,
we all agreed
that you were too much a part of this
house and we needed to move forward.
Oh, did we?
Did we all have a vote on that?
It was like you were dead, Cleave.
There were too many sad memories
and there was too much shit.
Rip van Winkle.
What?
It was Rip van Winkle
who slept for 100 years.
Rumpelstiltskin was the riddle guy.
You're killing me. You know that, Wendy?
I'm not meaning to.
We're getting married, mate.
Blow, bugles, blow
Set wild echoes flying
Blow, bugles
Answer echoes dying, dying, dying.
It was Rip van Winkle.
I didn't think
I'd hear from you for days.
I thought you'd be doing some
massive family thing.
Oh, you know, they all wanted to.
I was keen to keep it low-key.
I've got some news.
I followed your advice.
I did that audition thing.
And Tarquin, he heard my tape.
He really liked it.
A turtle listened to your tape?
Oh, no. That's a terrapin.
He reckons I could be some kind of
sensation. I don't really believe him.
Would you come?
It would mean a mountain if you did.
- Monday the 9th?
- Sure, mate.
Sorry, what are we talking about here?
What did I recommend?
You said I should audition
for Aussies Gotta Sing.
- Did I?
- Yeah.
You said, 'If you make your voice heard,
then people will listen.'
You said,
'Follow your dreams, my friend."
Mm. Right.
Sorry, mate - which show is it?
Is it the one where everybody's nice
to you or the one with the arsehole?
Yeah, Gordon.
Yeah, he's famous.
Increasingly, I hear people are famous.
I've no idea who any of them are.
He had a massive hit - Toledo Mio.
Oh, Gordon Martin, Toledo Mio.
Oh, yes. Early '90s - '92, '93.
Must have charted
for about three minutes in the top ten.
Do you really think it's a good idea
to let yourself be judged by this man?
You don't think I should do it?
You think it's a mistake?
No, no. No.
Just don't put too much weight
in that clown's opinion.
This is it for me, mate.
It's my only way out.
I'm not like you.
You can jump straight back in.
If I can do this, if I can
get a little bit famous, you know?
People forgive you, don't they?
Yeah.
Yeah!
Fame is the great
get-out-of-jail-free card.
If you take away the senseless violence,
fear for your life, man rape,
the slammer wasn't so bad, was it?
You know, quiet cell, pleasant company.
I reckon that year with you
was one of the happiest of my life.
Fuck, mate. It hasn't been
all Vogue Living in your life, has it?
Don't do that.
I'll get you another drink.
Sh, sh!
Sorry.
Shut up!
Thanks a bloody bundle.
I'm sorry. I completely forgot.
There's a new world order.
I'm in Topsy-Turvy Land.
No, they're not going to have any sex.
Did you take my mother's phone?
What?
No!
What does it look like?
♪ Oh, Toledo
♪ Gonna give my baby the heave-ho. ♪
Morning.
Ah, Chantelle.
Holy sh... Tikki!
Hello, Cal sweetie.
How's the hotel? How were the girls?
Oh. Oh, very good.
Thank you, Tikki.
I didn't realise you were coming.
Let me get changed.
No! Sit down. Relax.
Alright. Alright.
Lovely to see you
back in the real world.
- Yes.
- So, have you given any thought
to what you might do
now that you're out?
Ah, yes. Yeah. I've got a few plans.
Here's what I think we need you to do.
You're going to host a new television
program on one of my cable thingies,
and I think you would be adorable.
Well! I hadn't really
thought of the media,
but it does seem like a natural fit.
A current-affairs,
right-slant newsy thing?
Whatever you like, darling.
Bit of a rant,
mostly gambling and scandal.
That's what the public needs.
I presume
there's strings attached to this?
More ropes than strings, pet.
I need you to be au fait
with my new business model.
Have you got a dollar coin there, love?
Yeah, yes.
Just pop your one dollar into that.
And I give you back, say, 20 cents.
Uh-huh.
80 for me, 20 for you.
It's the perfect business model.
It's called a casino.
I am currently tendering
to build a new one.
I want to create something magnificent,
a great cathedral,
where people of all nations,
mainly China and Singapore,
come to worship in its chambers.
But I'm copping a lot of flack -
churches and anti-gambling lobbyists.
There's even talk of it being
a sacred site.
How can land on Sydney Harbour
be sacred?
The place is a festival of desecration.
Exactly.
Cal, I want it more than my children.
And I need a brave captain at the helm
to avoid those icebergs.
You are that man.
Come, Jerry.
Right, well, I'm with you, Tikki.
Specifically though,
what do you want me to do?
Just follow the bouncing ball, Cal.
- Bye, Cal.
- Yeah, bye, Jerry. Good to...
..S€ee you.
Glen was three points over.
He needs his car for work.
Why are we meeting here?
Ah, Glen, I just think that it's a lot
less threatening for my client base
if I meet them here rather than
in my big, showy chambers -
all that marble and so on.
Would you like a coffee?
Maria, if you're not doing anything...
Apparently, the machine's broken again.
Polish machine.
Look, I've been thinking.
This is my third time.
Probably not worth fighting it.
Really? If I had that attitude,
I'd still be in prison.
So would Mandela.
Some things are worth fighting for,
mate.
All it takes for evil to triumph
is for good men to do nothing.
- I was pissed.
- Were you?
Are you a doctor?
Did the machine get checked?
Was the reading accurate?
Did you get a blood test?
No, I refused. I'm haemophiliac.
Well, there you go.
We need to fight this.
I was reading an interesting article
the other day
from this scientist
at the Garrault Institute
who reckons the machine's readings,
once you've used it a few times,
they're not necessarily accurate.
I need to meet this person
as soon as humanly possible.
I've had two papers published
in scientific journals on the subject.
Governments choose
to ignore my findings, of course,
breath-testing being
such a great source of revenue for them.
But the truth does not disappear
simply because it is inconvenient.
Just how inaccurate are these machines,
Elliott?
It varies. Science demands exactitude,
but usually ends up with probabilities.
When you breathe out,
your breath goes directly into there.
With each breath also goes
a microscopic amount of alcohol,
or you wouldn't get the reading.
My contention is, the heavier
molecular weight of the alcohol
remains in the breathalyser.
If you breath-test, say,
200 people who have been drinking,
the cumulative effect, if you're
number 201, can alter the reading
by an as yet unquantifiable
but not insignificant margin.
Doubt is all I need to establish.
- You want a demonstration?
- Absolutely, we do.
I've been thinking about this.
I don't want to sing light opera.
I want to sing real opera.
No. You don't.
You will be Valjean, the part that
almost won our Hugh an Oscar.
So, already we're seeing a .0003
variation between the two machines.
Extrapolate that over many people,
and you would have to say
the numbers conform
to a predictable hyperbolic rise.
Well, let's tease out this hypothesis
a little more.
Maybe the pinot next.
Pinot, pinot, pinot.
Ah! Pinot.
If Humberstone is even a quarter
of a scintilla near right,
we are made.
We saw the numbers.
How many people have incurred fines
on faulty data?
How many licences
have been needlessly lost?
As many as there are
drops in the ocean.
We are talking a massive class action
against government.
More than the stars in the sky.
Are we absolutely convinced this guy's
scientific qualifications stack up?
A 100 per cent!
Right.
Then get it up on your website.
Tell everyone who has ever had a DUI
that there is a class action a-coming.
Put my name and number to it
and stand back and behold
the glorious tidal wave to come.
OK, I have you on 9th July - a DUI.
What do we think, gentlemen, 15 minutes?
I think more like two days, Your Honour.
This is a very complex case.
No. How?
Well, my client has a number of work-
and home-related factors
that I believe have considerable bearing
on this case, Your Honour.
Fine. 20 minutes, then.
And I have a welter
of scientific evidence
provided by an expert witness
that has grave implications
for the entire legal system.
OK! Back to 15.
Who is this man?
What is his story?
On Monday 9th July,
a very special edition
of Aussies Gotta Sing,
where, for the very first time,
the surprise card will be played.
This man will appear before our judges,
untried, unproven,
and with a shocking secret.
He will face final judgement.
Has Edie Newbar finally met her match?
So we bring him on.
You pretend you know nothing about him.
Shock, horror, reveal. He's humiliated.
I know the drill.
But really push it to fight stage.
Then he rallies and sings.
We line up lots of people
in the audience to whoop,
then you slowly rise to your feet
and clap.
Right, can the prick actually sing?
Oh, I think so. It's opera.
The guy's a bona fide murderer.
This isn't just us.
This is going to be news.
He's good for eight weeks.
- Eight weeks?
- Minimum.
- We need Gordon in make-up now.
- That's good. I'm coming.
Your Honour, there are many grounds
on which I could defend my client today.
Glen Hansi - family man
and production manager
at an aluminium-guttering company.
I could argue emotional stress.
His wife of eight years
recently left him for another woman,
which has seen him
in the hands of a psychologist
with whom he's already confronting
head-on the issue of substance abuse.
Yes. Indeed, there is considerable
precedent for such a submission.
But I'm not going to argue that today,
Your Honour.
I could argue that
his contact with his two young children
will be severely curtailed
if he cannot drive
and that his career
in aluminium extrusions could be lost.
Crown and Bayliss, indeed.
But I'm not going to argue
any of these here today.
Then why mention them?
Because, Your Honour,
there are bigger fish to fry here today.
Which still begs my initial question -
why bother to mention
the other reasons at all?
I'm trying to establish a context,
Your Honour.
What if I could prove here and now
that the entire foundation of this case
and potentially thousands
of similar cases
are open to serious question?
What if I were to say
that there may be prisoners
languishing in prison today
who are entirely innocent
or at the very least worthy of acquittal
on the basis of a fundamentally flawed
technology?
I would say, get on with it, and quick.
Indeed.
And to that end, let me call Dr Elliott
Humberstone, PhD from Princeton,
post-doctoral thesis from Harvard
and foundation member of the famed
Garrault Institute for Future Sciences.
Fine,
but can you get him to jog to the stand?
Dr Humberstone,
could you detail for the court's benefit
the body of your work
for the past 35 years?
Oh, please don't.
I'm prepared to accept
that he's a qualified scientist.
Indeed. Dr Humberstone, some years ago,
you began research into the technology
behind breath-testing.
Yeah, I did do that, yes.
Yes. Can you tell the court
what prompted this?
An epiphany, one of those great moments
in science where I realised
the basis upon which the taking
of alcohol samples from motorists
was premised on a questionable
scientific hypo... hypothesis.
- Is something wrong there, Doctor?
- A mild head cold, Your Worship.
Honour.
That the residual accretion
of alcoholic vapours
inside the very mechanism of the machine
contributed in no small part...
Mr Greene,
is your so-called expert witness
three sheets to the wind in my court?
No, I don't believe so.
Why is he wobbling in his chair, then?
He has an inner-ear issue, Your Honour.
[, however,
have his findings right here.
If it please the court,
I could possibly read them out.
I will not tolerate drunks in my court,
Mr Greene.
I'm used to derision.
I've been mocked before.
- But I have the science to back up...
- Remove this man from my court.
Mr Greene, I realise that this is
your first case since your release,
but I've a good mind
to find you in contempt.
Your Honour,
I have no idea what's happened.
When I met him a couple of weeks ago,
he was like a scientist in a movie.
Given that you have refused
to plead any alternatives,
I find your client guilty.
I remove his licence for 12 months
and fine him $1,500.
Next.
Don't even think about
sending a fucking bill.
Ah, that's a shame.
You'll be back in the harness soon.
Saddle, you fuckwit.
♪ Lovely lady of the sea
♪ Won't you come and comfort me? ♪
What the hell is going on, mate?
I don't want to do that song.
I want to sing the aria from Tosca.
I can do it unaccompanied.
Let me tell you a little something, Mal.
I don't really know if you can sing
or not. Opera all sounds the same to me.
The only thing I do know is
either you can play things our way,
or the road to obscurity lies that way.
You have just seconds to choose.
Malcolm, is it?
You're our...
.surprise card, is that it?
Tell us about yourself.
Why haven't we heard of you?
You're not exactly young.
What were you doing before now?
Don't tell me - you were a mime artist.
- I was in prison.
- What for?
- I just want to sing.
- You were in for wanting to sing?
It says here... murder.
Your father.
Is that right?
Righto, Mal. Give it a go.
Try not to murder the song.
- Aw!
- What?!
Did I say something wrong?
Fantastic.
Now just give it 30 seconds.
Let the tension build to fever.
Then walk back on as Valjean...
You know what?!
You know what?
Fuck Valjean.
Fuck you.
You stole my mother's phone.
No, I didn't.
Then why are
a lot of pissed people ringing her,
demanding legal representation?
OK, maybe I borrowed it by mistake
for a couple of days.
You're buying her a new phone
and you are paying her last phone bill.
Hello?
Yeah. No, mate. Look, I'm sorry.
I can't get your licence back.
No, I...
I know it said that on the website.
OK, same to you. Same to you, pal.
Oh, mate!
Oh, it's so good to see you.
Oh, I've missed you!
How are you, and what's all this shit
about you going to the Congo?
You know it's the most dangerous place
on earth.
I know. I don't want to talk about that.
I came to apologise.
I want to say,
I'm sorry for kind of cutting you off,
not visiting so much
the past few months.
Oh, that's OK.
It must have been a bit embarrassing.
No, that's not why I stopped coming.
I started to get really angry with you,
and I had no right to do that.
Yes, you did.
I was completely furious with myself.
You are who you are.
You can't change that.
No, I can change,
and I'm going to change.
No. People kept telling me you couldn't,
and I wouldn't believe them.
You're just someone
people can't rely on, and that's OK.
I just...
I had no right to expect any better.
Fuzz, if this is about
dropping out of school...
No, I don't want to study.
I want to be someone
who can help people.
I want to be someone people can rely on.
Mate, for someone who's forgiven me,
you sound pretty angry.
I promise you, I'm not.
I just don't want to have
any expectations of you anymore.
It's too hard.
I'm fine with it.
Well... no.
I'm your father.
We have a special relationship.
OK.
I'll call you in a few days, Cleave,
catch up before I leave.
'Dad'. Come on, at least call me 'Dad'.
Fuck.
There's a call for you.
Can you just tell them
I can't fix any fucking thing?
It's your friend, Mal.
Oh, the turtle show! Oh, shit.
Oh, my God.
Mate!
Oh, mate, I'm so sorry. The taxi didn't
arrive, and I couldn't...
How did it go?
Oh, I'm sorry.
No, don't be stu...
Don't be crazy, mate. Where are you?
What are you doing?
- What are you doing, Malcolm?
- No!
- Get down.
- Stop! You stay back. You stay back.
- It's over, Cleave.
- Oh, mate.
No, it's all finished now.
Oh, mate, come on.
Look, you've got another 50 years.
Is this all about some fucking...
stupid talent quest?
No.
That was it, mate.
The world will always be full of people
who want to judge you.
You can't let them.
Don't give them that power.
Don't give them that power! OK?
Look, things aren't turning out all that
well for me either at the moment,
but you have to believe
that things can change, alright?
They change. They do.
No, some lives don't change,
do they, Cleave?
Some lives...
..never really get started.
They're just fucked...
fucked up from the beginning.
It just goes on and on.
I never sang for you, did I, mate?
I wish I had.
Well, come on, mate - fucking sing now!
Sing your...
sing your little heart out.
Come on. And then will you get down
off the railing?
♪ O, dolci baci
♪ O, languide carezze
♪ Mentr'io fremente
♪ Le belle forme disciogliea dai veli. ♪
Mate.
Mate, that's fucking amazing!
That is fucking amazing.
Come on, keep singing, mate.
Keep singing!
Keep singing. It's fucking beautiful.
Come on, mate.
I told you I could do it.
Fuck.
Oh, fuck.
Oh, fuck!
Fuck.
Oh, fuck.
http://hiqve.com/