♪ ..my body
with the back of your hand
♪ Doesn't make sense
from where I stand
♪ Baby, baby
♪ Oh, why you want to mess it up?
♪ Sooner or later,
I'll find my place
♪ Find my body,
better fix my face... ♪
Nigel?
Nigel Turner?
Kirsty Ann McPhee. Good Lord!
How are you?
I'm good.
Yeah, I'm really good. God.
God, it's been such a long time.
So, how's your mum?
She passed away last April.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Come on. I can't wait forever.
It was very peaceful.
And all the family
was with her, so...
She was a lovely lady.
She was.
She always liked you.
And, uh...
You're married or...?
Yeah. Mick.
Mick! Hey, Mick.
Mick! This is Nigel.
Nigel, Mick. Nigel and I
went to school together.
And we grew up a block away
from each other.
Nigel.
Oh!
Ohh!
Well, maybe we could
catch up sometime or...
Oh, no, I don't think
that's a good idea.
No, I understand.
Thirsty work, isn't it?
Yeah.
Hey, I ran into Clive Witherspoon
the other day.
He's done well for himself,
that guy.
Oh, yeah! Yeah, yeah. I heard.
Um, a chain
of electrical stores or...
Um, hey, I would
really like to catch up.
You can get hold of me
on this number.
Um, I should get back to it,
I suppose.
Kirsty.
I'm not married.
They only laid this concrete down
a few weeks ago to extend the car park.
Just what the world needs —
bigger car parks.
The water mains hadn't blown up,
we never would have found the body.
Pretty recent?
Yeah.
My guess is on or around July 10
sometime after 9:21pm.
All this without
the aid of microscopes.
Well, some idiot left a
shopping receipt in one of the bags.
This used to be orchards.
Fancy.
They pull down beautiful orchards
to make a supermarket
that sells oranges
they fly in from Spain.
We got a full body yet?
Still chasing the left leg.
My guess is when they
put him together, we'll have
a balding 40s white Caucasian male,
slightly overweight.
I think we've got your full set now.
All non-recyclable.
Go and ask them for
their security tapes from July 10.
Ask em if they saw
anything suspicious.
They won't know.
They never know anything
in supermarkets.
Get me a Spanish orange
while you're at it, double bagged.
Jesus Christ.
No, you are not
bloody interested in my call,
or somebody would frigging answer.
How much do you
want to say this book cost?
Is it a law book?
If you want it to be.
Uh, 120 bucks.
And give it a boring title.
‘L'Estrange on Constitutional Law'.
And smudge the name of the shop.
If only you could claim
your gambling debts as deductions.
Will you go to prison, Dad?
Oh, I think the Tax Department
will probably count
my eight years with her
as time served.
Come on, fill in
some receipts, please.
You alright, Fuzz?
Um, yeah, I'm fine, thanks.
This is the, uh,
forensic accountant's report.
Somehow, she's managed to get hold
of all my Visa, Amex,
every bloody card statement
for the past eight years.
Come on, you cocks.
Can you just please...
mind your...
Thank you very much.
Can you just fill in a receipt for
the purchase of a new wig, please?
Thank you very much.
Well. Nice of you to take the trouble.
Is he ready? I'm double-parked.
Fuzz, get a move on.
How is he? Is he OK?
Yeah, he's alright.
Still a bit heartbroken.
Um, can I float an idea past you?
No.
‘Cause they're about to bring down
a finding in my tax case,
and I'm pretty sure
they're gonna find against me.
How sure?
In the range of 100% and upwards.
My best guess is
I probably owe about
786,500...
Fuzz, we're leaving.
All 'm saying is...
Fuzz, hurry up!
The house is in my name too.
You cannot be serious.
A second mortgage. You wouldn't
have to worry about anything.
I'd cover all the payments.
If anything, you're gonna be better off.
It is my house! Fuck you.
The only reason your name appears
anywhere on the title
is because you said it would cause you
a tax problem if taken off.
Now, look, I've spoken to the bank.
They seem quite positive.
You spoke to the bank? You spoke
to the bank without talking to...
Get me a gun!
You will not touch my house.
Alright? You will not come
anywhere near my house.
And you will not come
anywhere near me.
Just calm down, alright?
It's just chaos at the moment.
Yes. You are the chaos.
You're not the end result
of some butterfly effect.
You ARE the butterfly...
You are the original
fucking polka-dotted butterfly
that causes every bit of chaos
on this planet.
Fuzz! Get in.
I am humbled and thrilled
that the people of Huntley
have chosen me to represent them.
Naturally, like all of you here,
I am only sorry
our government was not returned...
Yes.
Rest assured, I am eagerly looking
forward to the challenges ahead,
and I promise you,
from the opposition benches,
I will be taking it right up
to this new government.
Watch this space.
Exciting times ahead.
I'm ruined.
I've destroyed my life.
I've given up 70% of my income,
and for what?
Joe's dead.
Premier's gone.
I've got no supporters
inside the party.
I'm gonna be a backbencher
in state parliament till I die.
Labor might get back in.
Oh, it was a landslide.
They'll get three terms at least.
No, I was better off at the bar.
The only thing I've got left
to hold onto is you.
I do have you, don't I?
My name is Jane.
Jane Tanner.
Both my parents
are still alive,
though you may not pick it
looking at them.
They haven't worked in 20 years.
They.. live off three pensions
and sit in a caravan in Taree
and drink beer and watch TV all day.
When I was 17, I pissed off,
and a few years later,
I became a prostitute
because, gosh, it paid well.
I let that career option
lapse a little while ago
so I could start to feel
better about myself.
I'm so sorry, David.
I think I'd like you to go now...
..Jane.
So you say you've never met
Nigel Turner?
Name doesn't ring any bells.
I knew a Turner in Kyabram.
Florist, divorced,
lives in Dulwich Hill.
No, I buy all me flowers
in the city.
Syd Turner.
That was the bloke from Kyabram.
He was a diesel mechanic.
Sorry I'm late.
I got...
You know you're not obliged
to answer, Mick.
Yeah, it's alright. Just having
a friendly chat with Bill.
You know Barney, Bill?
Bill, Barney. Barney, Bill.
Nigel Turner's mutilated body
was dug up near Water Street Park.
Out near Botany. Yeah, I know.
We laid some concrete out there
a month or so back.
Yes, over his body.
He was last seen alive
at 7:30pm on July 10,
and your company was pouring
concrete at 1:30am the same night.
Oh, we don't like to inconvenience
supermarket customers.
You know that area
used to be orchards?
You said he was divorced?
Might be worth
checking with his wife.
They're often at the back
of these things, you know.
We've found traces of your DNA
on his body.
And we're arresting you
on a charge of murder.
Mind if I have a private word
with Barney, please, Bill?
Get me Cleaver, and get me
out of this fucking shit hole.
If they've got your DNA,
it's not gonna be that easy.
He was a fucking florist
from Dulwich fucking Hill.
How the fuck would I know him?
I need you to brief Cleaver for me
straightaway. You got it?
I think we should go with a silk
this time. Cleaver is...
I know exactly
what fucking Cleaver is.
Right?
And he's who I want.
There are many
more eminent barristers...
I don't want fucking eminent!
I want someone I can trust.
Someone I know who fucking owes me.
You got it, Barney?
I'm sorry, Mick,
but I don't work with him anymore.
It's a matter of principle for me.
How much business did I steer
your way last year? 200? 300K?
That's a lot to lose
for a principle, Barney.
I'm sorry, Mick.
http://hiqve.com/
So literally everything
I know about you is made-up?
Pretty much.
You would have never looked twice
at me if you'd have known the truth.
You got that right, Jane Tanner.
How many clients did you service?
Oh, please, let's not go there.
It's just a question.
Roughly how many times a week
were you fucked by total strangers?
I'm really sorry that I hurt you.
Goodbye, David.
What the hell
did you think would happen?
That it might remain a secret,
that we might be happy?
But then you had to go
and save your neighbour's life,
and then Joe approached you
and you got elected to parliament
and we all ended up here
in Lake Shit.
Joe Sandilands?
You were working at the brothel
where he got sprung?
That's why you were so upset
when he topped himself.
You were with him, weren't you?
In the past.
I didn't know you then.
Oh, my God! Cleaver Greene.
That's how you know him, isn't it?
There was never any cousin Angus.
Oh, not him.
You mean the whole time
we were together, my whole campaign,
he was laughing
his bloody head off?
No.
Oh, well, you will forgive me
if I don't believe you.
It ends today.
Haven't you got a traffic island
to open somewhere?
I wouldn't miss it for the world,
I guarantee it.
Looking at the financial year 2005-2006,
Mr Greene represented
58 clients in court.
So I estimated the number of
billing hours he would have taken
to prepare each case.
Hang on.
Your Honour, how could she
possibly estimate that
without knowing the subject matter?
If that was an objection,
it was overruled.
I read the transcripts
of each case, taking note
of the substance of each charge,
number of withesses called,
complexity of issues.
What could a bean counter know
about complexity of issues?
I have found you in contempt
once before.
Do you want to play for
another three days in remand?
Hm?
Then I spoke to 15 barristers
of Mr Greene's
experience and rank...
..asked them for their estimates,
then took a mean figure.
Very mean.
In my estimation, Mr Greene would have
made no less than $238,000
for that year.
Were there any legitimate deductibles
during that year?
Well, judging by Mr Greene's
credit card statements,
most of his money went on
entertainment-related products
and two gambling accounts.
He doesn't rent an office.
He occupies the chambers
of people on holiday.
Oh, yeah. A floater.
He paid $5,200 for a law conference
in Bermagui.
What? Never been to Bermagui.
I think that is her point.
He made several trips there,
but no record of any law conference.
I don't even know
where Bermagui is.
Having reached the end
of this very long road,
this case has given me no joy,
but I eagerly await
any submission in mitigation,
because at this moment,
I think, Mr Greene,
you have avoided paying
a staggering amount of tax.
At worst, and I think
this is where we are...
..you have...
Great loss to our profession.
I had the very real sense
he was about to find in my favour.
I don't know how,
but you caused this.
Oh, I do.
I'm the original butterfly.
You are a codling moth,
and I will crush you.
You'll have your work cut out
from the opposition backbenches
in state parliament, mate.
Bermagui, two weeks.
$3,120. When?
$3,487?
Bermagui Electrical. $3,487.
Never even been there.
Suppose I should
thank you for coming.
You don't have to.
Look, I get you're angry with me...
We sent napalm to destroy
the North Vietnamese.
What did they send in return?
Forensic accountants.
The horror. The horror.
What do you want?
The healing to begin.
I can't stay mad at you.
I'm a weak man.
I can forgive almost anything...
Cleave...
No, no, no, listen.
I can forgive the disappearing act,
the reappearing act,
the whole hot/cold
English plumbing thing — I get that.
What I don't get is why you thought
you had to lie to me.
Cleave...
No, no, no, shut up for a minute.
I gotta...I gotta say this.
Oh, great.
I love a unilateral rant.
We all need to come from somewhere.
My Uncle Kel's New Year's Eve
party trick
was hanging his false teeth
off his cock,
pretending that Auntie Rena
had bitten him.
I didn't want to come from
where I came from.
I wanted to try a different life.
You can't try a life.
You got to lead an authentic one.
Oh, you think your life
is authentic?
Yeah, damn tootin', I do.
Anarchic, catastrophic,
without rhyme or reason,
the butterfly, the behemoth,
but fuck me, it's real.
An ability to list your flaws doesn't make
it authentic.
What we had was real,
whether you grew up in Peru or Taree.
I know that.
And then you end up
with Harry-sorry-David,
a man whose only aspiration's to have
a fucking fountain named after him.
That's not true.
You should have
given me a chance.
I gave you every chance.
No, no.
Really.
I would have loved you
with all the feebleness of my heart.
I still do.
For all my fucking chaos.
We could have been very happy.
David and I have split.
Wow.
I told him the truth.
He got both barrels,
the whole bloody grim catastrophe.
And?
And he ran a mile.
Unlike you.
So...
Wow.
Are you OK?
Yeah.
You look a little clammy.
No, I'm good. I'm good.
The first glimmer.
What?
The first hint of something
barely approaching commitment
and you're terrified.
Bullshit.
Joe Sandilands said to me
about his marriage
that somewhere between passionate sex
against a wall and bin night,
everything seemed to get lost.
Call me when you can get past
bin night, Captain Authentic.
I can do bin night! Thursday. Right?
Why?
Around $90,000 systematically
stolen from me, under my nose,
over eight years
by someone
I thought I could trust.
Why? Would have thought more.
Really?
Yeah. Don't be a smug shit. I took you
out of secretarial college.
I gave you a job. I took care of you.
You had all the time off you wanted.
I gave you a salary raise every year.
Surely this warrants some respect.
You would have wasted it anyway.
I put 30% of it into my super.
You don't even have that. And the rest
I put towards building a house.
That will employ people
and provide for families.
You can't justify it like that.
This is grand theft.
You would have lost it
on the third at Dapto.
Because you don't care about anything,
especially about yourself.
You're...you're not
connected to anyone.
You can't even remember
my fiancé's name.
How did you manage to conceal this?
Ooh, 12 numbered accounts
in the Bahamas.
What do you think, Cleave?
You never check anything.
Like I said, you don't...
you don't care.
Why Bermagui?
That's where
we're building a house.
Oh, so Brian's
in on this too, is he?
Bevan.
Bevan is in on this too.
This is now a police matter,
you realise?
Oh, yeah, right.
“Help me, Officer.
“The money I cheated from
the Tax Office was stolen from me.”
We haven't finished here!
Your client will be expected
to compensate my client
any money she has invested
in the house
plus interest accrued
had that money been in a bank.
Cleaver fucking Greene!
When the hell has any bank
ever paid this much interest?
Charged, yes, but not paid.
Fine.
She can have the house.
Let her pay me that number.
Scarlet?
I mean it. It's hers.
- She earns just as much as me.
- No.
No, I don't.
Really?
What, you aren't a member
of the New South Wales Bar anymore?
No.
As of, uh, 9:20 this morning,
I've been suspended.
- Pardon?
- Mmm.
Yeah, the Bar Association
are pretty cross with me.
They say I've broken the rule
against cross-examining a friend.
Oh, that fucking assault case!
I've tried explaining to them that...
that Cleaver Greene
is not a friend of mine or anyone's,
but they're so adamant that I've
abused my privilege to cross-examine.
So how long until
you can practise again?
Well, less the time
from 9:20 this morning, a year.
A year.
Nine...nine years at the bar.
I make one mistake, and this,
and Cleaver Greene,
with all the shit that he's caused,
he...he still gets to practise.
Yes, this does change things potentially,
considerably.
If my client no longer has
a steady income,
this poses all sorts of questions about
maintenance and provision.
Yeah, she, uh,
makes a valid point, mate.
You might have to sell your house,
given your current level of debt.
Yes, I know.
You're deep in
the sticky stuff here, Mick.
You're gonna have to give us
something to work with.
Well, how about the fact
that you owe me
close to 80K in gambling debts?
Get me off this shitbox charge
and watch those debts magically vanish.
And I'll throw in
a $25,000 line of credit.
None of this is gonna get you
past the DNA evidence.
Cleaver will.
He's a smart fucking boy.
Cleaver won't, mate.
They found more of your hair
on the victim's body
than Lassie shed in a lifetime.
I was working out there. Me hair's
probably all over the place.
Where were you the night that your
company was laying the concrete?
I was hosting a lifestyle party
at my place.
Swinging, OK?
Swingers?
You and Kirsty?
Well, we prefer the expression
‘lifestylers', but yeah.
My wife and I like to explore
our sexual boundaries
in a safe environment
amongst like-minded people.
OK.
And then this prick turns up.
Nigel Turner?
Yeah.
We met him at another party
a few months before.
And he started stalking us.
He wouldn't take no for an answer.
We weren't interested.
Turns out his missus had left him.
And I don't do three-ways
with another bloke,
unless his missus is filming.
Yeah, well, you've got to know
your moral limits, don't you?
Yeah.
Anyway, he shows up
pissed and dangerous at our place.
And I say, “Sorry, mate.”
And I chuck him out.
And he comes back later,
after everyone else has gone,
and pulls a knife on me and Kirsty.
And the turd keeps coming.
We crash to the floor
and he falls on his own fucking knife.
Can you believe it?
Straight through the fucking heart.
Bang, he's dead.
He killed himself.
And did he then chop himself up
into little pieces
and stuff himself
into supermarket bags?
I was scared, and I panicked.
And I didn't want to drag Kirsty through
the embarrassment.
Well, it's gonna be hard
to avoid that now, mate.
Is she prepared to testify
it was self-defence?
Course she will.
She knows what happened.
Thanks, mate.
We could use this swinging thing.
Distract the jury,
get 'em to focus on salacious sex.
Keep well clear of the facts.
You know, we need his wife up there.
You know he's lying?
Not for certain, I don't.
Shout you a sandwich?
Scarlet and I are getting divorced.
The house is on the market.
And thanks to you,
she hasn't got a job.
Well... It wasn't all my fault,
you know.
Don't take this the wrong way.
I'm doing it purely for the money.
I know the world has no meaning
if you two split.
Let me deal directly with Nicole.
Make it easier for both of us.
Can't. I sacked her.
Yeah, right.
I mean it.
She's been stealing from me.
From day one, as it turns out.
Then there really is
nothing to hang onto, is there?
‘Daily Telegraph'!
Come in, if you must.
Don't know why you bother.
I've already told the police everything.
He came back after the party,
he was furious and out of control,
they fought, he died, I pissed off.
Kirsty, you're the only credible witness
who can back Mick up.
It's gonna be difficult for you
on the stand.
Yeah, well, like I haven't
been there before.
And are you sure that your statement
covered everything?
How many people do you think
are looking at that and thinking,
“Ooh, I'd love to
have sex with that'?
Quite a few, I'm sure.
Mick bought that for me,
told me it covered my flab.
Could you tell me
how the scene works?
The scene?
The swinger scene.
A bit of a voyeur,
are you, Mr Meagher?
Maybe you'd like to take part.
No, that's not why I'm here.
Done worse than you.
I just want to understand.
It's just sex.
There's heaps of different ways.
There's full-swing orgy.
There's full-swing
partner swap.
There's soft swing.
There's soft swap.
Well, what's the difference between
soft swing and soft swap?
Sex with your own partner
in front of another couple.
Soft swap is oral permissible.
Oral permissible?
It's just sex, Mr Meagher.
I don't see how that can work.
When you've invested everything
you have into your marriage
and the two of you
have made this commitment —
you know, you and her,
and your kids, against the world —
doesn't having sex with someone else
destroy that?
Well, there's one rule
that you can't break.
What's that?
Never get involved.
You can't do that.
So are you confident
that you can testify?
Mick was trying to protect me.
They got into a fight.
Nigel fell on his knife
and he died.
And I pissed off.
Nigel?
Yeah.
You called him by his first name.
Yeah, well,
that is his name, isn't it?
Did Mr Corella explain
why he cut the body up
if he was just going to bury it
beneath a concrete slab anyway?
No.
And in your experience,
does this seem consistent
with an act
of spontaneous self-defence,
to accidentally kill somebody
and then take to their corpse
with a chainsaw?
It is more the sort of behaviour
you would associate with premeditation.
Objection.
Yes, sustained.
Please stick to the facts,
both of you.
I worked with Nigel for 15 years.
He was a gentle, loving man,
a great dad to Ella,
a fantastic contributor
to the Lions Club
and our Bowl for Asia appeal.
Tell me, in addition to being
a loyal member of the Lions Club,
did you know that your boss
was also a hardcore swinger?
No.
I think he was just so lonely
after his divorce.
He was looking for love
in the wrong places.
Doesn't make him someone
who deserved to be killed.
No, but it does make him
a very different man
to the man that you
claim to have known.
Nothing further, Your Honour.
I need to know about
your relationship with Greene.
Leave it, David, please.
All those times you disappeared.
No, it wasn't like that.
Then tell me how it was!
We played a lot of backgammon,
and we laughed,
and all of it was
before I knew you.
You know, when I turned 15,
I decided I wanted
to make a difference.
I decided that one day
I would achieve high office
so that I could make a difference.
Since then, I've tried
to live a good life,
to have no blots on my record.
Blots?
You have made me look like a fool.
Nobody needs to know, do they?
I really hope
it turns around for you, David.
You deserve it.
You here to take
another swing at me, Harry?
Harry?
It was wrong.
Completely out of character.
I'm not thinking clearly.
She takes it out of you,
doesn't she?
I'm in hell.
I know it doesn't mean anything
to people like you, but I loved her.
Love her.
Now I don't have a fucking clue
who she is.
Has it occurred to you that
maybe she hasn't got a clue either?
I mean, she's spent her whole life being
all things to all people,
you and me included.
Maybe we just like the look
of ourselves in the mirror.
I will take you down, Cleaver.
Well, I very much look forward
to that, Harry.
Almost there.
A truck will come
for the rest of it on Friday.
Bye-bye.
Love you guys.
Hm?
How's the flat?
Oh, you know that tent
we stayed in, in Hyams?
Smaller.
Uh, we were just about
to have some dinner.
Uh, would you like to join us?
Uh, no, thanks.
I'm catching up with some friends.
Oh.
Spoken to Kirsty yet?
Mmm. Poor woman.
She's sitting on something.
She knew Nigel Turner.
Right, so the prosecution
would chew her up.
In a minute.
Is it such a bad thing?
He murdered a man.
He hacked him up into bite-size pieces.
And the bloke he murdered
had a kid.
He was from all accounts
a lovely guy.
Yeah. Unfortunately,
we're being paid to get Mick off.
We are being paid to defend him,
not become him.
You're not seriously suggesting
I call a defence witness
who might incriminate my own client?
Goes against every principle...
Well, now, there's
a principle to live by.
Never call a withess
who might actually tell the truth.
Uh, yeah, well, my wife and I
like to exchange, um,
partners with close friends
as a means of, uh,
exploring our sexual boundaries.
Right, and you were
exploring these boundaries
on the night you met Nigel Turner?
Yes.
My partner and I
were new to the scene,
being more into amo...
..ama...
..maxia.
Amo...?
In cars.
This was our first night
in an open situation,
when this maniac burst through
the doors and started coming onto me.
Well, he was only human.
Well, I...
I tell him I'm strictly hetero,
but, um,
he wouldn't take no for an answer.
Right.
And so you would describe Nigel Turner's
behaviour as very dangerous?
My wife and I felt
very vulnerable.
I, personally,
was frightened for my life.
All yours.
Aren't you known around the traps
as Mick Corella's enforcer?
Objection, Your Honour.
The witness is not on trial here.
Your Honour, it goes to credit.
Tightrope, Mr Gardener.
I'll allow it.
I don't work for him anymore.
You were the state Muay Thai
boxing champion, I understand.
Never beaten.
Yeah.
Six title defences.
And yet we are to believe
you were terrified of this man.
Yeah, well, sometimes
it's the little blokes.
You knocked those off
from the foyer at chambers.
Well, you did steal $90,000 from me.
I'm not gonna
splash out on you, am I?
Fair enough.
So who told you I was here?
Bevan called me.
Oh, you got his name right.
Mmm. Something about
you being attacked by a demon.
It was a gargoyle.
What sort of gargoyle?
Oh, I didn't have time to look.
Well, you can have your job back
if you like.
Oh, I don't want it.
Yes, you do.
Who else are you
going to work for?
Shiny-suited conveyancing solicitor
in Newtown?
Your marriage is gonna be
boring enough.
Alright, I'll give you a 10% raise.
No.
Jesus.
Oh, I'd still charge stuff to you
when you're not looking.
You can't say that!
There's a principle at stake here.
Oh, you said once you put
principles and the Easter bunny
in the same category.
Alright, you can keep pilfering
from me, but cap it at 5%.
10% and we'll talk.
Missy.
It's bin night.
What?
You've got...stuff.
Yeah, I just grabbed what I could.
I've got a van coming on Monday.
Right. A van.
Yeah, you did say bin night,
didn't you?
I did, indeed.
Indeedy I did.
And by ‘bin night',
I meant that we could talk...
I know, but I just thought...
We should just move in together
and sort through all our shit as we go.
Right. Very good.
OK, so there's no van coming
on Monday.
No.
Very good.
Oh, I just wanted
to see your face.
I'm leaving. I've deferred uni
and I've booked a flight.
What?
Where are you going?
I thought I'd trace the steps
of my dead non-parents.
Rome, Florence, Spain.
Greece. Lima.
You can't leave me now.
I'm poised to commit.
It's too late.
It's not.
Don't say that.
When are you going?
Tonight.
Oh, for fuck's sake. Missy.
A journey in search of the real me.
Waste of time.
I promise you, every time
I've tried to find myself,
I've realised
it wasn't worth the trip.
We're this close.
We've always been this close.
No.
You're always poised, Cleave.
Listen to me.
I've been in love with you long enough
to know that it's not gonna happen.
I could come and find you
in a couple of months.
I might be a completely
different person by then.
I'd still love ya.
Who the fuck am I gonna
play backgammon with?
Have you thought rationally about that?
Huh?
Come on, let's get a coffee and...
Can't. Have a million things to do.
No, no, just one lousy coffee.
Come on.
- Dario?
- Piccolo, Cleaver?
Yeah, and a skinny flat white,
thanks, mate.
And maybe a cake of some s...
Have you got any aces up your sleeve?
‘Cause all your swinger mates
are really not cutting it with this jury.
Oh, I never trouble meself too much
about juries, Cleave.
All rise.
Mr Greene.
Mr Greene, your next witness?
Your Honour, I'd like to call, um,
Kirsty Corella, please.
And he attacked us with a knife
and Mick pleaded for him to stop,
but he wouldn't.
You must have been
in terrible fear for your life.
So you were absolutely convinced
that Nigel Turner was out of control?
Yeah.
Yes.
So let's set the picture
for the jury, then.
This madman bursts into your home,
and he's trying to kill
the man you love.
What happened next?
Um...
They...they...they fought,
and he fell on his blade.
I'm sorry, Mrs Corella, I can see
how difficult this is for you,
seeing the man you...
..love and adore
now charged with murder
for simply trying to protect you from
this venomous monster.
This gentle, loving man,
who married you for better or worse,
who shared your most intimate moments
but still allowed you the freedom
to explore your sexuality
with loads of other men
whilst remaining
emotionally committed.
He f... He fell on his knife.
Yes, surely a fitting conclusion
for this depraved degenerate.
Nigel never did anything to you.
He was kind and he was warm.
Uh, no further questions.
Thank you, Your Honour.
He brought me flowers.
And he held my hand.
And he told me how pretty I was.
And it didn't matter to him
that my legs were a bit fat,
and he loved me for who I am.
Thank you, Your Honour.
That will be all.
And he didn't make me
strap on a giant rubber dildo
and do unnatural things,
and you killed him, you monster!
She was seeing him
behind me back.
So I had 'em tailed.
They went for walks
and held hands.
He took her to the bookshop
at the fucking museum.
My wife.
You did let her
have sex with other men.
Yeah, but not going
to fucking bookshops.
He was being intimate with my wife.
And the prick had to fucking die.
Hello, monkeys.
We're not monkeys!
The Chinese drawers were mine.
No, they were given to us
by my mother.
Oh, oh! So that's how
you want to play this?
OK. OK, well, why don't we
go through everything again, hm?
What's in that box?
Look, I don't know what's in there.
Oh, well, it's got your name on it.
You packed it.
Oh, look.
Why don't we have a little
look-see, hey? Have a look.
Help yourself.
Let's see what else we can have.
And have a look in this one!
There we go!
You're just being stupid now.
I've smashed the ersatz Deco clock!
What a shame! You know what?
Take it all. Have...have it all.
It's shit! It's just fucking shit!
Have every last...
Yours! It's shit!
Take your fucking sh... Have it!
Hi.
Hi. Um...
Are you sure you want this?
Um...
Do you have the faintest clue
how much I love you?
It's a classic anxiety attack.
He's been in there for over a day now.
Used to get 'em when I was a kid.
Good.
Then you can tell him
how you got out of it.
I will. Booze and drugs.
If you're gonna live in here
permanently, mate,
I can organise some plumbing.
I'll come out soon.
I'm shit at everything, Dad.
I'm shit at school.
I'm shit at sport.
I'm shit at making friends.
And I know you and Mum
want me to be special, but I'm not.
I'm just ordinary.
Ordinary people don't spend two days
in cupboards, mate.
Fiona was the only person
that made me feel
like things were
gonna be OK in the future.
I love her, Dad.
Oh, you gotta love 'em, son.
No point if you don't.
Well, you didn't love Mum.
I loved her most of all.
But you don't give me any hope
that things can get better.
Everyone's always out of control
in your life.
And if you can't manage to be happy
with everything that you've got,
how's anyone with nothing
going to make it?
Chaos eventually finds its own level,
and more often than not,
it's in a better place than it was
when it started,
and it'll be the same
for you too, Fuzz.
I guarantee it, my friend, because...
You're wrong.
You are about
the most special person I know.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Hey, Cleave.
Hope I'm not disturbing you.
Look, I've, um, been sent round
to give you a bit of a hiding.
What are you talking about?
Mick's gone away for 25 years.
No, no, it's for Kirsty.
She's taken over the reins now.
Very easy to work for, I might add.
Oh, good.
Look, she reckons that even with
all the legals for Mick,
you're still about 38K in the hole.
You are fucking kidding me.
It's a matter of principle, Cleave.
Yeah, isn't it always?
What, is now a good time?
Well, no, not really, mate.
But...
Look, if you're gonna do it,
do it over the lino.
At least it'll be easy to mop up.
Righto.
Thought you and I should celebrate
losing our biggest client.
But perhaps you should
go to hospital.
No, it's just a...
light dusting, mate.
Fancy a game of backgammon?
You know I'm strictly a chess man.
Well...
We've all got... Ow!
Oh, shit.
We've all got to adapt, mate.
You know?
You and I are entering
a new era of enlightenment.
Oh. See, Missy would
never have done that.
Oh, please! I can't see the board,
dripping blood all over it.
Oh, well, I apologise
for my subdural haematoma
inconveniencing you, mate.
So I should hope.
Do you need a cloth?
Well... No, no,
I'm fine, thanks, mate, yeah.
I'll get it, then, shall 1?
All good here.
No, no, I'll go get you a cloth.
Oh, thanks very much.
Very kind.
♪ Sometimes
I feel a little sad... ♪
♪ But don't you know
that no-one alive
♪ Can always be an angel?
♪ When things go wrong,
I seem to be bad
♪ I'm just a soul
whose intentions are good
♪ Oh, Lord, please don't let me
be misunderstood
♪ I'm just a soul
whose intentions are good
♪ Oh, Lord, please don't let me
be misunderstood. ♪
http://hiqve.com/