200 bucks.
I'm in.
Out.
Relax, Cliff, you're amongst
friends who wanna help you.
Isn't that right, Vanessa?
That's right, Mick.
Look, we're all aware
of how stressful debt can be.
And none of us enjoys
its ugly consequences.
None of us, Cleave.
So Mick and I decided it would be
better to sit down with you calmly,
and, you know, just map out a plan
that provides...certainty.
So, as you can see here,
Mick and I have decided
to roll the two debts into one.
And that's because
of our longstanding
and close relationship with you.
My father loved you like a brother.
I know that.
We've agreed,
and this is exclusively for you,
on an interest rate
of 29%, compounded weekly.
This 29% is,
if you turn the page...
..it's subject to
a confidentiality clause.
So don't tell anyone.
Otherwise it'll literally become
crippling interest.
You understand, Cleave?
Yep.
Pretty much.
Does Barney know where you are?
Yes. I'm at my sister's.
Ah! Oah!
Ah!
Oooh!
Oh!
Oh-ho.
Mmm.
I told my shrink
that I was thinking
of having an affair.
Always a good solution
to marital difficulties, Red.
Spread the pain.
What did she say?
Well, she said that it might make me
feel better in the short term,
but that it would come back
to haunt me like Banquo's ghost.
She'd be right, for once.
So beat it, Red.
Come on. Stand not upon the order
of your going, knucklehead.
Just, you know, bugger off
back to your husband and kids.
What did you expect?
You've been together a long time.
It's gonna change.
And how
would you know? Hmm?
The longest relationship you've ever
had has been with a prostitute.
Oh, don't start
swinging wildly, sweetheart.
This isn't about me.
For once.
So you're full-time
at Chasers, are you, Marty?
Pretty much.
Oh, you know, other things come up.
Mmm.
Odd jobs. Life.
So that's it. It's over.
It's all done without Barney
even knowing it's been going on.
His life as he knows it — gone.
No right of reply.
Oh, fuck you, Cleaver.
I suppose
you saved him a lot of bother.
I mean, I do understand your point
because he's not that bright, is he?
I mean, he's completely lacking when
it comes to insight and integrity.
I mean, he wouldn't be able to
contribute to a worthwhile dialogue
about the marriage
you're meant to be sharing.
So it's better that you keep it
in your internal monologue, Red.
That way it'll be sorted out
to YOUR satisfaction.
http://hiqve.com/
Red.
- Yeah?
- Mate, it's me.
So my brother's a doctor and every
time I get called for jury duty,
I've got a medical certificate.
I didn't mind it. It was fun.
Mm-hm. What sort of case
did you get?
Hit the jackpot.
We got a murder.
Oh, really?
There was something about
her voice on the phone.
Just sounded so...alien.
I went round to her sister's,
but she said she'd left.
I'm not sure she'd even been there.
You must've read about it —
the model and the footy star?
Oh, wow.
Now, what was her name?
Oh, don't tell me what it is because
I read it in all the papers.
Um... Oh!
Tanisha Marx.
Tanisha Marx and Gavin Warner.
Mmm.
Oh, it was pretty cool.
Mm-hm. So she did it, yeah?
Yeah. Well, that was our verdict.
What do you mean?
I shouldn't be talking about it.
Mmm.
No.
Course not. Mmm.
So there's gotta be
another guy, right?
No. No! Not necessarily at all.
Marriages go through phases, mate.
Yeah, we've been in a rut.
I acknowledge that.
I absolutely acknowledge that.
But, you know,
not a day goes by still
where I don't thank God
for the miracle of her.
I mean, look at me.
Look at her.
You'd never think in a million years
she'd choose me.
Go home, mate. Tell her exactly that.
Oh...oh, God.
Oh, God!
How did she do it, again?
What? How did who do what?
Tanisha Marx.
How did she kill Gav Warner?
You wanna talk about this now?
Oh, I'm into crime.
It sort of turns me on.
She stabbed him.
She dumped the body in the bush.
He was a big guy, wasn't he?
Yeah.
Yeah, that was the thing.
What thing?
Well, he WAS a big guy.
I mean, how she even managed
to get the body in the car...
So you had a doubt?
A little.
Aren't you meant to acquit then?
Well...I really
shouldn't be telling you this.
Come on, Red.
Home you go.
That is filthy, by the way.
Well, he was a big guy.
I mean, how she even managed
to get the body in the car...
So you had a doubt?
A little.
Aren't you meant to acquit then?
Well...I really shouldn't
be telling you this.
Gav Warner's cousin...
Yeah, what about him?
Turns out he was a mate
of the head juror.
Kidding me. Fucking kidding me.
..Tanisha was a real bitch.
I have fought
to prove my daughter's innocence
from the day
of Gavin's tragic death.
And this recording proves
that at least one member of the jury
had serious doubts
about Tanisha's guilt
and that the jury foreman
had a connection to Gavin Warner
that he didn't disclose.
And my little girl had her
19th birthday in prison last week.
Here you go.
Here come the waterworks.
Because that man...
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
..the jury foreman —
he bullied other jurors
into finding my daughter guilty.
What, so...this is...this is her
at her daughter's trial?
Yeah.
Well... shit.
Wouldn't have recognised her.
Looks like she's lost about 20 pounds.
Just fuck off!
Had a complete makeover,
apparently, boss.
And went out hunting jurors.
Right, so, she loses 20 pounds,
has a complete makeover,
gives this idiot a blow job,
and we're gonna send her to jail?
Bill? Bill? She was right!
Hey? The system failed
both her and her daughter.
But you're the Attorney-General.
You can't say that.
I mean, you're responsible
FOR the system.
Oh, right. My fault now, is it?
Fucking typical — I'm responsible
for a system I can't control, eh?
What moron came up with the idea
of an independent judiciary?
Well, the...the separation
of powers...
Shut up, Bill. Just shut up, alright?
Two things need to happen now.
One — Tanisha Marx
needs to get out of jail.
Two — Lucy Marx does not go to jail.
Well, you know
that's down to the courts, boss?
Yeah, I'm
the fuckin' Attorney-General.
Course I know
it's down to the courts.
Idiot.
Having now had the opportunity
to investigate the matter in greater detail,
Your Honour,
it would appear, that,
er, the removalists I hired
were not responsible
for the destruction
of those financial records the
Tax Office has requested access to.
Er, it would seem that, er,
those documents were already damaged
prior to the move.
And I am reliably informed
by the janitor
of my former storage facility,
er, a Mr Tergit Erzrin,
that a dormer window
was inadvertently left open
during the storm,
which caused considerable flooding
in the area
where my documents were housed.
Your Honour,
my friend the respondent
has been granted every opportunity
to either produce
the subpoenaed records to the ATO
or provide a credible reason
for their disappearance.
At our last mention,
it was the removalists' fault,
now it's the janitor's.
What will it be after that?
The dog ate them?
Your Honour, we have
been bogged down
in procedural issues for 18 months now.
And we again respectfully submit
that Mr Greene be required
to produce the financial records
for the relevant period
or be found in contempt.
Mr Potter has a point, Mr Greene.
I think you've had
more than enough time.
Indeed, Your Honour
has been most indulgent,
er, but Mr Erzrin
has only recently returned to Sydney
after a six-month holiday
visiting relatives in Turkey.
I don't see how
I could have expedited matters
in any meaningful way.
Mr Erzrin,
could you tell me what happened
on the afternoon of 23 September?
I go, for building,
for clean.
Rain — bucket dogs.
Swish, swish!
Floor shine good.
No worries for you.
Swish, swish.
But window, er...
Your Honour,
this is getting us nowhere.
I agree, Your Honour.
Er, I had hoped to save the court
the cost of a translator,
but it would seem to be necessary.
Er, no! No, I beg you,
let's keep going.
No, in fairness, we are
going to need a Turkish translator.
Now, I have leave starting shortly.
We'll reconvene three months hence
on the 24th.
May it please the court.
Thank you, Your Honour.
See you at
the doggies on Friday night, Cleave?
Yeah, I'll try. Thanks, mate.
The evidence on which
the appellant seeks to rely
was gathered illegally.
And, as such,
we find it inadmissible.
This is a grave matter.
It is a cornerstone
of our system of criminal justice
that jurors not be harassed
and/or threatened
before, during or after a trial.
It is the only way
we can maintain confidence
in the independence
of the jury system...
This is your idea of justice, is it?! Did
you even bother to listen to the tapes?!
Mrs Marx, please restrain yourself.
Did you?
Now, you want the public to maintain
their confidence in the jury system,
then fucking do something to fix it!
Will the sheriffs
please assist Mrs Marx?
I don't need escorting.
The evidence was as plain
as the hairy ears on their heads.
But no, because
of some legal mumbo jumbo,
my daughter remains in prison.
Now, I am calling
on the State Attorney-General
to immediately rectify
this gross miscarriage...
I can't rectify it.
No, don't have the power, love.
I'm calling on him to have
a Royal Commission into this matter.
Oh, my sainted aunt.
..expose the rotten state of justice
in NSW.
I have nothing else to say.
She's good.
She's sensational.
She's Joan of Arc.
How do I look?
In section 68a of the ‘Jury Act',
a person must not solicit
information from or harass a juror,
or former juror, for the purpose
of obtaining information
about...de-da, de-da,
de-daa, de-daa...
Maximum penalty — seven years.
Well, that's fine.
Sorry?
Fine. I'm more than happy
to go to jail.
You wanna be with your daughter.
Oh, that's not the only reason.
If you go to jail, there's gonna be
a shit storm in the press.
That's what you're after, isn't it?
If I get off,
it'll be a story for five minutes.
If I go to jail, every day
there'll be more questions.
There will be more pressure
on my MP, on the Attorney-General,
on the Government.
Eventually someone will have to do
something about Tanisha.
So I am instructing you
to plead guilty.
That's not something we hear
every day, is it?
Now, Lucy, I don't think
you should plead guilty.
If it's really a shit storm you want,
plead not guilty.
Make them prove their case.
Do you know what I mean?
Let the public see them pursue you —
hound a grieving mother
until she's behind bars.
Won't be prosecution,
it'll be persecution.
But I will be found guilty?
Oh, in my capable hands,
I don't see how you could
possibly avoid a jail term.
She cannot go to jail.
It would kill us in the press.
And that is also
the Premier's firm view.
Good.
Can't you drop the charges?
Well, she's publicly admitted
to a very serious offence.
The Director's adamant —
we've no choice but to prosecute.
Yeah, fine. Fine.
Far be it from this office
to attempt to interfere
with the course of justice.
But is it not the Director
who selects counsel, is it not?
So you want someone green?
Emerald, I think,
is what we're looking for.
Now, who's gonna judge this thing?
Do we have a mother
on the bench at the moment?
If not, let's appoint one.
It's rather liberating,
don't you think, cock?
What?
Having a client who's guilty
for a very good reason.
And who wants to go to jail.
So even if we screw up,
we're doing the right thing.
I wish all my clients
were as guilty as she is.
Hey, shouldn't we get going?
No, Scarlet's meeting us here
at half past.
Cool.
How are things in the marital home?
Very cool.
Did she say where she was
the other night?
No, you were right.
She'd just gone for a drive.
If there is nothing else,
my servitude is over for the day.
Nicolette, you have, as always,
been just marvellous.
Mmm.
Bloody hell.
Is that a ring?
Mm-hm.
What?!
Congratulations.
When did this happen?
Oh, three weeks ago.
Oh.
Well, why didn't you say anything?
Well, there's a sweep going round
on how long it'd take you to notice.
I had two months.
Well, who's the poor bastard?
Who do you think?
Bevan.
Bevan! Oh.
Well...
..at last, an honest woman, eh?
Er, how long
have you two been going out, again?
Oh, 11 years.
11 years?
Mmm.
He really is
a bit slow off the mark, isn't he?
Oh, he's had commitment issues.
Has he? And you?
Knew the moment I met him
I'd marry him.
Wait a minute, weren't you
at school 11 years ago?
Mm-hm.
So what are you saying?
He was your first?
Mm-hm.
And only.
You've never been with anyone else?
Mm-mm.
Well, aren't you curious?
Cleave.
What, about other men?
Well, yes, about other men.
I mean, there's a whole world
of other men out there.
Different shapes and colours.
Sizes.
And what about women?
What about them?
Well, how can you possibly know
you're not a lesbian
if you've never been
with another woman?
Yeah, believe me, I know —
not a lesbian.
Oh, you say that now.
But five years down the track,
you're sitting opposite Bevan in some
tortuously deafening marital silence
thinking about the opportunities
you gave up
because you decided
to imprison yourself with one man
who may or may not even be
a good root, because who knows?
Because we haven't slept
with anybody else.
I mean, I understand
people who settle for second best
as an informed choice,
but you're not even doing that.
You're just sort of out there
in some fantastical
Jane Austen bullshit haze.
Anyway. Couldn't be happier.
Little chilly, isn't it?
Try not to pull a number
like you did last year, hey, mate?
It took Juliet eleven and a half
months to forgive you.
Best behaviour, mate. Promise.
Looking forward to this.
He didn't even stop at
the light. He just sailed through.
I mean, it is a miracle
that no-one was hurt.
There are so many lunatics
on the road nowadays.
Correct.
Mmm.
So, Blake, you know, he insisted,
you know, for his own peace of mind,
while I'm ferrying
the children around,
and, you know,
I couldn't argue with that.
So he test-drove the top four
and then he settled on the Porsche.
You know, and I don't care
what anyone says.
You know, it is not
a self-indulgence
when you're trying to keep your kids
out of harm's way.
Correct.
Here she is.
- Hello.
- Hi.
This is Barney. Scarlet.
This is Melissa.
- Hi. Nice to meet you.
- Hi. Scarlet.
You look lovely.
Thank you.
And I said, “Well, you know what?
The dressing gown doesn't help.”
I know, it was a little bit cruel.
Oh, that's terrible.
We had to do something.
Hey!
Harry fucking Potter?!
You're kidding me.
Tell me it isn't so.
Oh. When did this happen?
Oh, he gave a tax seminar at
law school a couple of months ago.
A tax seminar? That's where
the magic happened, was it?
That's where you heard the violins
and felt the earth move —
in a tax seminar?
Oh, Cleaver, please.
I've been bitching to you
for over a year about this guy.
Well, it took me a little while
to put two and two together
because you always referred to him
as ‘Harry'.
And he referred to you as ‘the clown'.
And a... He refers to me as what?
Oh, he says it
with a certain degree of affection.
Missy, the guy's
trying to bankrupt me.
If our time together
means anything to you...
Oh, for God's sake, get a grip.
It's nothing personal.
He took a brief.
He's a prig.
He's talented, he's honest,
he's loyal...
My point exactly!
There are any number of reasons
why he's wrong for you.
Missy...
Jesus, Cleave,
would you give it a rest?
Have you told him yet?
Told him what?
About your previous life —
as the other kind of solicitor.
I didn't think so.
Means I'll have to get
a whole new other Bobcat.
No.
To do them — just to get the other.
He did.
Checking it when we were there.
I remember that.
And your response.
Oh, bull!
So have you met
Cleaver Greene before?
Why do you ask?
Well, I just saw you two talking
when you were coming out of the loo
and it looked oddly intense.
Yes, well, as it turns out,
Cleaver is an old friend
of a cousin of mine,
Angus.
Family black sheep.
Right. Ah.
Ooh, did you hear my mobile?
I don't think so.
No. For the thousandth time —
I'm not going to the lvy tonight.
What is it
with these people?
OK, so there's more
to that point...
..that I was making.
So just let me say this, OK?
Just be quiet while I say this.
Because this really,
really irritates me.
And I've thought about it a lot, OK?
So what I wanna say is, “You've got
to keep the warring tribes apart.”
You know, it's the wretched politics
that drive me nuts.
It's supposed to be
a happy event.
Correct. That is absolutely correct.
Oh, excuse me. Er, I'm sorry.
L...Linda, isn't it?
Leanne.
Leanne, yeah.
Sorry to interrupt, Leanne.
But, um, I'm curious about something.
Oh, yes?
Yeah. I've noticed you say
the word ‘correct' a lot.
Really?
Yeah.
I hadn't noticed.
Yes.
When somebody says something
that you agree with,
you don't say ‘yes' or ‘uh-huh'
or even ‘you go, girl'.
You say, ‘correct'.
I'm sorry, you've lost me, Cleaver.
Oh, well, it's...it's sort of like
a schoolteacher
talking to a 10-year-old.
You know, it's...you're not
actually agreeing,
you're approving.
It's as if the statement isn't valid
until you deem it so.
Your point being...?
Well, it's like
you're an arbiter of the truth.
It's a way of being
smug and superior, Leanne,
which is why so many fuckwits
in the city use it.
And now it's spread into the mouths
of the spouses
like some sort of contagion.
Your kids will be saying it soon —
from the back seat
of the four-wheel-drive Porsche,
feeling safe and smug and superior.
Buying a Porsche SUV for the sake
of the kids' safety.
I don't think I've heard
such transparently banal bullshit
in my entire life.
You go, girl.
Ah! Harry-sorry-David.
Interesting evening.
Just trying to keep the conversation
chugging along.
So Melissa tells me
you're a friend of her cousin's.
Angus.
Yes.
Yeah.
Yes, old friends.
Old, old friends.
Oh, he's a piece of work,
old Angus is.
A dark horse.
Black sheep, she said.
Well, I don't know
if this racial profiling
of livestock's getting us anywhere.
She tell you why
he's such a...dark sheep?
No.
Well, they had a thing.
Yeah. He and Melissa.
Romantic thing.
Must've been, er, 10 years ago.
She'd have barely been 17.
Yep. It was something like that.
He would've been, oh, 38, 39.
Tell me, are they, er...
..are they first...
First cousins. Yeah.
Yes. Ah. The shit hit the fan
when the family found out.
You can imagine.
Lasted the better part of a year.
You must know all this.
Bits.
Yeah.
They ran off to Paris together.
All very tempestuous.
She left him,
he tried to top himself,
she went back and he went off to work
for Bob Geldof.
All very messy.
Makes you think.
Sure does. The poor darling.
Some of the things
she's had to cope with.
Well, hello.
Mr Greene, how are you?
Battered, Miss Marx, but, er, that's
a pretty common condition for me.
You live around here?
Mmm. Mmm.
Just up on Rockwell Crescent.
I have seen you around before.
Please sit down.
Piccolo, Cleaver?
Oh, thanks, mate.
Max!
Whom Whoa.
Er, sorry for the state of my life.
Ah.
Mmm.
Mmm. Oh, Cleaver.
So...
How's the Lucy Marx thing going?
She wants to go to jail.
She wants to be a martyr?
Mmm. Nothing wrong with that.
If the cause is right.
You know there's not a soul
at the DPP who worked on that case
who thinks Tanisha's innocent?
Yeah, well, that's because
you guys are the prosecution.
You have that
dominant suspicion gene.
Oh, really?
Mmm.
Come on, even Dennis has his doubts,
and he was her solicitor.
Ah, you wanna have a chat with him.
You're up early.
Oh, don't be rude.
Like that! And then...
Ah...
Hey, just so you know,
Cleaver told me about you and Angus.
Oh. Did he?
What exactly did he tell you
about me and Angus?
You two running off to Paris, him
trying to kill himself, Bob Geldof...
It must've been around the time
your parents died.
How were they with it?
Oh, I mean, they were...
..they were appalled.
But you did manage to patch things up
with them before they passed?
Yeah.
They weren't the sort
to bear grudges.
Hey, you know
you can tell me anything.
Or nothing. I'm just...I'm here.
Hmm?
You finish the coffee.
I'll get the paper.
Hey, Bruce.
How are you, Dave?
Good, mate. Good.
No rest for the wicked, eh?
Tell me about it.
Well, see ya.
Crisis.
What?
I blew it. And there's no more milk.
Oh, bugger.
Hey!
David!
Oh, dear.
Yep.
Yep, gotcha.
Thanks, mate.
They picked up
your neighbour's brother.
Some sort of family feud.
How is he?
He was very lucky.
His shoulder's a flesh wound.
The other bullet
went through the abdomen.
Oh...
No organs were damaged.
He'll be fine.
Oh, thank God.
Dad?
Where's the bloody thing?
I had it out this morning.
Can't believe you haven't seen this.
Dad.
Ali and Foreman —
the ‘Rumble in the Jungle'.
It's human perfection.
I'm seeing someone, Dad.
So she's a girl from your school?
And are you doing the...
Mm-hm.
And you're taking precautions?
Yes.
OK.
She's in your class?
She's in my class, yeah.
OK, I don't see what
the bloody subterfuge is about.
The...girl hasn't told her parents.
Won't. Can't.
And I know Mum would insist we start
a constructive dialogue with them
and make sure we're all on
the same emotional page.
I don't know.
Dad, I'm really into her.
Could we come here?
Oh, mate...
I mean, there's nowhere else
for us to go.
Oh...
You don't want us paying
for some crappy room in the Cross.
Oh, no, not when you've got
a crappy room in the Cross for free.
It'll only be...after school.
Two afternoons a week. Three, max.
And you'll be at work anyway, so
you won't even know we've been here.
Mate, I'm... Listen, I might have
my own needs with that bed.
I might be in love myself, you know?
And I might not want it smelling
of teen spirit.
You're in love too?
Yes, could be.
Could very well be.
She's like a mixture
of Mandela and Gandhi
and Mother Teresa all rolled into one.
Oh, yuck.
But hot.
Hot.
A Sydney barrister
remains in a stable condition
after he was shot trying to prevent
an assassination attempt...
..in Sydney's inner west
this afternoon.
David Potter was shot twice
after his neighbour's brother opened
fire outside a Lilyfield home.
Oh.
You're kidding me.
You are kidding me.
So the first bullet hits him
and he doesn't even go down.
Then the guy's gun jams
and he keeps pointing it at David
and pulling the trigger,
but nothing happens.
Oh, thank God for that.
If itd been me, I'd have bolted,
but David —
David just charged at him.
It's like...l couldn't
believe my eyes.
Yes, I'll bet. Yeah.
I've never seen courage
like it, Cleave.
I mean, nothing in my life
has ever come close.
Yeah, well, that sort of behaviour's
instinctive, isn't it?
I beg your pardon?
Well, I mean, it's not
a conscious decision, is it?
It bloody well was.
Well, he'd been shot.
He didn't know what he was doing.
I'd have done the same.
You?!
Do you remember the time that
the fire alarm went off in the club?
You were hysterical!
I was handcuffed to the bed.
You can't even give him credit
when he gets shot twice
trying to save his neighbour's life!
Yeah, well, frankly, it doesn't
sound like he was in that much danger.
I mean, four shots off,
no fatalities
and...and nobody even
on the critical list.
It's not exactly Mossad, is it?
You're impossible.
Oh, and by the way, thanks
for the details about me and Angus.
Oh, as if I was gonna let that
go through to the keeper.
Oh, shit.
Problem?
Oh, I was supposed to meet
Mother Teresa for a drink.
Go.
I can amuse myself
until Mum comes back.
Are you sure?
What's wrong?
Hmm. Hey, baby?
Mmm.
Hmm, Cleaver. What is it?
Nothing.
What's wrong?
Oh...this guy I know got shot.
Who?
Oh, not the hero lawyer guy?
Yes, the hero lawyer guy.
Oh, is he a friend of yours?
No, he's not a friend of mine.
And he's not a fucking hero, alright?
He's a tax lawyer.
Oh.
Now he's been shot, everybody thinks
he's Jesus F. bloody Kennedy.
He's not a hero. You're a hero.
Really?
Yeah.
You're my hero.
Really?
Mmm.
Er... Ooh?
Wha... Oh, what the hell is that?!
What?
Oh, God!
Oh. Oh, that would be my son's.
Oh, I thought
I could smell teenager.
I know. It's revolting, isn't it?
Oh.
Um...anyway.
We shouldn't let that
interrupt our conference.
Our conference?
Us doing it is a conference?
Well, for billing purposes.
You don't want me doing
any real prep, do you?
You might stand a chance of winning.
Mmm.
So what can I do for you, Cleave?
Who's Katrina Ryan?
Um, oh, I can remember
hearing something about her.
What, is she against you in Marx?
Yeah.
She is, as a matter of fact.
You know she's only two years
out of law school?
Is she?
Yeah.
No, I heard
she's a bit of a young gun.
I hear she needs a bullet.
No, nothing to do with me, mate.
It's the DPP's call.
I guess you guys just got lucky.
Any word on the judge?
Er, yeah.
Yeah, er, Jessica Mason.
Jess Mason? You're kidding me.
No. No, that's what I've been told.
Right.
Single mother with four daughters,
one of whom lost a leg
in that ferry disaster last year.
Yeah. Yeah, that was a tragedy.
Joe, what's going on?
No idea what you're talking about.
Well, I got Julie Andrews for a judge
and Shirley Temple
for the prosecution.
Yeah, mate, I've told you.
Nothing to do with me.
Ooh, mate, I've gotta go.
I'd, er, I'd wish you luck, Cleave.
I'm not sure you need it.
The bastards are throwing it.
They want her to walk free.
I heard about Katrina Ryan.
Yeah, it gets better.
We're gonna be before Jess Mason.
Oh, she's not gonna
send Lucy to jail.
She'll give her a bloody medal.
I know. So I've gotta figure out
some way to piss her off.
Her and the jury.
Oh, well, it's never been
a problem for you before.
You wanna have lunch?
I can't, mate.
I'm having lunch
with Dennis the Menace.
Why?
He defended Tanisha. He said
he's happy to have a quiet word.
The more we know...
Well, it was bloody weird.
Here was their star fullback
stabbed to death
and none of his teammates
would talk about it,
not even to the prosecution.
None of 'em had a clue, apparently.
‘Don't know anything,
barely knew her,
“Gav was a good bloke,
kept to himself.”
They have anything to say
about Tanisha?
No.
But, you know, but I could tell
she was not well liked.
Every time I mentioned her name,
the room got a little chillier.
Doesn't make her guilty.
- Here she comes!
- Ms Marx...
Will you go to jail?
Um...yes, Your Honour.
What w-we have...
What we have...the...
..the case, er, before Your Honour
is one of grave...greatness.
Great gravity.
Um...the relevant section...
IS...
Oh, sorry. Sorry.
If Your Honour will bear with me...
68a.
Thanks. Section 68a, er...
Here it is.
Your Honour, could I request
a brief adjournment
while I confer with my client?
Certainly, Mr Greene.
All rise.
Ms Ryan, may I have a word?
Oh, Mr Greene. Hello.
Thank you, by the way.
That was...very kind.
Oh, what are learned friends for?
You seem a little flustered.
Was it noticeable?
Only to the highly trained eye.
It's...it's my first big trial.
I... To be frank, I was rather
surprised when they briefed me.
I remember my first big trial.
I was throwing up all day.
Sowas I. I, um...
..still am, in fact.
Have you heard of beta blockers?
Um, I think so.
They take away
that performance anxiety.
Oh, really?
Mmm.
Look, I happen to have
a couple on me.
That's so kind of you. Thank you.
Keep the pack.
But don't you need them?
Oh, probably not today.
Your Honour, as I was saying before
Mr Greene requested the recess,
offences under the ‘Jury Act'
represent a most grave threat
to our system of justice.
Jurors must feel safe and free
in their decision taking.
Not just before, not just during,
but also subsequent
to their verdict.
What the hell?
She's...she's good!
What can I say?
Women.
They're such flighty things,
aren't they?
Erratic. Unpredictable.
Quick to respond to sudden impulses.
Laughing one minute,
crying bloody murder the next,
and not just
when they have their periods.
Mr Greene, may I ask
where this is leading?
Your Honour, my client is a woman.
We are aware of that fact,
Mr Greene.
And she's not just
a woman, Your Honour.
She's a mother.
Go on.
Thank you.
A mother's greatest boast
is that she will go
to extraordinary lengths
to defend and protect her children.
Tanisha Marx was born
as the result of a one-night stand
that Lucy had in Auckland,
some 19 years ago.
Er, the father...
..to this day is blissfully ignorant
of the fact
that he even has a daughter.
The fact that Lucy Marx
had a lot of sexual partners
when she was young
has absolutely no bearing
on this case,
and you must disregard that fact.
You must also disregard the fact
that Ms Marx is still clearly
prepared to sleep with anyone.
If that's what it takes
for her to pursue her quest
for justice and vengeance.
However much that quest
may seem to conflict
with the so-called laws
that govern this State.
Thank you, Your Honour.
He didn't!
He didn't?
That conniving bastard!
He's gone totally Broken Arrow
on us, boss.
Oh, shitty shit!
Fuck's sake!
In all my years,
I have never seen such a display.
Such wilful negligence.
Your opening was 100 times more
damaging to your client's case
than Ms Ryan's.
Er, well, I'm saddened
Your Honour feels that way.
Er, it was a strategy devised
in full consultation with my client.
Come.
Your Honour.
Have you sought further
instructions, Mr Meagher?
I have, Your Honour.
And Ms Marx is perfectly happy
with the way Mr Greene
is conducting this case.
Alright, you two,
what's going on here?
Whatever do you mean, Your Honour?
I mean I am this fucking close
to referring your conduct
to the Bar Association.
Were you aware
of the existence of the ‘Jury Act'
before contriving
to meet Mr Daniels at Chasers?
I most certainly was.
Oh.
W-were you aware
that seeking information
about a jury's deliberations,
even after a sentence
has been passed, was a crime?
A crime subject to the maximum
of seven years in prison? Yes.
Um...right.
Er...
Well, er, then...no further
questions, Your Honour.
Anything further, Mr Greene?
Nothing further,
thank you, Your Honour.
Are you sure of that?
Quite sure. Thank you, Your Honour.
We'll resume in the morning.
All rise.
I know the single mother's
about to have your balls on a plate.
Short-term tactical necessity.
Long-term testicular catastrophe.
Thought the conduct committee
made it pretty clear last time
they didn't wanna see you
ever again.
Ah, bunch of pussies.
Bunch of pussies who
could have you struck off.
Mate, we've got a client who's prepared
to go to jail on a matter of principle.
What sort of dipshit would I be to be
worried about the conduct committee?
What about Mick and Vanessa's
repayment plan?
Oh, you really are
Captain Buzzkill, aren't you?
What if Tanisha's guilty?
Barnyard, I'm a big boy.
I know what I'm doing.
Michael Warner?
Yeah.
Are you Gav Warner's cousin?
So you think Tanisha will get out?
There's a chance.
There's a lot of political pressure.
It's an election year.
And she's pretty — the public
always forgives the pretty ones.
Look, mate, I just need to know
what happened.
So we can do the right thing.
We wanna do the right thing.
Your name will never be mentioned.
Is it true
that you told the jury foreman
that Tanisha was a bitch
and that she killed your cousin?
Mmm.
You had information?
But you didn't give it to the police?
I wanted to tell the cops
what really happened.
But no-one would back me up.
They said it'd be my word
against theirs
and if it came down to it
they'd say I was the one
she was rooting out of school.
Who's ‘they'?
Oh, his...his teammates.
Tanisha was having an affair
with one of Gav's teammates?
No. She was having an affair
with his coach.
You know, he's married, Catholic,
father of six kids,
eight premierships.
Purer-than-pure supercoach.
Clive Booth?
Yeah.
Are you sure?
Yeah, Gav told me.
You know, he couldn't do anything
about it, though.
Clive Booth was a god to him.
He's a god to everyone.
Alright, the night he died,
Gav rang me and told me
he was gonna confront her about it.
And you think that Booth was there?
Well, not if
the time of death's right.
He was giving a speech
halfway across town.
But I'll bet you he helped her
get rid of the body.
When did Clive Booth die, again?
Er, four months after Gav.
Yeah, a heart attack, right?
Yeah.
Come up.
Is Lucy upstairs?
Yeah, but she's cool.
Tanisha did it.
Oh, not this shit again.
Yeah, this shit again.
Barnyard, you can't possibly know
she did it.
Yeah, I can. I just spent two hours
with Gav Warner's cousin.
The cousin. Well, he was part of
the problem in the first place.
Clive Booth was the problem, mate.
Tanisha was having
an affair with him.
Gav found out
and threatened to go public.
It's the only way
it makes sense, Cleave.
Everything that Dennis said,
the DPP...
Mate.
This is me talking, mate.
She's using you.
No.
What did he want?
Nothing important. He's, er,
just having a few problems at home.
I didn't wanna talk about the trial,
what happened in the jury room.
None of it.
She made me talk about it.
I feel violated.
Mr Daniels, what was Ms Marx doing
while you were having
this conversation?
She was...
..going down on me.
I beg your pardon?
She was going down on me.
Going down on you.
By which you mean
she was performing oral sex on you?
Yes.
That's how she compelled you
to break your oath to the court?
Mr Daniels, you're 28 years old,
is that correct?
Yes.
Ms Marx is 38 years old. Do you
prefer the company of older women?
Um, I don't know.
She was nice-looking.
I put it to you, Mr Daniels,
that it was you who was seeking
to take advantage that evening.
Advantage of a lonely,
vulnerable woman.
No.
I see.
How much did the ‘Tele'
pay you for your story?
How much, Mr Daniels?
20 grand.
So you got a slap-up meal,
oral sex and 20 grand,
and still you feel violated?
Some people are very hard to satisfy,
Mr Daniels.
What was that?!
Since when was attacking
Marty Daniels part of the plan?
For a moment there, it sounded like
you wanted to nail him!
Sorry. Old habits.
I am not happy
about what happened in there.
You were a part of Tanisha's alibi,
weren't you?
Yes.
You told the trial
that on the night Gavin died
you had a phone call from Tanisha
and you chatted for a few moments,
you said she sounded fine.
Yes. Her phone records
bore that out.
Why do you ask?
Because your phone records
also bear out the fact
that you made another call
after you hung up from Tanisha.
You called Clive Booth.
I'm presuming you told him
to go over to Tanisha's place
and help her dispose of the body?
You blackmailing him...
..sort of your M.O., isn't it?
Signature dish.
I did what any mother would do.
Not my mum.
I can't represent you anymore, Lucy.
I was only prepared to put you
in jail when you weren't guilty.
That is going to have consequences.
Everything does.
I really liked her.
It was weird, she reminded me
of you somehow.
How did that make you feel?
Strangely comforted.
Hmm.
I had this fantasy
about coming around here
one time with Lucy and...
And, what, we'd end up
jelly wrestling?
Oh, well, I hadn't thought of that.
But now that you mention it...
So. Did she displace
your feelings for Melissa?
What does that matter?
Answer the question.
Oh, come on, darling. You know me.
My feelings never get displaced,
they just get added to.
I still love everyone
I've ever loved —
you, Missy,
Miss Harbright
my fourth grade teacher.
And?
After Judge Jessica Mason
ruled a mistrial,
she referred Lucy Marx's counsel
Cleaver Greene
to the Professional Conduct
Committee of the Bar Council.
The Bar Association.
..sent shock waves
through Sydney's legal community.
Well, Cleaver Greene was
not only negligent at my trial...
Oh, hello.
At possibly the most vulnerable time
of my life,
he seduced me
and for most of the last week
before my trial,
we were having sexual intercourse.
Oh, yes.
He did almost no work.
He even bragged about it.
We shouldn't let
that interrupt our conference.
Our conference?
Us doing it is a conference?
Well, for billing purposes.
You don't want me
doing any real prep, do you?
We might stand a chance of winning.
I heard the news.
Are you OK?
http://hiqve.com/