Namibia,
Southern Africa.
A vast, dried-up lakebed...
...where temperatures can reach
almost 50 degrees Celsius.
DISTANT BRAYING
Overheating
is dangerous for all.
Nonetheless,
in this cauldron of heat...
...mammals have found
a way to survive.
Across the planet,
mammals have learnt
how to deal with heat...
...in the most remarkable ways.
The Serra da Capivara in Brazil.
A world of harsh, dry forest...
...and scorched cliff faces.
Here, the dry season lasts
for up to seven months.
And what little rain that falls
quickly disappears.
Despite this,
one mammal has made it home.
A family of bearded capuchins.
They have spent the night
high up on the cliff faces,
safe from any predators below.
It may be early,
but already temperatures
are beginning to soar.
The troop
needs to find water.
And none need it more
than a mother.
Without it,
she won't be able
to produce the milk
essential for her young baby.
But first, they must make
the treacherous journey
down to the forest floor.
The newborn must hold on tight.
Others forge ahead.
For the first
to reach the forest floor...
...the last few cashew fruit
provide some welcome sustenance.
But there's not enough
to go around.
Mother and baby must go without.
At nearly 40 degrees,
the heat is relentless.
Desperate,
the troop look for anything
that might contain water.
Could the trees
provide the solution?
Hidden in some trunks,
there is a little water,
left over from the last rains.
But reaching it
is a real monkey puzzle.
Mammals, however,
are experts at solving problems.
An older male
tries a different approach.
Perhaps a bit more brains
and a little less brawn.
A stick produces
a dribble of success.
Having watched all the others try,
the mother finally gets her turn.
WATER SLOSHES
Her tail acts like a sponge...
...soaking up any water
that has collected in the trunk.
Being able to tap
these hidden wells
is more than just a clever trick.
It's a life-saving lesson...
...and one the rest of her family
quickly learn.
Their ability
to solve such problems
will help the troop survive
these long, hot, dry months.
And, finally, the newborn
can get a much-needed
drink of its own.
But there are places
that are even hotter and even drier.
Australia -
the driest inhabited
continent on Earth,
with almost a million
square miles of desert.
A furnace where water
is almost impossible to find.
An Arabian camel.
Introduced in the 1800s
by early explorers,
it's estimated
that as many as one million
now roam the outback.
For this lone male
in search of a mate,
desert plants
provide a few slim pickings.
Any surplus nutrients
can be stored
in his most famous feature...
...his hump.
Full of fat,
it's a built-in energy store
that can be tapped when needed.
And as long as he can find food,
he can go without
drinking for months.
At last,
what he's been looking for.
GRUNTING
A herd of females.
It's important
that he makes
a good first impression.
GURGLING BELLOW
And he has a special way
of doing so...
...with a dulla.
GURGLING
BELLOWING
This inflatable sac
is unique to camels,
and accompanied by loud gurgling...
GURGLING
...is his way of attracting females.
Has he done enough to impress?
GRUNTING
Apparently not.
A raised tail
is a polite way of saying,
"No, thank you."
Not so easy after all.
Could she be the one?
GRUNTING
BELLOWING
Looking good!
Bad luck, Romeo.
GURGLING
Despite his best efforts,
it's not been his day.
Camels have overcome
the desert's greatest test -
its lack of water.
But this is not the only challenge
faced by mammals
in hot and arid conditions.
Just as dangerous
is the risk of overheating.
Sifaka lemurs...
...in one of the hottest
and driest places in Madagascar.
The trees provide some shade...
...and a little relief
from the burning sun.
But with midday temperatures
that can exceed 45 degrees...
...the heat up here
soon becomes unbearable...
...especially for the babies...
...the most vulnerable
members of the group.
But sifaka
have an unusual and clever way
to cool down...
...if only they can
find the right tree.
And once they have...
...they hug it.
The Salvadora tree
is one of their favourites.
These trees draw up cool water
from deep below ground...
...so their trunks
are a few degrees cooler
than everything else around.
At the hottest time of day,
some embraces
can last for over four hours.
And some trees are so popular...
...there isn't an inch to spare.
This remarkable behaviour
was first recorded
by scientists in 2017.
As the world becomes hotter,
we may see cooling
behaviours like this
become more and more common.
But some sifakas
have gone one stage further.
They know the best place
is within the trunk
of the Salvadora tree.
Here, the temperature
can be even cooler.
And that can give real respite
from the oven outside.
Sifakas have learnt
that tree-hugging
is an effective way to keep cool.
But some mammals
face a far more dangerous
source of heat than the sun.
The dry eucalyptus forests
of Australia.
Home to one of the most
bizarre of all mammals.
An echidna.
It's one of the most
ancient of mammals
and reproduces
by laying eggs.
SNIFFING
She's out foraging,
using her highly sensitive nose
to look for ants and termites.
To work at its best,
her nose has to be kept moist.
And this has led her
to developing an unusual skill.
She blows snot bubbles.
As the moisture evaporates,
it helps to cool her down.
But this female is not alone.
She can be followed
by up to ten or more males...
...all vying for her attention.
It's what is known
as a love train.
And it can run for weeks.
One male has managed to get close.
With such a prickly partner,
a gentle touch is needed.
But some romantic liaisons
don't last long.
With their sensitive noses,
echidnas can detect
the early signs of danger.
A bushfire.
Their best chance of safety
is to get underground.
Echidnas often go underground
to avoid the severe heat of the day.
But they also have to do so
to escape the heat of a bushfire.
Between 2019 and 2020,
Australia experienced
its most catastrophic
bushfire season on record.
Over 100,000 square miles,
an area larger
than the United Kingdom,
was devastated.
But in such dangerous conditions,
echidna have
a remarkable survival skill.
They go into a deep sleep
known as a torpor.
It's a form of hibernation,
during which their heart rate
may slow to only
four beats a minute.
Their core body temperature drops.
And they may only take a breath
once every three minutes.
By doing this,
they can live for days
without food or water.
After the fire has passed...
...the echidnas begin to emerge.
Not all are unscathed.
Melted spines
show that this one
has had a close call.
But others
show no ill effects.
Their unique adaptations
have kept them safe.
But as global temperatures rise,
forest fires
are becoming more intense...
...and more frequent.
The survival skills of echidnas
will become even more crucial.
Going underground to avoid the heat
makes obvious sense,
but one mammal
does the exact opposite.
Harris's antelope squirrel.
Even during the height of summer,
when ground temperatures
can exceed 80 degrees Celsius...
...he will be out foraging
amongst the cactus
of the Arizona desert.
By being out now,
he avoids competition
from other mammals.
But the squirrels don't
have it all their own way.
A rattlesnake,
which is looking for
a rodent-sized meal.
It's a stand-off...
...to see who can withstand
the most heat.
As the ground temperature
continues to rise,
the squirrel's core temperature
reaches 43 degrees Celsius.
That would be fatal for humans
and most other animals.
But the squirrels
have a clever trick
that can quickly reduce
their body temperature.
He heat-dumps.
By spreading its hot body
against the cooler sand
in the shade,
a squirrel can rapidly reduce
its body temperature down
by up to one degree a minute.
The rattlesnake
simply can't compete.
It has to find shelter
to avoid overheating.
With the coast now clear,
the squirrel can continue his search
for the fruit
of the spiny cholla cactus.
But this one
has already lost
all of its low-hanging fruit.
There's only one thing for it.
He will have to clamber up
the spine-covered branches.
He must be very cautious.
But this fruit...
...is a stretch...
...too... far.
Try again.
But the price of success
can be painful.
He has to remove
some very sharp spines.
A final heat-dump
before enjoying the fruit
of his labour.
This tiny squirrel
has found a clever way
to deal with the heat.
But when you're nearly
six metres tall
and weigh almost two tonnes...
...it's altogether
a much bigger problem.
The Hoanib Valley
on Namibia's Skeleton Coast.
Home to some of nature's
real giants.
Giraffes.
This herd is guarded
by a dominant bull.
They spend much of their day
out in the open,
searching for food.
Their tongues are black
with a pigment
that acts as a sunblock.
But this is only one of the ways
by which a giraffe beats the heat.
It's now about to use
another of
its heat-beating adaptations.
A rival male.
He approaches the females.
The dominant bull
moves to intercept.
The bulls square up.
These blows are violent enough
to tear skin and break bone.
They're now pushing themselves
to the limit.
Their core temperatures
are rising to near-lethal levels.
The reason they don't overheat
is connected to
their distinctive skin pattern.
A thermal camera reveals
that below each brown spot
there is a dense network
of blood vessels.
As the giraffes'
body temperatures rise...
...these blood vessels expand...
...releasing body heat...
...so enabling them to fight on.
The force of each blow
is visible as a white-hot slash.
SNORTS
The dominant bull wins...
...and his rival retreats.
In Trinidad lives a mammal
that detects the heat
that animals produce...
...and uses it to guide them
to a drink of their victim's blood.
The white-winged vampire bat.
On the prowl
for its next victim.
This cockerel is fast asleep.
But the bat must be careful.
Cockerels are light sleepers.
The bite must be delivered
with precision.
Heat-sensitive receptors
enable vampire bats
to detect subtle differences
in temperature...
...so it can pinpoint exactly
where the warm blood
flows close to the skin.
She bites.
Her saliva contains
a powerful anticoagulant
known as draculin.
It ensures that the blood
continues to flow freely.
This helps her feed quickly
and avoids her being noticed.
But blood isn't,
in fact, very nutritious,
so the bats have to drink
over half their own body weight
in one sitting.
As a result,
flight becomes nearly impossible.
But her kidneys are remarkable...
...and quickly extract
the water from her meal.
So, within minutes,
she vanishes into the darkness...
...leaving the cockerel
none the wiser.
CLUCKS QUIETLY
While vampire bats use heat
from the blood of their victims
to find their meals,
one mammal
uses the heat from the sun.
Uganda, in Africa,
on the banks of the River Nile.
A troop of baboons has gathered
at the end
of the long, hot dry season.
They are waiting
for a very special
seasonal opportunity.
It begins
with the annual emergence
of flying termites.
They provide the baboons
with a small but much-needed treat.
But the older members of the troop
know there is another delicacy
to be found here...
...one that provides them
with a far more nourishing meal.
SCREECHES
A Nile crocodile.
She laid her eggs...
...in the warm sand.
The baboons would steal them
if they could.
BARKS
But the crocodile,
weighing nearly a quarter of a ton,
is one of Africa's
most formidable predators
and well able to kill a baboon...
SNARLS
BARKS
HISSES
...so the utmost caution is required.
Their plan is simple.
They wait.
Whilst the crocodile
must stay in the sun,
guarding its nest...
...the baboons keep their cool
in the shade...
...waiting for just the right moment.
The crocodile begins to gape.
It's a way of losing heat.
The sun
gets stronger.
But the crocodile stays on guard
and risks overheating.
GRUNTS QUIETLY
Eventually, it gets so hot...
...that it takes to the water
to cool down.
But the baboons still do...
...nothing.
Their waiting game
has not yet finished.
There's no sense
in overexerting yourself
in the heat...
...when you can
let hungry monitor lizards
do the hard work.
Finally,
the moment
they have been waiting for.
MONITOR LIZARD HISSES
Now they need to move fast.
The crocodile
won't be away for long.
BABOONS BARK
CROCODILE HISSES
The oppressive heat
has allowed the baboons
to get the food they want.
But there are few places in Africa
where the battle to find food
is more demanding
than the Etosha salt pan in Namibia.
As temperatures rise
across this vast wilderness,
mammals of many kinds
are gathering around
a shrinking water hole.
DISTANT BRAYING
For a female jackal...
...this is a good place to hunt.
But it's almost too crowded.
ELEPHANT TRUMPETS
For a jackal to be successful,
it needs to be clever.
Just a ghost
in the background.
Some of the largest mammals on Earth
dominate the water's edge.
ELEPHANT RUMBLES
The jackal must bide her time.
BABY ELEPHANT TRUMPETS
DISTANT SQUAWKING
She spots possible prey.
Guinea fowl.
ELEPHANT RUMBLES
SQUAWKING
Thirst, however,
dominates everything else.
And hunters and hunted
drink alongside one another.
Temperatures are still rising.
BRAYING
The drinkers start to quarrel...
...and she retreats.
But then...
...things get even more difficult.
A hyena.
More than capable
of killing a jackal.
But driven by hunger and thirst...
JACKAL YELPS
...this female holds her ground...
...and now can get back to hunting.
This time, she sets her sights
on a flock of doves...
...and tries a more subtle approach.
Hiding in plain sight.
Lulling the birds
into a false sense of security.
She waits for the perfect moment.
But they aren't so easily caught.
Nonetheless...
...she's determined.
Success at last.
Her mate arrives...
...and he has brought
their hungry pups with him.
With so many mouths to feed...
...she will have
to be hunting again soon.
PUP WHINES
Mammals have
an extraordinary ability
to find water...
...stay cool...
...and use heat
to their advantage.
That has enabled them to flourish
in some of the harshest
and hottest environments
on the planet.
But if the world is indeed
to become even hotter,
as is predicted...
...then the challenges facing mammals
will become greater
than they have ever been.
In Madagascar,
the Mammals team
hoped to be the first to film
some recently
discovered behaviour...
...sifaka lemurs tree-hugging.
But to get there,
it's a three-day drive
over rough terrain.
A little too much
for producer Rob Pilley.
HE RETCHES
Happy to be back on terra firma,
the team set off on foot
through the spiny forest.
They've joined forces
with local scientists
from the ESSA research group.
And thanks to their expertise,
it doesn't take long
to find the sifaka.
WHISPERS: They're
a little wary of humans,
so we have to go really slowly,
approach them slowly.
They're quite skittish.
The sifaka are much more nimble
moving through the forest
than the crew
carrying bulky kit.
Keeping up with the troop
is not without its snags.
Ah, everything is out to get you,
it's just this giant cactus forest.
They are everywhere, the spines.
And the dense scrub
makes getting any shots a challenge.
Yeah, it kind of makes you
almost forced to shoot
such high-angle shots
when it's so dense
cos we can't get further back.
Also just manoeuvring
around the forest,
it's pretty hectic.
Trying to go quietly
without snagging your camera
or your lens or a cable or...
...is, uh, not easy.
Over the following days,
the team struggle through the heat,
with the lemurs
giving them the run-around.
We just found a group and
they've just disappeared off.
This is going to be a marathon,
not a sprint.
Lemurs Behaving Badly!
As temperatures rise,
the lemurs finally seem to settle.
HE EXHALES
This could be
a breakthrough for the team.
WHISPERS: Stu is up front.
It's just possible
that we have found
the perfect tree-hugging group.
Fingers crossed.
Not this time.
Just been given the run-around
all morning by these lemurs -
starburst, every direction.
Couldn't get a single shot.
It's like the worst day ever!
Back at camp,
it's 45 degrees in the shade.
While Stuart finds a way
to cool himself off...
Whew! That's good!
...Jeandre is more worried
about the equipment.
We raised the laptop up
on these hard drives
to give it some cooling.
It's just too hot.
The cameras are melting.
The little metal pins in the camera
have literally melted. It's...
I've never had that on a shoot.
Despite the heat,
the team are forced to work
during the hottest part of the day
if they want to film
this unique tree-hugging behaviour.
But as the lemurs lead them
deeper into the forest,
they notice something is amiss.
In the heart
of this protected area,
there are signs
that trees have been felled.
We see for the last two, three years
increasing cutting within the forest
and we believe that it's because
these people are so desperate
and cut the trees for
the forage for their animals
and then for their daily needs.
With ongoing drought,
crops are failing,
and local people are forced
to turn to the forest
to make ends meet.
Across Madagascar,
deforestation and the effects
of climate change
are only making life harder
for both wildlife and people.
It's a sobering reminder to the team
of the problems
faced by these lemurs,
who are having to adapt
to a rapidly changing world.
Back on the trail,
the team split up
to cover more ground.
Now separated,
the researchers have
a special way to keep in touch.
HE WHOOPS
Using calls similar to the animals
lets them maintain a low profile.
But as they push forward,
the heat of the day
is taking its toll
on Jeandre and Rob.
We... we all just have
to stop for a bit,
have a breather.
And when they start moving again,
they quickly realise they're lost.
It all looks the same.
I think it's up here.
We're not really quite sure...
...where we are.
HE WHOOPS
Ow!
In these conditions,
it only takes a few hours
for heatstroke to set in.
ROB WHOOPS
WHOOPING
Yeah, OK, they're ahead,
they're ahead. That's good.
There's a friendly face!
UNTRANSLATED
So nice to see you.
Somebody wandered off that way...
Quickly, things
can go really pear-shaped
unless you're on your game, so...
A lesson learned, definitely.
Despite this close call,
the team are determined to continue.
It's the hottest day so far,
which should work in their favour.
At last,
they find a group that is settling.
Lemurs only tree-hug
in the hottest conditions.
All the crew can do now is wait.
Finally...
...what they came for.
Thanks to the work
of this research team,
the efforts to protect
the sifakas' home
will continue.
With the education
and working together
at different levels,
from locals to national,
to international levels,
for common goals,
then I be very optimistic,
the future of Madagascar.
Next time...
...forests, where we
discover how nearly three
quarters of all mammal species
have made their home in this,
the richest and most
diverse habitat...
...on Earth.