Thank you. Have a nice day.
Hello, Mr Chandler.
Hey, Alice. How are you?
Bec and Mrs Chandler
have a nice time in Thredbo?
A lovely time. Thank you very much.
Has Bec started exams yet?
Uh, next week, I...
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
Just hit me!
Come on. Just hit me.
I'll give you a free shot.
Leave my property, please.
Barn, hit me, you fuckwit!
Come on, come on!
I deserve it.
Would you shut up?
The kids are home.
OK, sorry, sorry.
Look, Barn, I know this isn't
a usual cock-up, mate.
I know I can't excuse it
by saying that we were drunk
or that I was simply trying
to comfort your wife.
Save your bullshit
for the courtroom.
It's not bullshit, mate.
I have too much respect for you.
Oh, respect?!
How dare you
talk about respect to me!
You see, this is your problem.
You can talk about respect,
talk about it brilliantly.
I'm sure you can quote
Shakespeare or Einstein
or Groucho on the subject.
But what makes you a tragedy
is that as well as you
can talk about respect,
you never fucking give it.
You're a selfish turd.
So for the hundredth time, piss off!
Hi, mate.
Come in?
Nup.
I beg your pardon?
Mum doesn't want you here
and I don't want you here.
Oh, what? You're forbidding entry?
That's right.
Why am I in the shit here?
I don't understand.
I thought you were
having sex with a classmate.
You didn't tell me it was a teacher.
I let you use my flat.
Yeah, well, then you told her
to go fuck off.
Wendy!
What's going on?
Fuzz, get inside now, please.
Oh, come on. Forbidden access?
Well, you went behind my back.
Wendy, I didn't know
it was his teacher. I swear.
What? You think that's
some kind of defence?
Yes, I do, as a matter of fact,
and funnily enough not a bad one.
Don't you think
you ought to have known?
What?
Jesus, Cleaver, you're a barrister.
You cross-examine people for
a living, yet a 15-year-old boy...
I asked him if it was a girl in his class
and he said, yes, it was.
Did you ask him what her name was?
What difference could that have made?
I don't know the names
of anybody in his class.
No, you don't.
Doesn't matter, does it?
Doesn't matter what her name is,
what she's like.
None of that matters
because your son
is finally becoming a man,
a chip off the old block.
I didn't know she was 28, alright?
I thought she was 15.
Well, did you find out if he thought
this 15-year-old girl
was ready for intercourse?
I mean, did you make sure
he wasn't pressuring her?
Wendy, it's Fuzz. What... It's Fuzz!
I thought it was
a couple of kids in love.
It's a story as old
as mankind itself.
Why do you have to over-analyse
absolutely everything?
Cleaver, because
I'm the responsible parent, OK?
And it's not a role
I relish particularly.
I'm sick to death of being
the only grown-up in this family.
I'd love to share the load.
I really would.
So if you can convince me
that you can shoulder some of it,
come back then.
“Did you have a good day
at the office, darling?”
“Yes, I had a lovely day.
And how was your day?”
“Good. Would you like
a cocktail of some description?”
“That'd be marvellous.”
Oh, fuck me.
Bronwyn, another beautiful soul
has just taken her first breath.
Doctor, your briefcase
has been handed in to the police.
Oh, my briefcase. Good, good.
Thank you, Bronwyn.
Um, they're here, actually —
the police.
They'd like to have a word.
What's going on?
They found the DVD.
What do you mean,
“They found the DVD”?
It was in my case.
What?
It was in my briefcase
when it was stolen.
What was it doing in your briefcase,
for God's sake?
lt...
I needed to know where it was.
We have a perfectly good
safe at home!
It's not safe.
Bec has the combination.
Oh, no. God. Ohh.
Colin.
Cleave.
How's it dangling?
To the left, mate.
Good, good.
Come on. Fucking hit him!
Come on, get off the ropes!
Come on. Get in there!
Come on!
Want a beer?
The pope shit in the woods?
Manos. How are we?
Cleave. Long time no see.
Yeah.
http://hiqve.com/
Hey! It's only me.
Let me do the talking.
OK.
So are you gonna be charged?
It looks like it, yeah.
Can I see it?
What?
The DVD.
What? No!
You must promise us
you will never watch that DVD.
Well, they'll show it
if there's a trial, won't they?
If there's a trial,
I don't want you to be there,
for your sake as much as ours.
Please, sweetheart,
it cannot do you any good.
I mean, you mustn't let
this silliness distract you.
You've got exams coming up.
Distract me?
Mum, you can't possibly think
that this is just a distraction.
I'm so sorry, darling.
Ironically, my first exam's crim.
Sweetheart.
When in doubt,
stick your left out. That's my boy!
Come on, you joke!
Oh, you're a joke.
You're a fool to your family.
Col, double it.
Come on, mate. He's getting smashed.
Double it.
I'm good for it. Double it.
I'll have to ring Mick.
Ring him, fast.
Alright.
Come on. Come on, you little poof!
Yeah! That's the way. That's my boy.
Come on, you little prick. Come on!
Ohh!
I don't understand, Cleave.
You said you had the cash.
Mick's gonna fucking flip out.
Come on, Col. Let's get on with it.
Life's too short
to wait for a beating.
Justice delayed is justice denied
and if justice is denied,
the whole system crashes,
the walls come tumbling down, mate.
Just... Ooh!
Will this do?
Piss off.
Come on, mate.
Look at this. He was a pro.
He did a much better job
than you could ever do
and it didn't cost you a cent.
Go home.
Come on, mate. Are we square?
Look, I've taken my beating.
Come on. Barney, are we quits?
Come on, mate. Are we cool? Huh?
Ohh.
Thank you for coming.
You're welcome.
Can I ask why you came?
One good deed, you know?
When did I ever do a good deed?
Rumour has it
there have been one or two.
Does Harry-sorry-David
know you're here?
No.
I slept with my best friend's wife.
I know.
How do you know?
How do you think?
Yeah.
Hi. It's me.
Who's ‘me'?
- Scarlet.
- Oh.
Welcome.
Jesus, Cleave!
What's going on?
Barney's kicked me out.
He said he couldn't
bear to look at me anymore,
that I was the one who fucked up
so I was the one who had to leave.
I had to leave my babies.
Listen, Red, I don't have any tea.
Um, this could be
some sort of a yeast extract.
Uh, I've actually gotta fly.
I've gotta get to work.
That's OK. I've cleared my day
so I'll just stay here, if that's OK.
Sure.
We're down here, blossom.
Lincoln's running five minutes late.
Right. Who's Lincoln?
He's briefing you
on the Chandler thing.
Don't tell me you walked
into another cupboard door.
Cupboard doors are the natural
enemy of the sw...swine.
Cleave, you alright?
Hay fever. Is ‘Lincoln'
this guy's first name or his surname?
Uh...the correspondence
is still unclear. It could be both.
Let me just... Hang on.
It's a DVD, yeah?
Yeah, I've hit ‘DVD'. I've hit ‘AV',
I've hit ‘DVD', I've hit ‘Pr List'.
Good, good. Don't hit it.
NICOLE! What? It...
Ohh,
Jesus Christ, on a bicycle!
You are fucking kidding me.
Oh-ho-ho-ho! No. Ohh.
Oh, my sweet sainted aunt.
Have you got a copy
of the record of interview?
I was sure I had it with me.
[...must have left it at the office.
Well, it's sort of important,
don't you think?
You might want to get your secretary
to fax it through
or email it or something.
Uh, no. She's, um...
she's not in today.
She found out her sister
has a...a lump.
I don't mean to sound
uncaring or anything...
Hold on a minute. Yes, I do.
Have you at least read
the record of interview? Lincoln?
Mr Lincoln?
Yes. Yeah. I've read it.
Yes?
Like...yeah.
Well, he...
At first what he initially...
He initially denies
that it is he in the room.
Oh, itis he. It is he. I know he.
He delivered my son
and about 12,000 of my godchildren.
Oh, well, perhaps that's why
he requested you as counsel.
He then goes on to tell the police
that, yes, he was in the room,
but that the room was in Canada...
..and therefore he's committed
no crime under New South Wales law.
Canada.
What the hell is he talking about?
I could see the Opera House
out of your window, Bruce.
It's as clear as day.
There's a copy of the ‘Sydney
Morning Herald' on your coffee table.
I panicked.
You didn't do yourself any favours.
Listen, Cleaver. Cleaver.
All Jan and I care about is Bec,
you understand?
Whatever happens to me,
she'd be lost without Jan
and Jan would be lost without her.
Jan hasn't been charged yet.
And it has to stay that way.
Well, what exactly have you told Bec?
Well, uh, I was with a prostitute
and I'd been taking drugs.
Mate, look, I'm usually
not one to be defeatist,
but it's only a matter of time
before everyone knows it was Jan.
You've seen the DVD.
We were masked!
Bruce, it's your house and
your mask falls off YOUR face
for eight and a half
exceptionally visible seconds.
I know that, but Jan's... The other
woman's mask didn't come off.
Let's...let's forget about
the mask for a minute, OK?
Forget about the mask.
You and the “other woman”
were having a three-way
with the family dog, alright?
Masks are the least
of my problem at the moment.
Bruce, drinks.
The prosecution's gonna
want to see receipts, Bruce.
- They will want the...
- the hooker.
I paid cash. I don't know her name.
I picked her up off the street.
What, you just happened
to pick up a hooker
who was happy to take it
from a rottweiler?
Mate, it doesn't work that way.
Believe me.
That is a job for a specialist.
I picked her up off the street,
we took a combination of drugs...
Bruce.
..and things got out of hand.
It wasn't Jan!
Then why is she
standing by her man, huh? Why?
Why wasn't she on the first
Greyhound out of town
when this thing came to light?
Please, Cleaver.
The woman I was with
was a prostitute.
It wasn't Jan.
Bless you.
Are you alright?
Am I alright?
And finally I want to assure you
that if I am selected as
Labor Party candidate for this seat,
it will be my honour
to fight for you.
And as some of you may be aware,
I am not one
to back away from a fight.
Thank you.
Good.
So Sussex Street wants to parachute
in another celebrity candidate,
someone who's their own man,
someone whose vote they can control.
Mr Potter has spent
his working life as a tax lawyer.
I spent my working life
as an electrician.
Mr Potter spends his time
helping the big end of town
evade their responsibilities.
I've had 15 years experience
on the Leichhardt council,
serving the community.
If anyone can fend off
the Greens at the next poll,
it's a local who knows the issues,
not some Macquarie Street blow-in
backed by the machine.
We might have to go
a bit retail on this one, mate.
The electrician will trump
the tax lawyer every time.
I thought it was
going to be uncontested.
What can we say?
The Labor Party's a democracy.
Well, at least it has
to be seen to be one
until an actual decision
needs to be made.
So what? Jack Fulton's
a threat? NOT a threat?
Oh, look, I don't think
we need to worry about him.
He's just a hardworking local who's
worked his way up through the ranks.
He hasn't got a chance.
Still...
Still?
Well, Jack's a tough customer.
25 years, he's been an active member
of the Electrical Trades Union.
I mean, you're not even
a union member, are you, Dave?
He's been selling raffle tickets
at every branch meeting
since Gough Whitlam was a boy.
Do you know what they say in
the Boy Scouts, Davo? “Be prepared.”
Hi.
Hey.
I got us some chicken from Deluca.
Was it a little wrinkled?
On my return,
I went to turn on your oven,
which, of course,
was a fool's errand
because on opening it, I did
discover it is in fact a library.
Well, that may well be the case, Red,
but I won't have a word
said against this iron.
This iron has heated up many a fine
casserole for me over the years.
How do you live like this?
By setting it on ‘Cottons'.
I'll be a sec.
You want some wine?
Please.
Didn't you move in here
after Wendy kicked you out?
Uh...yeah.
Cleave, that was 11 years ago.
Really?
I thought this was
just a temporary thing
until you found your own place.
Itis.
Well, here's to long nights
on slow trains.
Cheers.
Speaking of moving in,
is that what this is, Red?
Um, ‘cause, you know, I've been
thinking. There's your sister.
Yeah, well,
Alex's parents are in town.
Oh, yeah. What about a hotel?
Or a motel?
Or a YWCA or a bus shelter
or a park bench?
Anywhere but here.
Come on, Red.
What if Barney finds out?
He dropped me here.
Red, Red, Red.
Don't!
This had to happen for a reason.
You and I, that night.
It had to be for a reason.
It did happen for a reason —
because we were drunk
and miserable and lonely.
Oh, I won't have that.
I won't... won't lose
my house and my family
just for one miserable drunken fuck.
It's too easy. It's way too easy.
Where the fuck is my bag?
You know what?
Even after Barney and I
were married,
you still kept flirting with me,
you still used to give me that look.
What look?
You know the look!
What are you talking about, Red?
I only have one look with women.
Yeah, that's your problem.
Red, come on, come on. Red, Red.
Red, it's OK.
Come on. It's OK.
Come on. Drop them.
You don't have to leave.
So I'm guessing “Be prepared”
means we better start to think about
finding some dirt on Jack Fulton.
No, in the ALP,
“Be prepared” means “We already
have some dirt on Jack Fulton.”
What?
23 seconds into
your political career
and you're already
going Karl Rove on me.
I thought you were meant to be
one of those rare honest ones.
Oh, come on. Since when does
“Be prepared” mean “Be dishonest?”
You know what Joe and Gav are like.
Yeah, Joe and Gav
live in the real world.
They've been doing this for years.
That is such bullshit.
This is your campaign, David,
your name, your responsibility.
Hold on.
Do you honestly believe
that Jack isn't out there right now
trying to dig up dirt on me?
It's the way of the world.
And you want to be
a part of this world?
Look, I've been given
an opportunity, alright?
It's a once-in-a-lifetime thing.
Now, Joe's got it all figured out —
a couple of terms in
Macquarie Street and then Canberra.
Who knows what then, OK?
I can do this. Joe thinks
I can do it with him backing me.
The higher you get,
the deeper they'll dig.
Well, that's the price you pay.
I'm not prepared to pay it.
I didn't mean you.
But it will mean me, won't it?
Well, who cares? I mean, Jesus,
what have you got to hide?
That's not the point.
Well, what is the point?
I'm a very private person.
You said you were OK
with me going into politics.
Yeah, well, I'm beginning
to have second thoughts.
Well, it's a bit bloody late.
Can I come up?
Uh, you know those lines
in the sand you keep drawing...
I've left David.
Really?
I think so, yeah.
Right, and you've got
nowhere else to go?
I've got plenty of places to go.
It's just I wanted to see YOU.
Oh.
Have you got company?
Yeah. Yes, I do, as a matter of fact.
Shit. Sorry.
Silly idea. Sorry.
Missy!
Come back, come back. It's alright.
She's just a mate. Come on.
We'll just have to be quiet.
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
Uh, you two have met,
I seem to recall.
Hi.
What do you mean,
David's too good for you?
Just that.
Yes, just that, Red, alright?
It's a thing. I've read about this.
It's documented.
It's a kind of goodness imbalance
that happens in
a lot of relationships
and more often than not it's fatal.
Oh, what rot!
Listen to me. David's
an exceptionally good guy.
I mean, how can that be a negative?
Oh, it's getting late.
I'm talking to Melissa.
Are you... What?
Are you unfulfilled?
I mean...
No, no, the sex is great.
Red, you're looking really tired.
It's been a big day for all of us.
So, to summarise,
David is a good guy.
He's great-looking,
he's smart, terrific in bed...
God, are you out of your mind?
What? What is it?
I used to be a prostitute, Scarlet.
Oh.
Melissa?
As in...this is Missy?
Small world, huh?
What the hell, Jan?
What is he doing in here?
Sit!
Oh, he was so lonely outside.
We talked about this.
We agreed. We promised we wouldn't.
He was crying.
He doesn't understand.
Oh, come on, darling.
Don't be silly now.
Silly? This isn't silliness, Jan.
This is our life.
Everything we have has been
built on my good name
which has been more
than a little sullied
by having been caught
buggering the family hound!
Darling, you can't go on like this.
Like what?
What's happening to us is real.
It's not a minor setback.
It's not silly.
You can't keep believing that
everything will be the same.
Bruce?
Darling.
How did we get to this place?
I was a Rhodes scholar.
I brought thousands of children
into the world.
I believe I've been
a good and loving father.
And yet for the rest of my life,
I will be known for one thing
and one thing only.
No, I won't have that.
You're still a marvel of a man.
Whatever they say,
you are still the kindest,
the most decent and loving man.
l, um...
..I think I'm going to tell Cleaver
to change my plea to guilty.
What?!
A trial will only make things
worse for you and Bec. It will.
Don't be ridiculous!
You've done nothing wrong.
We are going to fight this thing
and you're going to be acquitted.
Now come back to bed.
You're being silly. Come on.
Even if I am acquitted, you...
..you have to realise
that our lives as we know them
are over, my love.
It's over.
Ohh!
Oh, fuck!
What the f...
- Yeah.
- It's me.
Is Fuzz there?
He hasn't texted or anything?
No. I thought I was
persona non grata.
God. He's with her. He has to be.
Well, then we know he's safe.
Not with that woman, he isn't.
Well, why don't you go round
to her place and find out?
I did. She must have moved.
OK, here. Have a drop of this.
You look like a nervous wreck.
Oh, I haven't slept for 36 hours.
Jesus!
Mm, she...she's a succubus.
I thought she was born in July.
Don't you dare be glib about this.
I'm not being glib.
You know, we tried being heavy
and that didn't work.
He's still a boy.
We're gonna have
to change tack at some stage.
He's gonna be 16
in a couple of weeks.
I don't care what the law says,
Cleaver. He's our son!
At some point, he's going to need
to see some moral leadership.
Yeah.
Who is in your bed with Scarlet?
Uh, who is... Oh, yeah,
that would be my friend Missy.
I may have mentioned her
a couple of times.
Oh.
Hello, mate. This is your
sometime-father here.
Um, your mother and I are
a little worried about you.
We assume you're with Fiona.
Could you at least
confirm that's the case.
We don't want to cause a fuss.
I may deserve to suffer, mate,
but your mum doesn't, OK?
See ya.
Yeah.
So what's the story with these two?
Oh, well, the presidential suite
at the Intercontinental
was taken by Lady Gaga so...
..we just had to make do.
I'm not, uh...I'm not doing the deed.
I know. I can tell.
That's what's so funny.
Good.
Oh, yes, yes. He's fine.
He's with her.
He's gonna see you in the morning.
Would you like a bit more?
Mm, I shouldn't.
Are you kidding?
I was desperate to go.
I would have winged myself to
Melbourne to meet Michael Hutchence.
Cleaver didn't want to go.
He cannot stand the idea
of being in a room
and not being the man with
the highest testosterone level.
Barney and I, we took him
to see the Dalai Lama once
and we got invited backstage
and Cleaver just stood in the corner.
He couldn't even
go near the Dalai Lama.
Oh, and here he is.
- Morning.
I was thinking ‘Witches of Eastwick'
for a minute,
but then I realised
it was a bit more ‘Macbeth'.
Hi, Cleave!
Beasts, how are we all, huh?
Barney's got an abscess
in one of his teeth
so he had to drop them over.
So I see. Ohh! Oh, yes. Good.
Well, the more, the merrier, I say.
I gotta pee, Cleave.
What's that under your nose?
Oh, well, I was trying
to brush my teeth
and I missed my mouth and hit
my nose, and it's all your fault!
It's your fault!
It's your fault, you little pest.
Oh, Alice, where's the rosemary
hiding, sweetheart?
Um, I'll... just...
Branch warfare has
broken out today in the ALP...
Counting really good, Max.
Really good.
Hello.
Hey.
..an affair with Greens MP
Lenore Harris.
Mr Fulton and Miss Harris have both
been referred to ICAC.
for misusing council resources...
One day? You couldn't
even wait one lousy day?
Where are you?
The poor bastard
didn't even have a chance!
I have been worried blind.
Come home, please.
Hold on a minute.
In 2007, Lenore Harris and I had
an affair lasting several months...
Why are the children still here?
Barney's still not very well,
apparently.
I need some time to think.
I betrayed my wife and family
at the worst possible...
- What's the time, Mr Wolf?
- Go, go, go, go, go!
Boy Wonder?
What's the deal?
[... don't know, Cleave.
I just don't see how it can work.
Oh, that poor man!
Who?
Jack Fulton.
I mean, he just made one mistake
and courtesy of the party machine,
his past came back to haunt him.
Please don't mistake this for
me being compassionate or anything,
but you really need to either
tell David the truth
or end it.
I know.
If you think you can keep a secret in
this town, you're out of your mind.
But, look, if you need a distraction,
I could use a hand at the moment.
I've got this doggy case on.
The solicitor is a complete mutt
and I need a good retriever
I can rely on.
Oh, my God.
Oh! Oh, my... Oh, God!
I thought you'd seen everything
and done everything.
Oh, make it stop!
It's amazing, you know —
when I first saw it,
I was reaching for a bucket too,
but after about 50 times, it's a bit
like watching ‘Itchy and Scratchy'.
Who are these people?
Well, that's Dr Bruce Chandler...
Actually, do you know a girl
called Bec Chandler?
She'd be about a year
ahead of you at law school.
So?
That's her dad.
Thanks. It'll only
be for a few nights.
Yeah. I'll just get the kids settled.
Jules is going away so I can have
her place while I work things out!
Oh.
Don't you want to stay here?
I don't know what I want
at the moment, Cleave.
Hey, Bec! Come on,
give us a smile, will ya?
That's it. Give us a smile!
Come on, Bec. Come on.
Woof, woof, woof, woof!
Bark for me, baby.
Bark for me, baby. That's it.
Come on, come on...
Hey, do you mind?
Oh, I'm so sorry!
Ohh! Fuck.
Thanks.
It was my pleasure. Believe me.
Do you know why
he was taking those pictures?
‘Cause of your father?
You know, it's not that unusual, Bec.
What isn't?
There are lots of good people
into weird shit.
What?
Everyone's into something, Bec.
Tits, undies, hair, shoes,
back, front, black, white,
pure, dirty, leather, rubber, SMBD.
Trust me. They've run out of letters.
What are you saying?
I'm saying that sex
can be totally separate
to the rest of someone's personality,
particularly men.
You can be a good employee,
a wonderful parent,
you can devote your life
to those less fortunate...
You can be any and all
of these things, Bec,
and still have a dirty little secret,
which for all practical purposes has
no bearing on the rest of your life,
so long as that dirty little secret
is adult and consensual
and nobody gets hurt
more than they really want to be.
By the way, I'm working
for your father.
I'll just be another 10, darling.
Dad.
Oh, sweetheart.
Can you explain it to me?
What possible explanation
could I give
that would be satisfactory
to you, really?
OK.
Why was Mum so quick to forgive you?
Well, she's a...
..she's a very forgiving person,
your mum.
Are you protecting her?
Don't be absurd. Of course not.
How could you possibly believe
that Mum would be involved...
I don't know what
to believe anymore, Dad.
Oh, darling.
Arggh!
So, Dr D'Antonio, we've heard
a lot from the prosecution
about the dog Felix's lack of ability
to consent to the acts that were
recorded in exhibit A-1.
As a professor of animal
behavioural psychology,
what would you say
are the traditional signs
that a male rottweiler is up for sex?
Um, well, the classical signs
are an erection, obviously,
panting, salivating, wagging tail.
I see.
But as I wrote in ‘Nature', June 2006,
despite the fact that consent is not
an issue that crosses a dog's mind,
it should not be taken for granted
that we humans therefore
are free to do as we please.
There is a moral dimension.
A moral dimension?
Certainly.
We abhor paedophiles.
In those cases, consent
is not an issue either.
Consent for human beings
is not an issue up to the age of 16
because the law says
the consent must be informed.
Jesus, did you really write that?
Oh, no.
Oh, she's gonna
compare him to a paedophile.
Almost certainly.
She's made the comparison in
at least six articles I could find.
Magic fucking word.
You want a conviction,
throw the word ‘paedophile'
in front of a jury in any context.
God. She got any religious
affiliations or anything?
She goes to church.
Right, but no sort of nut bag thing
we can throw at the old bitch?
“Old bitch”?
She's 35 and this is the photo from
the dust jacket of her latest book.
Ooh, hello.
I don't want to cross-examine her.
I want her phone number.
If I were the prosecution,
I would just hand out
sick bags to the jury
and make them watch that DVD,
get them worked up,
get them scared, you know?
As soon as they put
on that bloody DVD...
Maybe we shouldn't
be afraid of the DVD.
I mean, like you said,
after you see it 50 times,
you become immune.
So, what? Just play it
and play it and play it?
Maybe.
Oh.
I may have come up with a way
to minimise the times the jury
has to look at that DVD.
Oh, yeah.
But if we turn to frame 379...
Mr Greene, really.
The jury has already
watched this footage 13 times.
With great respect, Your Honour,
they have not seen it in slow motion,
nor frame-by-frame.
Frame-by-frame?
Your Honour, this DVD
is the prosecution's case.
It would be,
in my respectful submission,
most prejudicial
to my client's defence
if the jury did not become
intimately acquainted
with the act of which
he's being accused.
Very well.
As you can see, there's
an unknown prostitute
sitting naked but for her face mask.
Then, uh, Felix enters frame,
salivating, his tail bobbing about,
his eagerness to participate
evidenced by a very
impressive erection.
Oh, and look — he's happily
wearing protective socks
presumably so as to not scratch
the unknown prostitute
with whom he's...
Yeah. And there he goes.
Frame 32,875.
As you can see, Felix's tail
is still bobbing around.
Frame 32,876.
Oh, the lighting here is very good.
And again if we turn to 86,426...
..as you can see,
Felix's tail is still wagging about,
he's still enjoying
the loving embraces
of his master
and an unknown prostitute.
Your Honour,
these constant references
to an “unknown prostitute”...
Yes,
I'm with you, Ms Habib.
Can I see counsel
in chambers, please?
We'll take 15 minutes.
All rise.
What's going on, Cleave?
We all know it's Mrs Chandler.
My instructions are
that on December 27,
Mrs Chandler was watching the cricket
with her mother in Rose Bay.
Ken, it's an insult to the court.
Nadia, if you've got the evidence against
them, why haven't you charged her?
Do I have to do
your job for you as well?
When he gets in the box
I'll ask him about her
and if he's lying
I'll have him for perjury as well.
OK, my instructions
are the doctor and Mrs Chandler
love their daughter Rebecca very much
and wish her a long and happy life.
Come on, guys. Give the kid a break.
So, Dr D'Antonio, do you equate
the act my client is accused of
with the act of paedophilia?
Yes, I would, as a matter of fact.
In a moral sense?
Yes.
So children and dogs,
they're pretty much the same to you?
Objection.
Mr Greene.
Your Honour.
Uh, Doctor, do you believe
the life of an animal
equates to the life of a human being?
We are all animals, Mr Greene.
I know I'm all animal, Dr D'Antonio.
Doctor, do you value
the life of a dog or a sheep
or a guinea pig
as much as you value human life?
I believe we've erred
in creating classes of people,
classes of animals.
It's affected our values, it's
affected the way we run the planet.
Please answer the question, Doctor.
Yes.
I don't see why a dog's life
should be less valuable
than a human's life.
I see.
Doctor, I put it to you that your
views on animal welfare are extreme
and uncharacteristic of
current thinking on the subject.
I reject that.
So you think that a dog should
be able to vote and drive a car?
You're being ridiculous, Mr Greene.
I don't think a dog should be forced
to have sex against his or her will.
Let's have another look
at the DVD, then, shall we?
I'd encourage you, Doctor,
to show me the exact moment,
or moments,
where you feel that Felix
is being forced or coerced
or even encouraged.
There we go.
Bec? Bec, what are you doing?
My father's on trial in there.
You don't want to go in there.
‘Cause of my mother?
Is she the other woman?
No.
Swear it wasn't
my mother in that room.
You should know I'm an atheist,
so swearing really won't...
Was it my mother? Please.
No, it's a prostitute.
How can you be so sure?
Her name's Wendy Brenner. She works
in a brothel called Club Jules.
Animals are her speciality.
I have her number if you want it.
How do you know all this?
It's my job.
So where did you pick up
this prostitute, Dr Chandler?
Well, I rang a brothel
and I asked if there were any girls
that specialised in...
..that sort of thing.
I see.
And how much did you pay
for this...specialisation?
$3,000.
No further questions.
Australians as a nation
have always rooted for the underdog.
Ladies and gentlemen, the truth is
my client didn't hurt anyone or anything.
Under New South Wales law,
the maximum sentence I can get
for poisoning a water supply
is five years,
but having sex with Felix,
the rottweiler with a waggly tail,
allows for a sentence of 14 years.
Now, Peter Singer —
considered the founding father
of the animal rights movement —
has himself stated
that having sex with animals
does not necessarily involve cruelty.
The prosecution keep
banging on about consent,
but do horses consent
to being ridden around a track,
having their backsides whipped?
Do rabbits consent to being tested
for something Posh Spice
dabs on her pulse points?
46 million families in America
own at least one dog...
..and this year they're going to cook
roughly 27 billion pounds of beef
sliced from some 35 million
harmless, sweet, vegetarian cows.
It's a devastating hypocrisy.
Ladies and gentlemen,
how many of you here own a dog
but love a T-bone?
Members of the jury,
have you reached a verdict?
Yes, Your Honour.
What say you?
We the jury find the defendant
not guilty.
- Thank you. Anything else?
- No, Your Honour.
See, this scares me because I thought
he was completely screwed.
How do you feel?
Pretty pumped.
Hello.
Ah. Joe Sandilands. Can you talk?
Yeah.
Good, good. Look, um,
I just got off the phone from David.
He sounds pretty low, Miss.
So?
Look, I don't think you realise
how hard this is for him.
He didn't want to go
Karl Rove on Jack,
but we gave him no other choice.
Bravo.
Come on, Miss.
You know he's crazy about you.
Look, the system
is morally bankrupt.
That is why we need
people like David.
Without them, how do you think
it's ever gonna change?
Isn't that why you got into
politics, Joe? To change things?
I forget.
Right. Got it. We're off.
Where do you wanna go?
You know what? I'm beat.
No. Really?
Yeah. Another time?
‘D' is for ‘Dog'. ‘Dog'.
I love you so much.
I'm so sorry.
Shh, shh, shh.
It's not your fault.
Oh, itis.
http://hiqve.com/