Bosoms don't have to be big.
Surely the great test of a democracy
is its enduring ability
to handle truth.
That's not what it's about for me.
They can be small and pert.
When the Athenian Draco
began to wrestle with
the inherent difficulties posed by
the notion of democracy in 631 BC,
he set forward a series of propositions
that have reverberated
over the brutal passage
of the past 2,500 years.
It's about the nipple.
We in the Western world
still struggle to understand
all that the term ‘democracy' entails.
No, correction.
It's more than that.
It's about the areola.
When Western governments
stifle information
in the pretence they are
protecting democracy,
when through
the uncritical gaze of media
they extol the need for secrecy
and covert operation,
then bit by bit
we erode the very fundamentals
of free and open government.
I love the dark bit
around the nipple.
Sometimes it isn't dark.
Sometimes it's more pink.
I don't like that as much.
I am effectively
charged with treason,
‘heresy' in the language
of the Spanish Inquisition,
where this trial rightly belongs.
Treason because I chose to release
so-called top secret information.
Only top secret because
they didn't want the public to know
of the lies and the deceit
that they were trying to conceal.
I could have fought extradition,
but I chose not to.
I have come home voluntarily,
not only to defend these charges
but to defend democracy,
and if that is a crime...
then hang me.
Josh, do you think
you'll get a fair trial?
Thank you.
Care to accompany me to the police
station for my twice daily weigh-in?
Oh, Josh, that's
just what I had in mind.
We going the right way?
“If that is a crime then hang me”?
It's pretty butch, right?
You are the consummate wanker.
Oh! Come on, remind me not to
call you as a character witness.
They will call me, won't they?
Mm-hm.
Ex-prostitute, political contacts.
They're gonna throw
everything they can at us, huh?
Bet on it.
If I do end up going to prison
for the rest of my natural life,
at least you can write another
warts-and-all novel about it.
You'll make millions.
Left.
What is this place?
A portal to a lion's den
somehow springs to mind.
I wouldn't be surprised.
Yeah?
It wasn't as though
I was touching the nipples.
I was metres away each time.
That's not a crime, is it?
I think you'll find, Alistair,
that being a peeping Tom
does actually infringe the democratic
rights of other free citizens,
particularly those with pouting,
or even sagging, breasts.
Would you mind waiting outside
for a minute
while I go over the nuances of
this matter with Mr Lincoln Lincoln?
Sure.
Where's the file?
There is, um, a tad of confusion
with the paperwork.
Yes, well, unless that fella
is a 53-year-old mother of two,
there would appear
to be some confusion.
I think that that is a photograph
of the woman whose breasts were...
I think it might be useful
for the case
if we have the file
of the accused.
No, that's exactly right.
No, it's either right
or it's not right.
It's either exact or it's inexact.
The combination of the two words
doesn't make it either
more right or more exact.
That's very true, isn't it?
Alistair. Eyes up.
Yeah.
Lincoln is gonna let you know
when we have a date.
I've given Mr Emery the date.
Oh.
There's no trial date yet.
OK, then, I won't. But I will.
Do you want a hand there?
Oh, no, thanks.
I haven't sealed it yet.
Thanks.
Uh, shall we, Mr Emery?
Um...just watch the...
Yeah. Yeah.
Sorry.
No.
Have we found a new home yet?
No, we haven't!
What else have we got on
apart from the areola-philiac?
A couple of parole violations,
AVO application,
another flasher, burglary.
Armed?
No, afraid not.
Oh.
Oh, here we are.
Got a nice little bashing.
Oh, and it's grievous.
Great.
No money in the light ones.
Sally! Come out and talk to me!
I have rights! It was my child too!
Sally, please, just talk to me!
Fuzz! For Christ's sake,
can you shut up?
You're humiliating us
in front of the whole neighbourhood.
What's happening?
Sally! I love you!
Do you hear me?!
Everyone except her can hear you.
You OK?
It's OK. It's fine.
Go back inside.
He's just having a drug episode.
No, I'm bloody well not!
It's better they think
you're a normal 18-year-old
with normal problems.
You tried to bash her door in
when you found out.
I had cause!
Did you know she was
having an abortion?
Oh, God! What did you expect
she was going to do? Grow up, Fuzz!
She's a divorced mother of two
and you haven't even finished school!
OK! Mum, we had a connection.
We could have worked it through.
Oh, yeah, you could have
bought a small farm
and grown organic alpacas
and raised cushions.
Stop being weird.
Why can't you at least
get a girl your own age pregnant?
You're worried about
what they think?
They all think you're pathetic.
Sally!
Yell all you like.
She's gone to Byron.
SALLY!
Oh, he's single again,
if you're interested.
Mr Greene, I believe
you're representing yourself?
Yes, that's right.
I am capable of that.
Others need a lot more help.
As I say, let's try and
keep it constructive, shall we?
Mr McManus, would you
like to kick off?
Yes, the facts are as outlined...
The facts are that this man,
probably through a deep personal sense
of self-loathing and failure,
shamelessly lied and defamed me
in a blog and on radio.
Failure! Failure!
Before he ran off to the safety
of the stalls at State Parliament,
this cock was a hack tax lawyer,
for Christ sakes.
I'm hearing a lot
of emotional language here.
Please let Mr Potter make his case.
He doesn't have one.
This asexual pontificating clown
slandered me and I responded in kind.
I underestimated, however,
the sensitivity
of his emotional condition...
Please, Mr Greene.
You are a pathetic, alcoholic,
drug-addled excuse of a man,
a tragic example of everything
gone wrong in the legal profession...
Yes, and I don't think that's
particularly helpful, either.
He is beyond help.
To invest any effort in him
is a waste of breath.
Shall we recalibrate here?
Recalibrate away, love.
Unless you can do it with
mime or picture cards,
he won't understand it.
Well, I'm sorry our mediation process
has been cut off at the nuts.
Looks like you'll be paying
your circus monkey
for a while longer, mate.
What?
This one's on the house, Cleave.
Oh, Tom!
Mate!
And here's the Canadian survey
on mandatory sentencing.
It's a few years old.
Yeah, read it.
Same conclusion as
the British study, right?
It's never worked anywhere.
You know the Yanks jailed
a 17-year-old kid for life
for stealing a can of soft drink?
I mean, three strikes
and you're out. It's madness.
Hold on.
I thought I was in for
an all-in brawl with you on this.
On mandatory sentencing?
Uh-huh.
No. The evidence is in.
It doesn't work.
Hey, Engels, what do you make of
this Joshua Floyd business?
Oh, um...
Well, as a civil libertarian,
I'm torn.
If what he leaked endangers lives,
I don't know.
Yeah, but he's got a point,
though, hasn't he?
I mean, all this bloody secrecy
over bugger all, really.
The public already know
we're a bunch of liars and frauds.
Why not make it official?
Still, bloody glad
it's not our fight.
Col.
Very, very bad news,
I'm afraid, mate.
What's that?
Kirsty's father passed away.
She's very upset.
Oh, that's t...that's...
Bummer.
She was an only child,
so they were really, really close.
Terrific bloke.
We shared many a laugh over
a coldie, always up for a yarn.
I'm gonna order some flowers
straightaway.
Nicole!
She's your woman, mate.
You need to be by her side now.
She is hurtin'.
And I will be by her side, mate.
It's just, you know, tomorrow's...
Maybe I can move my 9am.
You can move them all before
I move every organ in your body.
Consider it done.
Look. Look, there he is
with me when I was five.
A fine, fine-looking man.
No, that's a farmhand.
That's him there.
Even better-looking.
That's our farm,
and that was my pony, Wingo.
A magnificent animal.
His real name was Ringo, but when
I was little I couldn't say my ‘R's,
and so Daddy said to me, he said,
“It's alright, love...Wingo he is.”
Too many memories.
Too many to count.
So...
So, I guess the farm's yours now?
No, no.
After all that...
after all that shit with Mick,
Daddy said to me, “You know, I know
you've got your own dreams, love.
‘I know you're not gonna
want to run the farm,”
and so he sold it
and he gave me all the money.
That's the sort of man he was.
So, he sort of willed it to you
before he died.
Is that right?
I can't believe
you're asking us this.
The gall is gobsmacking,
even by your standards.
It's common practice.
More than that, it's common sense.
He isn't dead.
And thank God for that.
But how can you possibly
claim your share of his estate
if he isn't dead?!
Look...Dad loves us, alright?
He wants us to be happy.
I'm gonna get a third anyway,
and it just so happens that I have
a great need right at the moment,
and so if I could just
get an advance on that.
Not all of it, just enough to
get me out of a temporary bog.
You keep pissing your life
up against a wall, don't you, Cleaver?
I will discount my share.
And what about the money
we spend on him while he is alive?
That's the beauty of the discount.
Cleaver, he hasn't
left you anything.
“Lily and Jane, thank you
for being such a comfort to me
“in difficult times.
“To you, I leave my house
“and any cash in whatever
accounts I may have,
“and I also leave you
all my shares.”
Well...yeah, he's gotta...
Does he mention me somewhere?
“To Cleaver, I leave you my watch.
‘I have given you
a lot in life, son,
“and you have earned a great deal
of money in your career
“and have been given
ample opportunity.
“Know that I love you
and still hope...still hope
‘you can make something...
better of your life.”
I told him that
I thought it was unfair.
Cleave, he does love you.
It's just that he pinned
SO many hopes on you and...
OK, this is worse than
the grilling I got from ASIO.
Who's grilling? I'm just asking.
You saw her yesterday.
Why is it necessary for her
to join us here tonight?
Your past is littered
with way more baggage than mine.
My God, woman,
you wrote a book about it.
Yes, but it's in the past.
As is Therese.
We divorced five years ago.
Our time together's precious.
Well, listen,
if it wasn't for Therese,
good plumbing probably
wouldn't even exist.
She raised a lot of money.
She still is.
I don't wanna argue. We don't even
know how many more nights we have.
I don't wanna spend it arguing.
OK, don't overplay
the life behind bars thing.
It loses impact.
Hmm.
So when am I gonna meet
Cleaver Greene?
This ex-great love of yours?
Stop saying that.
And just for the record... Oh.
How great. She's early.
I'm really tired.
I don't think I'll read
the rest of those submissions.
OK.
What?
Nothing.
Fine.
There's no reading.
No reading, then.
Let's have another month
without reading.
You can if you want to.
No, it's fine.
Barn, if you wanna have sex...
Who said anything about sex?
No, I wanna read.
I wanna read all night.
Long and hard and deep.
Oh, God, I'm coming. I'm coming!
on
LAUGHS)
Oh. Oh.
Oh, I'm feeling so many emotions
right now, you know,
like, um, oh, God, grief and joy
and, oh, shit, maybe even love.
Oh.
Kirsty, uh, we really need to talk.
What?
I'm just worried that
things between us are...
Are what? What?
Come on, tell me.
No, just that they're...
..too good.
Aw.
You know, the last time I ever felt
like this about anyone, you know,
it was when...it was when Mick...
Yeah, got put away for chopping
your lover up into bite-sized chunks
and burying him under asphalt.
Mmm. I don't think
I could go through that again.
And that sentiment does you
no end of credit, Kirsty.
Oh, thank you.
Really.
But the thing is...
..we just...we come from
such different worlds, you know?
I mean, I move in such weird,
tricky little circles.
Yeah.
I'm just worried that
that's gonna destroy us both.
You're right.
I am, arent I?
Yeah.
Dammit.
We'll just have to introduce
each other to each other's worlds.
When the Athenian Draco
began to wrestle with
the inherent difficulties posed by
the notion of democracy in 631 BC,
he set forward a series
of propositions...
Draco the Athenian. Fuck me.
Joshua, the interminable wanker.
Wendy?
Hi. Sorry to call. I just...
Fuzz has flipped out again.
He found out she had an abortion.
Who, Sally?
No, my mother.
Yes, of course bloody Sally.
She's gone to Byron, so at least
I'm not gonna be a grandmother
to a woman who's nearly
a year older than me.
Well, um, technically you were
never actually gonna be that,
but that's a good result
then, isn't it?
Oh, he's blaming me,
you, the universe.
Want me to come over?
No, it's alright.
I just wanted to talk to you.
Oh, well, at least
he knows we adore him.
That's gotta count
for something, hasn't it?
Yeah, well, we can love him
all we like,
but he's still kicking in doors.
Do you remember
how you felt when he was born?
Yeah.
Delirious.
He was such a happy baby.
Well, you know, I mean,
happiness is a pretty fluid
old concept these days.
I mean, it's basically
people sipping lattes, isn't it?
You know, every lifestyle ad
you see these days
has got a his or her professional
chugging down a latte.
You know, we've got
no other fucking vision of happiness,
save pouring frothy milk
over the top of beans
picked by indentured
12-year-old labour.
Have you got
someone there?
Yep, but, um, don't worry about it.
Why didn't you tell me?
Oh, no, it's...it's OK.
She's just a...woman
I owe some money to.
You heard Dr Anastasio's view
that in Alistair's loneliness
and lack of self-worth,
he emotionally fixated on the very time
that he felt safe and loved,
when he was suckling
on his mother's bosoms.
This is not about sex.
He never touched any of these women.
Spied on them, yes,
and maybe masturbated in public.
But these are symptoms
of a profound condition.
Mr Emery poses no threat
to society whatsoever.
He is a sick, sick man
and he needs treatment.
We do not lock up sick people,
we treat them.
He keeps going on about that.
Cleaver. Cleaver, there's
someone I want you to meet.
Ah.
Joshua, this is Cleaver.
Hi.
“We don't lock up sick people,
we treat them.”
Great stuff. Very entertaining.
Yes, well, I was gonna invoke
the ghost of the Athenian Draco,
but it felt — what's the word? —
pretentious?
Yeah, that's exactly what she said.
Excuse me.
Sean, mate.
Just give me a sec, will you?
Sorry, I have to take this.
Sean Penn's coordinating
some support for me in the States.
It was great meeting you.
Coordinate away.
Tell the Sean-meister
he owes me a grand from Vegas.
Well, your practice
is still flourishing, I see.
“Great stuff.
Really entertaining.”
What the fuck are you supposed to say
about a guy who jerks off over
the dark circles around nipples?
Maybe his dad was a big darts man.
So you gonna come tomorrow or not?
Remind me.
The lunch.
Come on, you're frightened
that you'll like him.
He's funny, he's rude,
he loves getting up people's noses.
There's gonna be some
seriously important people there.
Oh, sweetheart, you are
talking to an open door.
Will Sean be in attendance?
Let me just... I'll park the Prius.
I'll be right along.
You know what I think?
I think you dislike him
on the compelling principle
that he's fighting a truly noble cause
you wish you were fighting.
Sweetheart, no. No.
Thank you.
And you wonder why I describe you
as a child in my book.
Your name will be on the door.
Yeah, but, look, I've gotta go.
Alright, well, just email me
through everything,
then I'll have a look at it, OK?
OK, how'd that go?
Cal. What the hell is this?
I don't know. What is it?
“An inside source
said it is hotly rumoured
“that the Attorney-General
will introduce
‘mandatory sentencing legislation
in the life of this parliament.”
Here.
Fuck.
No photo.
Um, what happened to,
“Mandatory sentencing doesn't work.
“The evidence is in”?
It is in. It doesn't work.
Why wouldn't they print a photo?
Why did you have me running around
chasing up all those studies?
Oh, well, I have to counter
all arguments.
I mean, look, I don't like this
any more than you do,
but that's what the tabloids
tell the people that they want.
Right? That's the trouble with having
a bloody democracy and a free press.
Can't cope with both, Engels.
Fucking idiots.
They'd have thousands on file.
And it's still OK
if I come and watch you milk,
and grab a couple of litres and see
if we can make ice-cream with it.
What do you reckon?
This mob are exactly the kind
of self-sufficient smallholdings...
Get out of it.
Jesus Christ!
I hope you don't mind.
I had a key cut.
I've got a key for my apartment
to give to you as well.
Oh, beauty.
You know, I woke up this morning
and I said to myself,
“Kirsty Corella,
get a hold of yourself.
“Your daddy wouldn't want you
wallowing around in the blues.”
So I thought to myself, didn't I,
I thought what about...
what about a little lunch?
Ah. Oh, that'd be great, but I'm...I'm,
uh...I'm a bit busy, guys.
Actually...
What?
Do you know what?
Let's do it.
Come on, all work and no play.
Come on.
Let's go, I've got...
I've got the perfect venue for us.
Really?
Yeah.
We are going to have a blast.
“good plumbing”?
I know this prick.
This bastard sold
our country's secrets.
Let me guess which paper you read.
Yeah.
But it's gonna be full of celebs.
Like who?
Oh, they'll all be in here.
Russell's in there,
Nicole'll be in there.
The bald chef from the TV show
you're always talking about,
he'll be in there.
Draco the Athenian will be there.
Maybe you can get some autographs.
You've got quite a collection now.
This is very much
an autograph kind of an event.
If you wanna be a part of
my world, this is it.
Mate, am I dressed right for this?
Oh, mate, it's very much
come as you are. Yeah.
Excuse me, sir,
your name please?
Look, we're here
with the bridal party.
This is His Serene Highness, Prince Col
of Batavia, the Duchess Kirsty.
Yeah, OK, mate. Piss off outta here.
Well, let's...
Hi. Hi, you came.
Hi. I'm Melissa. Col, right?
Yeah, Col.
G'day.
Yes, I remember. Hi.
And?
Kirsty. Hi.
Yeah, I'm Cleaver's, um...
I suppose... Yeah, we're an item.
Terrific. Why don't you come in
and talk to Joshua?
Let's.
Shit. That is Magda, isn't it?
Over there.
That is Magda.
She seems nice.
She's, uh...she's extraordinary.
We're very much in love.
If you're trying to make a scene,
Josh won't give a rat's arse.
Hey, Cleaver.
I'm sorry. I've forgotten
your name already.
Oh, I'm hard
to avoid, aren't I?
Ted's here.
We'll talk.
Will we?
Historically, America
had the chance to back India,
but they were so fearful
of its ties to Russia,
they poured billions of dollars
in military aid into Pakistan instead.
They turned it
into a military dictatorship,
and India is a vibrant democracy.
It's the wrong intelligence,
and everyone bought the lie.
You give people all the facts
and we can make better choices.
It's exactly the same with
‘Dancing with the Stars'.
I think if everyone had have known
that Tina and Roy were dancers
before the competition,
it would have swayed public opinion.
Denise and Warwick were ROBBED.
Oh, I have to say, I thought
your article in ‘Harper's
about the reductive capacity
of media was exactly right.
Excuse me. Thanks, pal.
Ah, marvellous.
Oh, Kirsty — Russell!
Shit.
Col, drink up, mate.
The revolution's paying.
Melissa. You look
absolutely gorgeous.
Thanks, Therese. So do you.
Mind if I drag this man away?
It's time to earn his keep.
Excuse me, folks.
So, is he what you were expecting?
Ladies and gentlemen...
Ah...
I hate guys with two first names.
It is my privilege to present
our hero of the hour,
a man who faces
an eternity in prison
for defending the rights
of each and every person here,
a man who has always fought
government abuse of the individual.
I admire him more
than any other man I know,
despite the fact
he is my ex-husband.
Ladies and gentlemen, Joshua Floyd.
Yeah!
Thank you.
Well, look, I'm not worthy of all this,
I promise you that.
I leaked some documents.
If we'd waited long enough,
the public service would have
leaked all that shit by accident.
Mate, why do we drink beer, eh?
Be quicker to avoid the middle man
and pour it
straight down the toilet.
How familiar are you with these charges
they're hitting me with?
Not my area.
No?
Nuh.
But if you pressed me,
I'd say you're probably guilty.
Really?
Yeah.
Well, the whole point of the act
is to give the government
the power to lock up people
they don't like.
I mean, there's people
under this legislation
who've been arrested for wearing
inappropriate T-shirts at airports.
So, you know, they're gonna
get you for something.
Mmm.
Some might call it ‘draconian'.
I call it shit.
You should try being
on the receiving end.
Who's heading up your team?
Geoffrey?
No. He's a smart man,
but not what I'm chasing.
Well, who's your wig of choice, then?
Don't know.
You interested?
Oh, yes, very droll.
I'm serious.
I'm not a silk, mate.
That makes two of us.
You don't know anything about me.
I've asked around town.
Look, if the people you've asked
are lawyers, most of them hate me.
No, it's much worse than that, mate.
Almost every single one of them
described you as
“an intriguing choice”.
Is this a game?
If you don't want the gig...
No, I...
[-I'm not un...interested.
Good.
Then let's see
if we can make it work.
Your chambers?
Say, 11 tomorrow?
OK.
Cleave, Cleave,
can we go now, please?
Col's just had a bit of a thing
with Russell.
Oh, Jesus, quick.
Come on, let's go. He's coming.
Cleaver, come on. Let's go! Go!
What are you doing?
I'm packing the last of the boxes.
I told you we don't have a room as of 9.
Fuck!
What?
Fuck. OK.
OK, you've gotta find out
who's in court. Ask around the PAs.
Offer anyone who's got
a spare room 100 bucks
to get out at 11:00 for one hour.
We may have a new client.
Oh, what, rapist, thug or pederast?
Joshua Floyd.
Oh, very funny.
Joshua. Floyd.
I will build us chambers
if I cannot find one.
Mm-hm.
Cleave, they're coming
out of the lift.
Shit.
Mr Floyd.
Joshua, please.
Joshua, hi.
Hello, Melissa.
Hi, Nicole.
How are you?
Good.
Are you married yet?
No, five weeks. Five weeks to go.
How exciting.
Yeah.
I loved your book. That's
the best ever description of him.
Well, the child is waiting, so please,
just, um, come on through.
Welcome.
There are three main
areas of attack, I reckon.
There's at...there's at least
12 sections of the act
that are generally considered
to be loosely drafted
and open to interpretation.
Now, the good news is
that this is all virgin territory —
none of these sections
have ever been tested before.
Why do you think I'm here?
Early onset dementia?
Look, I can get any damn QC in
the world to make a good argument,
quote the act chapter and verse.
What I need is someone
who's prepared to play
outside of the rules.
Someone who can say ‘mammophile'
without flinching.
Who can bring the circus
and the carnival to court.
I need someone who can take
top secret, highly prejudicial evidence
and still get it before a jury,
someone who isn't frightened
to join me in a cell for a while.
Are you that guy?
Do I get top bunk?
Well, this one thinks you and I can
stop the world turning for a while.
Who's this?
Uncle...lan.
He's...he's just
a funny, funny uncle.
Do you remember him?
He's... And he's never aged.
He's...
What?
Cleave, Josh knows
you don't have chambers.
Oh, that's great.
You're what's known
as a floater, I believe.
I'm a floater.
Let's see what we can do
about that.
I'm told this trial
might run for a year.
At the least.
And it is gonna take you
completely out of action,
possibly damage
your...existing practice.
Well, I'll have to just suck that up.
Well, I have very wealthy backers
who believe passionately
in this cause.
We could offer you
a $6,000-a-day retainer.
That should be enough to establish
chambers of your own.
Starting from today, of course.
With me, it's never about the money.
Some of the world's leading lawyers
have offered their services,
and I am grateful,
but in the end, I have decided
to go with my heart.
Let the government tie up
every silk in the country —
they will need them.
I need only one man
to argue my case,
someone who has spent his career
fearlessly crusading for the rights
of ordinary people,
my friend, Cleaver Greene.
The other day,
Josh was talking about
the Athenian Draco's struggle
to define democracy.
I remember cheering at the TV
at the time.
Oh, someone please tell me
this is a fuckin' joke.
..an end to the great lies
of government,
to the pretence that our security
requires great cloaks of secrecy.
It does not.
Bit by bit, imperceptibly,
as our politicians and media
play on our darkest fears,
we are robbed of our freedom.
Josh, let me jump you forward
2,500 years from Draco
and quote Martin Luther King.
“Our lives begin to end
“the day we become silent
about the things that matter.”
Mr Greene, who will you
be calling for the defence?
Zazie got in trouble
for hitting Kyle.
I suppose you heard the news about
Cleaver and Joshua Floyd?
Yes, I did.
Mr Crichton says he's gonna
suspend him if he does it again.
He's bound to sack him.
It won't last.
Who knows?
You seriously think that
Joshua Floyd would put up
with Cleaver Greene?
Yes. Because he's
a brilliant choice.
And somewhere,
you know that as well.
Hey, Dad, Zazie says he's gonna get
his dad in to belt up Mr Crichton.
I suppose you wish you were
part of it too, don't you?
Would you pass the pepper, please?
And now you're blaming me.
The pepper?
Barney?
Yes, of course I fuckin'
wanna be a part of it.
Why did you say the F-word?
This is why I became
a lawyer, Scarlet.
This is why Cleaver
became a lawyer.
This is what we dreamed about
at uni, this exact sort of case.
But because of a mistake you made,
and because some shrink tells us
it's the only way to save
this chimera of a marriage...
..I'm not a part of it.
Don't let me stop you.
http://hiqve.com/
Ah! Here's Santa!
Oh, come on.
Mwah!
Oh, who's a good boy!
Who's a good boy?
Find the fucker. Where is the fucker?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Alright, alright.
Relax!
Ah, hang on. Yep, I've got it.
It's here, I've got it.
Are you sure?
I've got it. Yes.
Thank you.
- 17, do we have that?
- Yeah, yeah.
Sub-point 4,
and then I think it was...
10 plus 23 is...
Ah.
There it is in sub-clause 20.
Great. That's the one.
Come on, Cock.
The night's a pup.
As we still don't have
a jury of 12,
I shall allow you both
four challenges for cause.
Mr Greene.
Your Honour.
Please complete this sentence.
I admire Alan Jones because...
Because he always tells the truth
when no-one else will...
Thank you. You can go.
I admire Alan Jones because...
He stands up for all those
who can't stand up for themselves.
Thank you. You can go.
Principle among the many reasons
I admire Alan Jones is...
I wouldn't listen to him.
Thank you.
You can keep your seat, please.
OK.
Alright, fine, if you won't
release the documents,
I will subpoena
the entire US State Department
and question you all individually.
Be a nice little trip
to Australia for you.
No skin off my nose, pal.
I couldn't get a year's lease
and it's still a fortune, but...
No, it's perfect. Mmm.
Alright, now, I don't want
people looking over our shoulders,
so locks changed
on all the doors, please.
Oh, and I'm gonna need
a pullout sofa.
I think I'll be sleeping here a bit.
It's like working for a real lawyer.
Cool, huh?
Hey, your name is mentioned on
the front page of ‘America Today'.
“Leading Australian
civil rights lawyer”?
Yeah, I don't have time
for all of that.
Barney's at 10:00, yes?
Yes, 10:00. Yes.
There's something
we need to talk about.
OK, look, if this is about
the Shadow Attorney-General suing me,
I can explain.
That guy is a total...
I couldn't give a shit about that.
Oh, OK.
I'm sitting on an unexploded bomb.
Information they don't even
begin to know I possess.
It's an insurance policy,
if you will.
Most of my intelligence came through
a high-level British attaché.
Please don't ask names.
But there is another source,
in Germany,
so sensitive that no-one outside you
even knows that he or she exists.
May I ask what sort
of information this is?
Not yet, but if something
should happen to me...
Whoa, what do you mean?
No, I'm saying ‘if.
..an email will be sent
to this address.
That's the password.
Have you got it?
- Have you got it?
- Yes.
Now, understand if you choose to
release the contents of this email,
all hell will break loose.
It could conceivably
bring down three governments
and shake the foundations
of the Western banking system.
Hey. How is working for
Darth Vader faring?
Seconds away from
mandatory sentencing, are we?
He's actually smart, and his politics
are not what you think.
He has none. He doesn't believe
in anything beyond winning.
Well, your side can't even
believe in that anymore.
I thought we were your side as well.
Just mind he doesn't use you
as pretty front of house.
Nice of you
to look out for me, David.
Oh. I am so bloody proud of you!
I don't know if I'm up to this.
Rubbish. You absolutely are.
You should have been doing this
a long time ago.
Oh, should I now?
Mm-hm. Absolutely.
Where's Oedipus?
Just remember
what Oedipus did to his dad.
How are you, mate?
I'm shit, thanks for asking.
Listen, I know it's hard
at the moment but, you know...
Mate, in six months
you are gonna realise
what a very big bullet
you just dodged.
Um, Fuzz has asked me to take him
somewhere, and I've refused.
But I don't know,
you might feel differently.
Name it, pal.
I'm waiting in the car.
No. Will you come with me?
It'd be like letting a cane toad
into sugar fields, mate.
I-I don't buy any of it,
you know, the flaming bushes and
holy ghosts and walking on water.
It's all a bit like tax law
or something.
I know it's weird,
I know it's half-baked.
I just have it in my head
I need to do this.
I need to confess to someone to...
Confess to me.
Confessing to you is like receiving
career advice from Chopper Read.
Oh, thank you.
Please, Dad.
OK.
Ah, you right?
You all cleansed, are you, mate?
Satan banished?
You gotta burn something now,
or prostrate yourself?
It helped clear my head.
Good, mate.
I'm gonna go call Sally.
Tell her I'm OK.
Alright, mate.
Make your call.
Take your time. I'll be here.
Go forth, my son.
Try not to multiply this time.
Bless me, Father, for I have sinned.
It's been Christ knows how long
since my last confession,
and I've been entertaining
some impure thoughts
about a certain choirboy.
That's more one for the Marist Brothers,
I think, Cleaver.
That you in there, Frank?
I see your son has
the same genetic compulsion
to confess to a god
that he doesn't believe in.
Yeah, you're a sort of a council tip
for spiritual guilt,
aren't you, Frank?
He's a good one,
that boy of yours, Cleaver.
Take better care of him.
He's struggling, isn't he?
Yet with you
as a role model?
How are things, Cleaver?
You still Kirsty's rent boy, or
have you got some new stuff for me?
Well, you know, I think things
might be turning, for the better.
I'm sorry to hear that.
I always look forward to
the odd occasion, hearing from you.
Good to get a man who's
actually done some serious sin.
I'm starting to wonder
if you might be right, Frank.
Not about virgin births and
singing pigeons and all that hoo-ha,
but...but, I don't know,
maybe a sort of moral order
to all this madness.
You back a winner recently,
or something?
I think I did, mate.
After all these years of shit and...
..and feeling desperate
and dead inside...
..something might have shifted.
Sounding horribly positive here.
Well, it's like I'm...
I don't know, it's like
I've been given a chance.
There's all these people who've had
all these hopes for me along the way,
you know, my...my father
and my ex-wife and...
..and Fuzz and Barney and...
..and...it's like
I can maybe deliver, hey?
Do you reckon
people can change, Frank?
Yes, I do.
Be a little wary
of epiphanies, mate.
They have a nasty habit
of disappearing.
Oh, great.
Well, I'm gonna enjoy this one
while it's around,
if that's all the same to you, Frank.
Fine.
Maybe all the shit's
behind me now.
I pray itis.
Yeah. All of it.
I'm like Moses
on the road to Damascus.
Or was it Noah?
One of those guys, I think.
Listen, I'm sorry about
being a prick the other day.
We all have to work for someone,
don't we?
Yeah.
Look at me. I'm working for
what used to pass as a political party.
In that golden era where
there were parties and policies,
not just polls and focus groups
and an endless procession
of mediocre minds.
Job going well, then?
How's Barney?
Things are not great
at the moment.
I'm very sorry to hear that.
Thank you.
Ah, no, no, no. Thank you.
Well, it all starts tomorrow, folks,
the biggest year of our lives.
And I want to thank you both
for hanging in there with me
and maybe now I can pay back
some of what you've given me.
Thank you both.
To tomorrow.
Cheers.
Oh.
And in the middle of all this,
to the wedding.
Ah, yes. Thank you.
A thousand happinesses
to you and your beloved Bruce.
Yeah, Bevan.
Thank you.
Bevan.
Excuse me.
Ah, yes, Josh.
Wants me to quadruple check
a couple of things.
Alright, you two, stay put. Enjoy.
Mm-hm.
I've, uh...settled the bill.
Who was that masked man?
Good old Barney.
Yeah.
He is so...
..beautiful
and wonderful,
and he's a generous man.
I've always wanted
to get to know Barney.
Oh. You should. You must.
He really, really likes you.
No.
I can't hurt him again.
No, you mustn't.
He's a wonderful man.
Nuclear attack,
marauding refugees,
avian flu,
Communists in broom closets,
white-tailed spiders.
So many things we fear.
Scary, scary women we fear.
..S0 many things we fear,
including, sometimes, the truth.
There is, is there not,
ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
so much we can learn about ourselves
if we have the integrity,
the courage,
to stand up and not only
tell the truth,
but to listen to it.
It has a distinctive ring to it,
the truth,
a purifying timbre
that will not be silenced
even by the monotonous drone
of governments and corporations.
Joshua Floyd has reminded us
that the truth exists
and defines itself
as a function of who we are.
It may be ugly, it may be unwelcome,
and it may be the very last thing
we wish to confront,
but the only way
that we can confront it
is to know it...
..to embrace it.
The only way we can move onward
is to know that which is manifest
about ourselves.
We're due in.
Yep. Absolutely.
I hope you don't...
No. No, not at all.
Good.
Because, you know... Oh, good.
No, fine. It...
Great.
It was...
It was, yep. Yeah, it was...
Hello?
Have I got the wrong day?
No.
What's going on? Where is everyone?
Where's the press?
Trial of the century.
He's dead.
Who's dead?
Josh.
Murdered last night.
Oh, no.
You should know, they've...
taken Missy in for questioning.
http://hiqve.com/