Jen, it seems JM Doolan's memoir,
‘A Thousand Lies I Have Told',
which records the author's life
as a high-class prostitute,
has sent shock waves through
both Macquarie and Phillip streets.
Do you have any insights into
JM Doolan's book,
‘A Thousand Lies I Have Told'?
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Oh, God!
Craig Frasier was
so Catholic and guilt-ridden,
he always wept after intercourse.
Excuse me, Minister,
do you have any insight
into JM Doolan's book,
‘A Thousand Lies I Have Told'?
I've never heard of it.
Surely you must have heard of it...
No, not at all.
Nothing excited Marcus Wardell
more than wearing nappies.
Mr Justice O'Shea liked
fo be locked in a confined space
while wearing a latex hood.
Well, maybe it's your fault!
Milo Markley had a tiny dick,
and this curse filled him
with an unrelenting rage.
Clearly it's a good time.
Francine Pritchard took to hiding
a dildo under her judicial robes.
She used it in order to stay awake
during complex commercial trials.
Damien Chambers was not a client.
I saw him as someone
I ought to be in love with.
I saw him as a way out,
not only out of my life, as it was,
but also out of the lure
of Mitchell Browne.
Mitchell was mercurial.
He was a lightning rod for madness.
Brilliant. Chaotic.
A dream and a nightmare.
All the blessings of a glad father
compass thee about!
Arise and say how they cam'st here.
How beauteous mankind is!
Oh, brave new world
that hath such people in it!
I said ‘virgin'.
So happy you enjoyed it.
Thanks for coming.
Highness.
Oh, you're too kind.
Indeed I am.
You were the one snoring, right?
No.
Mmm.
Oh, mate, that is a stinker.
Really?
Apart from you.
You are great, you're...
And who'd dare to say
that you couldn't still play 15
so effectively?
Ivan.
Cleaver, I'd like you to meet
our illustrious director and star,
Ivan Yermolinsky.
Do svidanya.
Yes, it's great to meet you.
Listen, I don't wanna stay
at this shit party.
Let's just go back to the hotel.
Ivan, people wanna meet you.
They wanna congratulate you.
For what? This fucking play?
Jesus, piece of shit Shakespeare.
Oh, Shakespeare.
Third time this week
the big dryer has broken down
before it consumes Caliban.
Honestly, do you really think
the problem with this show
is the big dryer breaking down?
Cleaver.
Yes, yes. The fuckin' big dryer!
May we interrupt?
Ladies. How are you?
Such a thrill to see you, Charlotte.
Did you enjoy the show, ladies?
Oh, yes, very much.
Oh, you did? There you are.
There you go, Charles, maybe it's not
the worst production of Shakespeare
in recorded history.
What would you fucking know?
Ivan.
Well, I know enough to know
that “The Tempest'
is Shakespeare's final great testament
to life and imagination.
And that instead of setting it
on an Aegean island,
you've popped it into
a laundromat in Potts Point,
in which there's a spin dryer that,
for reasons probably
unknown to the author,
is also some sort
of a time machine.
Cleaver, enough.
I mean, what's next, mate?
‘Hamlet' in a radiology clinic
on the Gold Coast?
Oh, oh, Ivan!
Let me go!
“The Merchant of Indooroopilly'?
Ladies, let me introduce you
to our other cast.
Come on.
‘Two Gentlemen of Wodonga'?
- Let me go.
- Go home.
You know, you're right.
It was complete shit.
Cleaver Greene, at your service.
How many?
I don't know. I haven't counted.
50? 1007?
Yeah, 100 sounds about right.
100 murders?
Wow.
How many have you got off?
My average is 51%.
That doesn't sound
very impressive, Mr Greene.
Not until you realise
99% of my clients are guilty.
My friend Emily and I are making
a short film for Tropfest.
It's about a couple of girls
who get away with murder,
sort of Hitchcock meets Polanski.
Oh, yes, so a feelgood story,
is it, then?
Jesus. Sartre. Heraclitus. Nietzsche.
You love your
light reading, don't you?
What can I say?
I'm a sucker for a nihilist.
Breakfast, darling.
Thanks, Mum.
Was that your mother?
Yeah.
Right. Right.
It's OK, she's cool.
OK.
I'm sure she is, but
it's not really a good look, is it?
Why have you got pictures
of Charlotte Gardyne
all around the place?
Well, she's my aunt.
Aunt, right.
So that's why you were
at the theatre last night.
How else do you think
I got opening night tickets?
Michelle.
You're her niece, Michelle.
Jesus wept.
I was at your christening.
Michelle, how old are you?
How old do you think I am?
23.
I'll be 16 in a couple of months.
Oh, fuck. Fuck.
Don't worry.
You'll be invited to the party.
Oh, my God.
Oh, Jesus, I didn't even think.
I swear to God.
God. Cleaver,
you're not the first.
And besides, I invited you
back here, remember?
No, they'll be cool.
How can they be cool?
How can anyone be cool?
This is not... This is...
They shouldn't be cool.
It's a deeply heated situation.
Fuck.
Fuck. Fuck.
Fuck!
Taxi!
Hello? Baz.
No, listen, mate,
now's not a good time.
Really?
Who's the trainer? Oh, yeah?
OK.
They're approaching
the bend, around the home turn,
and Canard Mort is leaving
the rest of the field for dead.
This 2-year-old, 120-to-1 rank outsider
is streaking to a massive win...
Come on!
..In her first outing.
Oh, come on!
12, 13 lengths now.
This is surely
the win of the carnival.
When did we last see
a performance...
Oh, yes! Yes!
..as impressive is this?
Yes!
Oh! Oh, no! She's lost her jockey.
The veteran David Elliott
has fallen off Canard Mort.
Dear God, the other riders
are trying to avoid Elliott,
and Canard Mort herself
has come to a complete halt.
Oh, what a tragedy.
Let's just hope there's a future left
for this plucky beast,
but, dear, oh, dear,
you've gotta fear the worst.
Did you know ‘canard mort'
is French for ‘dead duck'?
I do now.
Come on, mate, a quick beating's
a good beating.
You're 200 in the hole
already, Cleave.
It's more than a beating, mate.
You know, I read about this bloke
who lost an eye at work,
got 100 grand payout.
Apparently there's this schedule
the insurance boys have got,
tell you how much an eye's worth,
oran arm, or a leg...
Col...
My question is this.
If one eye is worth 100 grand,
are both eyes worth two?
OK, you're freaking me out.
Boss wants to have a word.
If I was you, I would
pull out all the stops.
Kirsty.
Hey, Cleaver.
How lovely to see you.
Yeah.
It's been too long.
Yeah, yeah.
Shall we walk?
What a lovely idea.
You've put me in
a tricky position, Cleave.
200 grand's a lot of money.
And I don't wanna
have to hurt you, you know,
but I've got a reputation
to maintain.
I can't be seen
to be being weak, right?
No, no. God, no.
The thing is, you were so kind to me
during Mick's trial,
and I've never forgotten that.
Truth is...
..I-I think about that, a lot.
Do you?
Mm-hm.
Oh, that's lovely.
So I don't wanna make
any hasty decisions.
No, no. God, y... No, no.
I was wondering
if you would be interested
in coming and having a bite...
to eat with me...one time.
You know,
that's a funny thing,
because I'm going to
a party tonight
and I was asked if I'd like
to bring someone.
Would you like to come?
Love to.
That's great. OK.
Um, I'll pick you up at 7:00.
Wonderful.
Ooh.
I should take this, sorry.
OK.
Yep?
What'd I tell you?
What did I fucking tell you?!
No, no, that is the wrong answer.
Listen, you tell him
if he doesn't deliver by Friday,
he's not gonna enjoy
waking up Saturday morning,
if he wakes up Saturday,
you hear me?
And, cut.
That was really, really good.
It looks great.
Oh, my...
Just out there.
So, what brand of bloody and bizarre
have we got here?
Movie shoot gone seriously wrong.
- They're just schoolkids. Barely 16.
- Get me some shots with this.
Grollo, you done
with the knife?
Grollo.
Love.
Stunt knife.
Use 'em all the time in movies.
Press this little button here,
blade retracts with pressure.
Release the button,
it's a normal knife.
Where do two schoolgirls
get a hold of that?
There's nothing you can't
find online these days.
Friend of mine got a bazooka
off eBay once.
Why am I not surprised?
♪ Everybody
♪ Do what you're doing
♪ Your smile will bring
a sunshine day... ♪
Yeah.
♪ Everybody
♪ Do what you're doing... ♪
Ah!
♪ Your smile will bring
a sunshine day
♪ Everybody
♪ Do what you're doing
Your smile will bring... ♪
I don't really get out much.
You know, the last year's
been...been really tricky,
what with taking over
Mick's business and everything.
And I really...l didn't think
I had it in me, you know?
I really...God,
I really didn't think
that I could have
someone's legs broken.
But after the first few,
it's...
Yeah.
Well, you've gotta love your work.
Look, thank you for...
..a f-f-fantastic night.
You had a good time, didn't you?
I had a great night.
Yeah.
Well...goodnight.
You know it's still early.
I guess itis.
You did what?
You heard me.
You rooted Mick's wife?
Are you out of your mind?
Mate, I had no choice. I'm 200 down.
There was talk of blinding.
I don't know how to play this one.
I'm not surprised.
You free for lunch?
No, Cleave.
I'm not gonna see you.
..back to Australia.
Barn, I... Come on.
This is serious shit.
This is exactly the sort of shit
I don't want to be a part of anymore.
Look, I need a mate, alright?
I hated going behind Scarlet's back
on that Fenton thing.
I can't do it anymore.
Mate, I'm not asking you
to go behind her back.
I'm just asking you
to have a bloody drink.
They are the same thing, Cleave.
So no more drinks,
no more lunches, no more cases.
Do you understand? Goodbye.
In other news,
two schoolgirls face charges
of manslaughter
after a tragic accident
whilst shooting a short film.
Police have confirmed that
an 18-year-old man was stabbed to death
after a so-called stunt turned deadly.
The girls, who both attend
the prestigious private school
Kelly House,
appeared to be in shock...
..as they were taken away by police
for questioning.
Kelly House released a statement
early this morning,
which did not comment specifically
on last night's event...
Charles.
Oh, Charles.
Come on. Come on, it's alright.
It's gonna be alright.
It'll be alright.
It'll be fine.
We need you, Cleave.
Yeah, listen, anything I can do to help,
anything, I-I'll be there.
So you'll defend Michelle?
I meant anything
in an abstract sense.
What?
Well, I-l can't... mean,
I'm too close to y-y-...
I'm too close to you, I'm too...
[-'m emotionally involved,
so I can't...
But that's exactly what we want,
someone we know
will be in our corner.
Oh...
This isn't about money, is it?
I mean, we're not asking
for a freebie, if that's it.
No. No.
It's...
Well, then, what is it?
I-I've been there for you, Cleaver,
at some of your darkest moments.
Yeah, yeah.
I need you now.
My niece needs you now.
It was one of the first things
she asked for after they charged her.
What was?
She said, “I want Cleaver Greene
to defend me.”
They're here, Cleave.
Fine. Show 'em in.
Michelle.
Hey, Cleaver.
Lovely to see you, despite
the unfortunate circumstances.
Charles.
Cleaver, you've met my sister, Caroline,
and her husband, Ted.
Yes. Hi.
Hi.
It's been a while.
Please.
This is my instructing solicitor,
Lincoln Lincoln.
Ms Gardyne.
It's an honour.
I'm a huge fan.
I must have seen
‘A Day's Remembrance'...
..12 times.
Alright. Marvellous.
Could we get on with it now?
I don't know now.
I'm not sure of anything.
I thought I'd pushed the button in.
Em says she thought
she pushed it in.
So, um, if Em pushed it in,
I may have released it.
Cleaver, is this really necessary?
Uh, look, we're gonna have to
put Michelle in the box,
and she'll face
tougher questions than this.
But she's just an actor, Cleaver.
She isn't the one
that bought the knife.
But she is the one
that we have on film
plunging it through
the deceased's ribs.
She's a child.
Be that as it may, Ted, um,
the charge is manslaughter —
she's being tried as an adult.
Look, we'll adjourn
for the day there, OK?
Oh, um, uh, Ms Gardyne?
If you don't mind,
can I just grab a quick...?
Cleave, could you? If you just
press...just press the button...
It's not...
No, mate.
The lenses these days are amazing.
You just keep pressing the button.
Thank you. Thank you.
Just press...
Can I just... Oh.
Hi.
Fuck. What are you doing?
I thought we could use
a moment alone.
I've been thinking about you.
Where are your parents?
In reception, waiting for me.
Are you crazy?
Take a breath, Cleave.
Everything's cool.
No, everything is not cool.
You told me you and Emily
were making a film
about two girls
who get away with murder.
What can I say?
Life imitates art.
I'll call you later, gorgeous.
“Back in 20 minutes.”
I hate “back in 20 minutes”.
What does it even mean?
What does it mean?
See, we don't know if he's been gone
for 1 minute, he's back in 19,
or if he's been gone for 19 minutes
and back in 1.
So if you think about it,
he's actually bought himself
a 40-minute window of opportunity.
Why can't they specify a time, huh?
“It's now 6:00. I expect I'll be
20 minutes, so I'll be back at 6:20.”
How friggin' hard can it be?
You do the arithmetic.
Oh. “Because I have
paying customers and I care.”
I guess he left 19 minutes ago.
Yeah.
For Christ's sake, just don't
let him get under your skin.
Harry.
David. Come on.
How are ya, mate? Alright? Huh?
Alright, fuck the pleasantries.
Listen, come on, let's sort
this shit out here, OK?
It doesn't have to go to court.
Yes, it does. You defamed me.
Alright, I said some things,
you said some things,
let's call the whole thing quits.
Come on, mate, I'll take you out
for a drink. What do you say?
Cleaver, I'm a public figure
and you deliberately set out
to damage my reputation.
Oh, you didn't set out
to damage mine?
Damaging your reputation
is like trying to make shit stink.
If you're so upset about it,
why don't you make a counterclaim...
Fine. I'm trying to be reasonable.
I'll tell you why.
You know [I'll plead truth and win.
I'm happy to go in there.
You know I can prove you're...
We'll waste their fuckin' time.
..a disgrace of a human being.
More than happy to do it.
I'll see you inside.
Your Honour, in a former life,
the plaintiff, Mr Potter,
was briefed by the Australian Tax Office
to act in a matter against me,
a matter from which, I might add,
the ATO ultimately withdrew.
The plaintiff's defeat in this case
left him in what I would describe
as, um, a dangerous
state of mental health,
which was compounded
by the discovery
that prior to their engagement,
I had been a longtime sexual partner
of his then fiancée.
Having already pursued me
like a serial killer in one life,
the plaintiff was then able
to use parliamentary privilege
to savage my reputation in the next.
So you see, Your Honour,
it is the plaintiff himself
who is the root cause of this matter.
This man is after vengeance
and not justice,
and I would therefore
respectfully request
that Your Honour dismiss it.
Yes, well, not in a month
of Sundays, Mr Greene.
What of mediation?
Your Honour, we have twice written
to Mr Greene, requesting mediation,
but he has not replied.
Your Honour, I would be more than
willing to attempt mediation.
I am completely persuaded
by Your Honour's argument.
Yes. Well, I made
no argument, Mr Greene.
I merely asked a question.
But it was a question laced
with insight, Your Honour.
I'm so sorry.
He should be here in a second.
Would you like another coffee
or some water?
No, thank you. I'm fine.
- Damien Chambers.
- Mitchell Browne.
My chapter's bigger than yours.
Hi.
So how do you wanna handle this?
Maturely, of course.
Got a coin?
Heads?
Hi, Mr McGregor. I'm Scarlet Engels.
I'm sorry.
Have you read that book
by the hooker?
I am aware of it, yes.
Well, a very reliable source
just told me
that the bloke who's into nappies
is our transport minister.
Have a seat.
Thanks.
Would you like a drink?
Oh, I'm fine, thanks.
Engels?
So my parents tell me.
You a leftie?
Pretty much.
Is that a problem?
But I'm told these days
it's fashionable
to have opposition voices
inside the tent.
Helps to know what bullshit
they're gonna come up with.
Right.
So, you were at the bar?
Criminal prosecution mainly.
Mm-hm. And why the shift?
I have three kids.
Three days a week here
will be easier
than running
a full-time private practice.
Yeah, well, you're gonna have to
try harder than that, Engels.
You've got to want it.
Oh, hold the friggin' phone.
Says here you were suspended
from practice for a year.
That's right.
Well, what'd you do?
[, uh...
I cross-examined a friend.
Rush of blood to the head.
Pretty bloody silly mistake,
if you ask me.
Mmm. Things were a little tough
at home at the time.
Oh. OK, look, here's the deal.
I like you. Very impressed
by your experience.
But this matter of suspension
calls into question
your judgement and/or ethics,
and either way, that makes you
a little hot for me.
I'm sorry.
If you'd just give me a moment...
No, I've interviewed
four others for this job
and they've all got
less experience than you
and they're dull as fuckin' paint,
but they've got good
right wing credentials
and they don't have
a rap sheet.
It's been nice chatting.
OK.
Just for the record,
this...so-called friend who
I shouldn't have cross-examined?
Yeah?
He's no friend.
In fact, he's brought nothing
but chaos and despair into my life.
Yes, well, we all have people
like that in our lives.
And yours is Cleaver Greene, right?
Well...so is mine, as it happens.
Oh, the stories I could tell you.
Oh, well.
No, no, no, no. Wait, wait, wait.
I had no idea there were
such mitigating factors.
This is very hard for me to say,
but when I finished reading your book,
I couldn't help but think
that for all his hideous flaws,
being Mitchell Browne sounded better
than being Damien Chambers.
There's no point of comparison.
David, you two belong
in separate universes.
Mine being the universe
of the school prefect.
No.
You used those exact words.
Well, you're quoting me
out of context.
I've toughened up
since you've been away.
David...
Let's go get a drink or something.
David, I'm engaged.
Oh.
Yeah.
Congratulations.
Wow. Who is he?
Oh, you've heard of
good _plumbing.com?
The leaks site?
Yeah.
What about it?
I'm engaged to Joshua Floyd.
- Hello?
- Got my email yet?
Yes.
You have a webcam.
Don't need one.
Lincoln's right. The lenses
on these new phones are amazing.
Everyone assumes you can't
capture images in low light,
but...look at you.
Yes, look at me.
Mmm, I'm so pleased
you're my barrister, Cleaver,
because having had sex with you,
I know you can get me off.
Hmm. You've had a good day,
by the looks of things.
Bloody internet.
Is yours down?
I wish.
I wish it had never been invented.
It's the end of civilisation
as we know it.
www.fuckme.com.
Bring back paper, quills
and carrier pigeons.
What's happened?
Nothing.
What's this stuff with Fuzz?
Oh, he just said
he had something to tell us.
Oh, yeah? What's it about?
Well, whatever it is,
let's just be calm.
If he has a problem,
then we need to be supportive
and work through it
with him rationally.
OK?
Yes, Sister Wendy.
Mum?
In here, darling.
Hi, mate.
What is it? What's up?
There's something
I need to tell you guys.
I've been seeing this girl
for the last year or so.
It's been pretty full-on.
We're in love.
Oh!
Good-o.
Why the secrecy?
It's Sally. Sally?
Sally who?
I don't know any Sally.
Yeah, you do.
It's Sally from across the road.
I'm really happy.
Right.
Um, am I right in assuming that
there's no Sally Junior over there?
All that exercise?
You haven't been jogging
in the afternoons.
Not vertically, it would seem.
The thing is, guys, we're pregnant.
Ah.
Mum?
Mum, what are you doing?
Hey! Wendy!
Mum!
No, no!
Sally!
Wendy. Wendy, I wouldn't.
Mum, stop! sally
Mum, she's not home!
Sally, you get out here now!
Wendy, she's not...
Treacherous bitch.
Wendy, she's not home.
What is wrong with you?!
She's got a boy your age!
Look, let's just go back inside
and talk about this rationally.
There is nothing rational about this
situation. This is totally insane.
What, because of the age difference?
Well, just for starters, mate, yeah.
You are such a hypocrite!
I beg your pardon.
It's alright for
middle-aged men like you
to go around having
young girlfriends...
Isn't it? No, that is not the point.
It's not as if your father
is gallivanting round town
rooting 17-year-olds,
so don't you make this about him.
Yes. Don't make it about me.
I knew you wouldn't understand.
Look, mate, you can't
go around dropping bombs
and then whinge
when everybody screams.
Says the man who's made
dropping bombs into an art form.
Maybe I have, but when I fuck up,
I take the heat.
You think this is a fuck-up?
Isn't it?
Are you telling us
you planned this?
It's my child we're talking about.
It's not a fuck-up!
First his English teacher,
now Sally.
You know he's never brought home
a girl his own age.
This is officially a pattern.
Hmm.
What have we done to him?
Oh, bit early to start
blaming ourselves, isn't it?
We should be doing
what other 21st-century parents do
at times like this —
blame someone else.
You know, there's the school,
there's...there's
general societal malaise,
there's your mother, GFC,
tensions in the Middle East.
We can blame any number
of phenomenon
before we have to shine the old
searchlight of truth on ourselves.
And when we do, my darling,
I think you'll discover
that it's pretty much your fault.
Excuse me?
You know, it's Oedipus.
It's all that shit. You're the shrink.
I'm not amused.
I'm not saying it was deliberate.
You know, you obviously just
brushed your hand up against it
when you were giving him a bath
when he was four, or something,
and that was it.
I don't know who I can trust.
You know, any one of my friends
could be targets.
I mean, it was bad enough
when you were cracking onto them,
but both of you...
We'll have to work out
a roster or something.
Oh, no.
Here we go.
Charlotte. Charlotte.
Please, leave her.
Charlotte.
Charlotte, have you
released a statement?
My client, Emily Carlton,
is a 16-year-old.
She attends the prestigious
girls' school Kelly House
on a half scholarship.
She's a straight A student,
second in her year.
She's a member of the debating,
swimming, hockey and tennis teams,
and an accomplished equestrian
in her own right.
She's a member of
Amnesty International, Greenpeace
and was voted Young Lion
in her district last year.
Needless to say, she doesn't have
the slightest whiff
of a criminal record.
Yet this fine young girl
you see standing before you
is accused of
the most terrible thing —
causing the death
of another human being.
Ladies and gentlemen,
everything my learned friend
has said in his opening address
can also be applied to my client,
except that my client
was first in her year,
captain of the debating team
and attends Kelly House
on a full scholarship.
Isn't this a school night?
And by school night, I mean
aren't you both out on bail?
Your parents have any understanding
of the word ‘curfew'?
Oh, come on, Cleave,
we're dying to see your place.
Oh, my God.
You're a barrister
and you live like this?
No. He's only criminal.
I'm definitely going corporate then.
You do make more money
in corporate, right?
Listen, you two...
We're not very happy
with you, Cleaver.
Really?
Really.
Oh, well, am I gonna
get some notes now?
Well, you know, your heart just
didn't seem to be in it today.
Are you OK?
We wanted to let you know
if there's anything that we can do
to help you.. lift your game.
So, what is this, blackmail?
Yeah?
If I don't get you off,
your iPhone footage goes viral
and you cry rape
and the judge declares a mistrial
and the whole thing disappears.
Is that...is that the plan, Michelle,
the master plan,
along with bumping into me
at the theatre?
You're right. He is
a little jaded and cynical, isn't he?
Mmm. Yeah, but still...very cute.
I guess. We'd better go.
Yes, we better.
See ya, Cleave.
Fuck.
- Hello?
- Who are they, Cleave?
Who are who?
Don't you fuck me around!
The girls in your flat.
Kirsty, where are you?
Are you...are you having me followed?
You have two girls,
and they're hookers, aren't they?!
They're hookers dressed up
like schoolgirls.
No, no, they're not. They're not.
They're not hookers.
They're not hookers
dressed up as schoolgirls.
They're actual schoolgirls.
I mean, they're...they're...
They're the...the schoolgirls who are
on trial for murdering the actor.
What?
Yeah, do you remember?
I told you about it.
I'm defending one of them.
Oh.
Oh, darling, I'm so sorry.
Yeah, oh, that's alright.
You know, I...it's, uh...
It's understandable enough
with me, I guess.
Oh, how can I make it up to you?
http://hiqve.com/
Oh, hello.
Hey.
Dry-cleaning?
Yeah.
I can drop it off in the morning
on my way to the office.
I found 50 bucks
in your blue pinstripe.
Ker-ching.
Mmm.
And this in your grey serge.
Mmm, thanks.
That's Cleaver's handwriting.
Yeah, must be from ages ago.
Leonard Fenton, wasn't it?
No, no, Lawrence.
Lawrence Fenton, I seem to recall.
We'd represented Lawrence before,
so can we just keep this
in perspective?
I didn't wanna upset you.
It wasn't that big a deal.
It was big enough for you
to lie to me about it.
Don't make this a thing.
It was just a case.
It's not like I...
Well, go on.
Finish your sentence.
Coming up next
in our Festival of Classic Thrillers,
two cold-blooded Killers,
one hapless victim —
Alfred Hitchcock's masterpiece ‘Rope'.
Have you seen ‘Rope'?
What?
They're sociopaths, right,
or psychopaths?
A bit of both, really.
I think...I think they're my clients.
Or one of them is my client.
What, that little girl?
She can easily pass
for 24, that girl.
Anyway, she and her friend
are both Hitchcock fans.
You know ‘Rope's based on
a true story?
Leopold and Loeb.
Chicago in the "20s.
Yeah.
Describe them.
Highly intelligent
but emotionally infantile.
Go on.
Well, an IQ of 170 and the
emotional maturity of a 5-year-old
is a pretty hairy combination,
psychologically.
From what I remember, these guys
believed they were supermen.
Supermen, as in...?
As in the Nietzschean view that
society was moving towards
the evolution of a superman
who would be beyond
the laws of good and evil.
Nietzsche.
I've always thought,
never trust men who wear capes.
Now, you're sure
you're on top of this?
Yes, I'm sure.
Now, you cannot cock this up.
Trust me, Cleave, OK?
I played Caiaphas in
the school production of ‘Superstar'.
I know what I'm doing.
Jesus Christ.
- Morning, Lou.
- Morning, Cleaver.
- Lincoln.
- How was your evening?
Fine. How was yours?
Oh, you know, pretty relaxing.
A little bit of homework.
Watched a DVD.
Have you seen Hitchcock's 'Rope'?
Oh, years ago, I think.
No, it's OK, Cleave.
It's a really interesting movie,
It's about these two young guys...
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I'm sure Lou
doesn't need to hear about
your evening highlights, mate.
Sorry, Cleave.
‘Rope'. ‘Rope'.
Yeah, I've seen that. That's the one
about the two young thrill-killers.
Sorry, Cleave.
Oh, fuck.
And it transpires, Your Honour,
that this film, ‘Rope',
which depicts a premeditated murder
committed purely
for the thrill of it,
was on the Kelly House
Year 10 visual arts curriculum.
Your Honour, I object. I object
in the strongest possible terms.
Does my friend here really think
that he can bolster his paper-thin case
by tendering as evidence
a motion picture
made almost 50 years
before my client was born?
Your Honour, when the film
was made is entirely irrelevant.
For fuck's sake, guys,
what are we doing?
Are you just being silly?
Bloody movies?
Have you seen
this bloody movie, Robbo?
These girls are carbon copies.
It's a joke, Robbo.
Cleaver's right, Lou.
It's also circumstantial.
I reckon they did it.
They set out to copy the movie,
only this time, of course,
they get away with it.
Then you should withdraw manslaughter
and hit 'em with murder.
Is that something
you're contemplating, Lou?
Because it would be a brave move
if all you've got's coincidence.
Nup.
Alright, then.
The charge remains manslaughter.
Now, we all know
where this thing is going.
I'm not about to ruin
these girls' lives
by sending them off to jail
for an accident.
So please,
can we wrap this thing up?
It's not good news, I'm afraid.
The judge has suggested
to the prosecution...
...that he withdraw...
..the manslaughter charge
and replace it with murder.
Now, I said if they did that
that we'd immediately appeal
and take it all the way
to the High Court if need be.
The judge has backed down,
but God knows what instructions
he's gonna give to the jury.
Now, if the jury comes back
with a guilty verdict,
His Honour has indicated
that the girls will be doing
some serious time.
So what options do we have?
Well, look, Emily was the director.
Emily bought the knife.
It was her house.
Emily was the one
who downloaded ‘Rope'.
You were just an actor in this thing,
weren't you, Michelle?
So you had no influence over it
whatsoever, isn't that the case?
Darling?
OK.
Now, I need to have a quiet word
with Michelle, please.
Lincoln, my phone's died.
Could I possibly
borrow yours, please?
Well, don't you have a landline?
I do, but I've been told
that my contract has expired.
It's gonna be OK.
OK, well, just be careful,
it's got...
Mmm.
I'm the only thing standing between you
and a lengthy jail term,
followed by a life
of complete misery.
Do you realise that?
I've been watching the judge.
Bet he's got daughters himself.
He's not about to give us
serious time.
Really?
Why would I lie to you?
To rattle me.
Maybe get me to strike
some sort of bargain with you.
Well, what sort of bargain
could I possibly strike?
You could have your little video
of us on 100 drives by now.
Exactly.
So you know
what the consequences will be
if you don't get out there now
and do your fucking job.
I'd think very seriously about
my next step, if I were you, Michelle.
I swear by almighty God
that the evidence I shall give
shall be the truth, the whole truth
and nothing but the truth.
Please take a seat.
You and Emily have been best friends
for many years now?
We have. Yeah, since we were five.
And you've studied
and played together.
You've lived in and out
of each other's houses?
That's correct.
As close as friends can be?
You're also the smartest girls
in your class.
You're both exceptionally well-read,
both highly creative.
And through
your cinema studies class,
you became devotees
of Alfred Hitchcock.
You decided to emulate him,
to make a film of your own.
I'm sorry, but when you say,
“You decided to emulate,”
it wasn't me, or even us.
It was Em who decided
she wanted to make the movie.
She wrote and directed it.
I was just an actress
without any influence, really.
She told me what to do.
She told you what to do?
Emily'd like that, wouldn't she —
the girl who always came second?
Emily felt inferior to you,
didn't she?
Objection.
I'll allow it.
I don't know about that.
She was desperate to assert
some kind of superiority, wasn't she?
And this was the way
that she was gonna do it.
She was going to seduce you
into a situation
where she could direct you
to fulfil her own sick fantasies.
Is that not the case?
Objection!
Mr Greene, get to the point.
That is what happened,
isn't it, Michelle?
Emily was the one
who turned the knife into a weapon.
It was her plan. This was her idea.
You have to stop protecting her.
You lying bitch.
Emily!
It was you, you're the one
that told me to download ‘Rope'...
- Shut up, Em!
- Miss Carlton!
You picked up the guy at the party
and you told me that
after you stabbed him, you came!
This is completely outrageous!
Your Honour, I'd appreciate
an adjournment.
The Crown may wish
to amend the indictment
and replace the current charges
with charges of murder.
Why would I lie to you?
To rattle me.
Maybe get me to strike
some sort of bargain.
Well, what sort of bargain
could I possibly strike?
You could have your little video
of us on 100 drives by now.
Exactly.
So you know what
the consequences will be
if you don't get out there now
and do your fucking job.
I apologise for the shitty framing.
She's a very ill girl, Charles.
You took advantage of her.
No.
Alright, I'll have anything
that incriminates you dealt with.
She still trusts me.
She idolises you.
She's barely 16.
She should have
her whole life ahead of her.
16 is the new 35.
I never want to see you again.
I figured that.
Ms Gardyne?
Charlie?
Did you ever suspect
she had any responsibility
for what happened?
This has come as a great
shock to all of us in her family.
Our hearts go out
to the victim's family.
Obviously it's a tragic event.
And I'm still processing information.
It's very shocking.
Nothing really changes, does it?
Tragically, no.
There's always one place
I know I can find you.
Yeah, well, there used to be two, but
that was when I was a petulant child.
‘Lost' child.
I think you'll find it's ‘petulant'.
Well, I wrote the fucking book, Cleaver.
It's ‘lost'.
We should talk.
Indeed we should.
I understand things are getting right
out of hand in the Gaza Strip again.
I'm getting married, Cleave.
One engagement
may look like a misfortune.
Two look like a habit.
Why are you here?
I just wanna talk to you.
OK. Why?
Because you have
an inquisitive mind.
Is that what you call it?
What would you say of my mind
if I told you
that it had been seduced
by a 15-year-old sociopath?
Middle-aged men
do not get seduced by youth.
Oh, really?
No.
You can't be seduced by something
you're already craving.
Saying that you've been seduced
is just a bid for victim status.
Are you free for dinner tonight?
He gets in tomorrow.
Oh, brave new world
that hath such people in it.
http://hiqve.com/