Shit! Oh...
Shit, shit, shit! Ohh!
Police! Open up!
Come on. We know you're in there.
Cleaver Greene?
Yeah, you know who I am.
Sorry to bother you this late,
but we understand you reported
a child's bracelet
stolen some time back?
What are you talking about?
Silver-plated, semi-precious stones
and an “I love Justin Bieber”
love heart.
Very nice.
Yeah.
Not you?
Oh, dear. Don't tell me —
this is the wrong place.
And at this time of night!
Mmm.
Nice shirt.
Come on, guys! We'll be late.
Darling, are you sure?
Yeah, it's fine. I can take them.
I don't have my first
appointment till 10:30.
‘Bye, Mum.
‘Bye!
I've got a million things
to do around here.
‘Bye, Mum!
‘Bye!
Rusty!
Ladies and gentlemen
of the board,
doubtless you would agree
that it is vitally important
that we confront the variables
of our current economic landscape
and recalibrate our thinking
in terms of our client base
moving forward.
Excuse my emotion, Madam Chair,
but that for me —
and I hope for all of us —
was a genuine “wow” moment.
Let me pose this one
simple, clear question.
Are you as a company moving forward,
as the engine room
of a greater organism,
genuinely embracing
and honouring the fundamentals
underpinning the goals expressed
in your mission statement?
Are you nurturing and cherishing
your “ongoing commitment
to excellence at every level”
both in terms of your charter
and at your customer interface?
Because that is your mandate,
that is your remit,
that is your duty of care.
Outcome focus as a means
of achieving positive deliverables
within a realisable factual matrix...
Plus achieving
customer satisfaction targets.
Oh, KPIs.
Yes, yes, yes.
And isn't that another way
of saying it's about...
- Lawrence Fenton?
- Stop there!
..communication!
We're arresting you
on charges of trespass.
Look, can I just finish
making this point?
It speaks directly
to their core values.
No, come with us.
What is the meaning of this?
This gentleman is a consultant.
He has every right to be here.
Oh, really? In what field
does he consult?
Oh, he is a leading...
..leading...
..consultant, hm?
So he was invited to the meeting?
Well, Russell asked him.
I did no such thing!
That's what we thought.
Come with us, please.
It's Audrey, isn't it?
I think I met you once before
at the Branman Energy AGM.
All these words have lost
their essential meaning.
That is what my protest is about.
Pick any of these words at random,
shove them in any order you like
and they'll make just as much sense.
Off you go.
Read any government document,
listen to some corporate guru —
elaborate,
technical-sounding twaddle.
It was you who phoned us
about the Omnico meeting.
You said lives were
at stake, Lawrence.
They are. Our very civilisation
is at stake.
This is how the world will end —
not with a bang,
but with a diminished
verbal response capability.
That's how CIA agents
at Abu Ghraib described a whimper.
The Pentagon describes a plane crash
as “an unintentional flight
into the ground”.
This is what we've come to.
These people are robbing us
of meaning, you see,
and they have to be stopped.
You wanted to get caught
so this would come out in the press.
Now read that out without pause
as if it had some meaning.
Stress ‘only' and ‘consistent'.
“The uplift manifests only
when positional change occurs
“within the context of our deliverable
modular units
“consistent with our core
underpinning fundamentals.”
Oh, brilliant. Now just add
“moving forward” and you're set.
Yeah.
Oh, g'day, Cleave.
Way too long, mate.
Yeah.
High time we squeezed the nectar
out of a few grapes.
Mmm?
Listen, mate.
I was wondering if you're
free for a spot of lunch.
I might be able to steer
some work your way.
Yes, today, mate.
See, this is the thing, Paul.
You've told me that I should be
less structured and more impulsive.
Well, I...
“Make impulse
and spontaneity your mantra.”
OK, that's...
that's entirely my fault.
Um, but at the end of the day
it's about outcomes, isn't it?
What is it you want to achieve?
Uh, I want...
I just want to make things right
for Barney and the children.
I want to make up for what I did.
Scarlet, you need to stop
punishing yourself
for your affair with Cleaver.
That's all in the past.
Isn't it, Barney?
Yeah.
Are you still seeing Cleaver at all?
No.
So, uh, tell me —
how's your special night going?
Um, we've decided...
..that we might try the role-play.
I'm a little nervous. I'm no actress.
Well, that...that was
merely a suggestion.
It's about having
a fun, relaxed time,
you know, being yourselves
and reconnecting with those original
feelings you had for each other.
What the hell is he doing here?!
Is this some sort of bad joke?
How marvellous
to see you too, Clover.
Ah, Cleave!
Come in, mate.
Not on the terrace.
I have Bridey and Geoff coming over.
Yeah, righto.
Jesus, Damien. I can't believe
you brought him to our home!
Ignore the Clove, mate. Sorry.
I didn't think she'd be home.
She's still pissed about
you shagging our ex-premier.
Oh, yes.
Caused some real headaches
for the party.
You know, I once had sex
with the premier's sister
30,000 feet above Denpasar.
I take it you're a paid-up member
of the Mile High?
No, but I once had sex
in a portaloo, if that counts.
Where are we, exactly?
This is my sanctuary, mate.
Yeah, I've got something
like this at my place.
I hope this isn't lunch, mate,
‘cause I haven't eaten.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, lunch.
Yes, yes, yes. You said...
you said lunch, actually.
I've been doing a bit
of pro bono financial work
for the kids' leukaemia foundation.
CFO by default.
It's one of Clover's little pets.
I said I'd help sort them out.
Things have gone a bit pear-shaped
and, uh, I thought I'd employ
your smarts from the get-go.
I don't do commercial law, mate.
No, no, this is criminal.
OK.
Look, I borrowed a bit from
the foundation — purely as a loan.
I haven't had a chance
to pay it back yet.
I mean, I will. I guarantee that.
But they've called in
the forensic accountants
and I think...
..there's a chance
I'll be wading in the brown stuff.
How much are we talking about?
Two mill.
Well, a smidge over,
but I'm good for it.
You stole $2 million from
a kids' leukaemia foundation?
It wasn't theft, mate. I had a couple
of investments go sour and...
Oh, yes, I can see those.
And that bitch has me
spinning on a rotisserie.
She's given me an allowance,
a drip-feed from the family trust!
Do you know how
humiliating that is, mate?
Sorry, mate, I still
haven't moved on from
you stole $2 million from
a kids' leukaemia foundation.
I don't mean to
editorialise here, mate,
but what sort of a man are you?
Look, I didn't fucking steal it.
It was a loan. I'll pay it back.
I got a plan.
Right.
By that, I take it you mean
you hope a roughie comes in
at 20-to-1 at Randwick.
I love it — you're all
this and that, aren't you?
Now, what's the play?
There's no play, mate!
You live in a fucking
$12 million mansion!
You steal from dying kids!
They haven't invented the words
to spin language to get you out of this.
You're in deep shit.
Shh!
Keep your
fucking voice down, mate.
You gotta help me out.
And I can pay you, but the wife
can't know, otherwise I'm fried.
What's your advice?
Oh, how many times have I told you
to ring before you bowl up here...
I rang, I rang.
There's a message on your phone
saying, “I'm in a taxi,
I'm coming to your place,
“I need your vacuum cleaner.”
Well, there's a sentence
I didn't expect to hear from you.
You look shocking. Have you
had a party or something?
Yes, a party celebrating the return
of my Justin Bieber bracelet.
Have you got any food? I'm starving.
Uh...
Fuzz in?
He is indeed.
He's studying, what's more.
He's not going out.
He jogs every afternoon.
Amazingly enough, he's not having sex
with any of his female teachers.
Ladies.
This is my book club.
Book club, ex-husband
on the way through.
Oh, you're in a book club.
How wonderful.
The vacuum cleaner's in the laundry.
Do...do you know where that is?
And so what happens here, ladies?
You sit around saying things like,
“This novel has
a delicious sense of irony,
“although I think Mabel's character
is more trope than substance.
“Could you pass me
the quince paste, please?”
Don't anyone engage
with him, alright?
Well, pretty much,
and then we open another bottle.
‘A Thousand Lies I Have Told',
JM Doolan. She a lawyer?
Ex-prostitute.
Same, same.
“‘Doolan's savage first novel
is as gut-wrenchingly moving
“as it is devastatingly funny.”
She's covered all bases,
hasn't she, old JM?
Well, it's fiction, but it's
clearly based on her own life.
It's a good read.
I think it's a really brave book.
It's visceral and honest.
I mean, she doesn't protect
these sleazy, depraved men.
Hold on, hold on. Back up. Rewind.
Why are all of the menfolk
sleazy and depraved,
but the bravest woman on earth isn't?
Wasn't she porking them for coin?
Oh, hang on.
This is the ex you said
spent half his life in brothels.
No wonder
he's so touchy.
I told you that stuff in confidence.
That was therapy.
No.
See, as I've told you
on SO many previous occasions,
I'm not your therapist.
I'm your ex-wife, OK?
And if you're gonna offload your
squalid little personal life onto me
then you run the risk that I will
repeat it for my friends' amusement.
Old Sally's looking good, isn't she?
No, no.
Divorce really seems to suit her.
No!
Sally is a neighbour, OK,
and as such,
she is strictly a no-fly zone.
Are we absolutely clear on that?
Alright.
I'm just getting to the stage
where I can recall your good points.
Really? What are they?
Phone ahead and I might tell you.
Come on. What are they?
I'm gonna report your mother
to child welfare.
There's absolutely bugger all
to eat in this place.
There's some old bread
in the pantry.
“A necessary
but not sufficient condition.”
What the hell does that mean?
This is frying my brain.
Don't go anywhere near the
living room, then, for God's sake.
It's brutal in there, isn't it?
Mm.
Legal studies.
‘Herewith', ‘Forthwith',
“Pertaining to
but not inclusive of...”
This is how people
control us, isn't it —
make it all so mysterious
the rest of us don't understand.
Yes, that's why the law and religion
were in Latin for centuries,
but then they realised
they could make English
just as incomprehensible
as a dead language.
So if I understand you correctly,
you make your living
strangling words
So a jury doesn't know
which way is up.
Yeah. We also get to wear wigs.
It's why law's a four-year course.
I could take you through the nuances
over a pub lunch, if you'd like.
I can't. I wanna go for a jog later
and I've gotta get this essay done.
You know, I am thinking
of having your DNA tested.
There you go.
When did it change from ‘For sale'
to ‘Selling', do you think?
Wouldn't you love
to be in that meeting?
You know, some child genius saying,
“Sale' is so passive.
“We need an action.
We need a doing word.”
I bet they're hoping it makes
people ignore all the dry rot
and think, “Shit, we'd better hurry
‘cause they're really selling.”
I'm thinking of
abandoning my compost sandwich here
and getting a pub lunch.
Would you be up for that?
Mr Greene.
We need you to come
with us to the station
in regard to the abduction
of a 15-year-old girl
in Surry Hills three months ago.
Oh, yes. Hey, this is
not how it looks.
I promise.
OK.
This is police harassment
on quite a large scale
and I will not be cowed by this.
You can tell Cal McGregor from me,
this will not break my spirit.
Maybe you should get a lawyer.
ow!
OK, see you.
Thanks.
Sorry about this
misunderstanding, Mr Greene.
Yes, I'll bet you bloody are.
What about some bickies next time?
Barnyard.
Cleave.
You're looking well.
I'm fine. Thanks.
No, I mean it. You've dropped
a couple of pounds. Back at the gym?
It was about time.
What brings you here?
Never fuck a premier.
Cleaver.
Lawrence! As I live and breathe.
Whom have we offended now?
I appear to have upset
the board of Omnico.
Brilliant. How?
I believe they were
under the impression
they'd invited me to a board meeting
to help them unpick
their ongoing commitment
to excellence.
So are you briefing anyone
in particular these days?
I've been briefing Rob Curlewis
on a few things.
Rob Curlewis. Oh, very nice.
He's a good man. I'm sure
you'll make a dynamic duo.
This won't require
Rob's services.
Why?
Omnico's embarrassed.
They don't want anyone to know.
They're not pursuing it.
What about Lawrence's day in court?
What about the media?
That's what I said, Cleaver.
Listen, Lawrence. I'd consider myself
lucky if I was you.
This is what? Your ninth offence?
Keep this up,
they'll send you to jail.
Over my dead body.
Oh, Cleaver — a man who truly
understands the value of language.
Certainly no-one
distorts it like he does.
Listen, Lawrence. I've gotta run.
Cleave.
Barney.
Shame you two have fallen out.
I always saw you as inseparable.
Oh, well, Lawrence,
we're both to blame.
It happens in the best of
barrister-solicitor relationships.
You know, you think you've made
a professional commitment for life.
After a while, you start
taking each other for granted.
His briefs started dropping off,
I wouldn't get back to him.
Sometimes a whole month would
go past and he wouldn't brief me once
and I didn't even notice.
Hmm, very sad.
But Barney also mentioned something
about you having sex with his wife.
Well, there was that too, yeah.
Open up! It's the police!
Oh, that is so great for you guys.
How long have you
and Jaz been trying?
I want everything we can find on
Cal McGregor. And I mean everything.
I wanna know what brand
of nappies he wore.
Yeah, hang on. I got
your ultrasound now.
Oh, oh, there it is!
Oh, did you cry?
Particularly anything relating
to police harassment, alright?
Nicole? Hey, I can't see from this.
Is it a boy or a girl?
Absolutely urgent, Nicole.
Highest priority.
Alright, alright, I think...
I think it is a boy.
Oh, no, hang on. Maybe it's a girl.
What else would the woman
be having? A marmoset?
Oh, look at its... Here.
Looks like Newcastle's
in for showers.
Can you...
Congrats on the pregnancy, OK?
But can you please tell
my secretary the frigging sex
or we're gonna spend the rest
of today watching a woman
trying to pick a winner
in a two-horse race
that no-one outside you and your
husband gives a flying root about.
OK, thank you, caller.
Thank... Oh, thanks.
Oh, sorry.
Yes, of course it was him.
Yeah, I told you —
no-one believes me.
Yeah, every day, the same.
So names?
This government is ever cognisant
of the ongoing, ever present and
ever real threat of global terrorism
and we unequivocally applaud...
You sure I'm not
committing us to anything?
No, the “in principle” covers us.
But it still sounds
like we are committing?
Oh, very much so.
Good.
On arrival at 2:10,
you will formally greet
the British home secretary
and Sir Ryan Telford, head of MI5.
Press photos for
10 minutes on the steps.
At 2:20, you will escort them
and their party into the building
to be welcomed by their
Australian counterparts.
Alright.
No cock-ups, fellas.
International coverage
bouncing around the globe,
the city in lockdown.
I want the Cahill Expressway
shut down,
Martin Place shut down,
Hyde Park shut down.
Anything west of New Zealand,
shut it down.
And let's make sure the Feds
pitch in their fair share.
You know, it's their show too.
I don't want some ABC kids' program
turning this into a circus.
So I've spoken to the DPP.
Charges are imminent,
but the foundation has requested
there be a suppression order.
Apparently, they don't
want people knowing
that money given with
the very best intentions
was actually donated to
the drug habit of a rich idiot.
So my name stays out of this?
Prison?
Oh, mate, I'm not going to prison.
Fuck that. I'm not
a bloody criminal!
I can maybe argue two of the charges.
Well, what does that mean?
You'll only get nine years.
Or we can plead
not guilty to the lot.
And...?
You'll get 12.
Are you bullshitting me?
Or we can plead guilty from the kick,
show remorse, throw ourselves
on the court's mercy.
Which will get me what?!
Seven. Five if the judge is in
the same men's club as your wife.
Cleaver, I thought
you were helping me out.
Mate, I feel like I'm stepping
outside my comfort zone
a little here when I say this,
but what you did,
even by my relatively low standards,
was totally immoral.
Yeah?
Well...how immoral
do you really think it is?
Just like to take your photo.
Thanks very much.
I'll see you inside.
Madam Home Secretary,
you travel so well.
Thanks very much. See you inside.
And so security remains for all of us
the critical issue directly confronting
us in a global context
as we move into an uncertain future
where the nexus between terrorism
and the vulnerabilities
of global interconnectivity
become ever more virulent
and threaten our core values
of freedom and democracy.
Get down!
- Everyone, move!
- Let's go!
Hey, hang on! I lost my fucking shoe!
I cannot begin
to understand the humiliation
the Attorney-General must
be feeling at this point.
Here we have the self-styled
champion of law and order
at the most expensive
intergovernmental security forum
ever held in this country,
our skies littered with helicopters,
our city a no-go zone.
And what happens?
A retired English teacher
manages to slip through the cordon,
have drinks with the British
home secretary and the head of MI5,
then sit centrestage
with all the dignitaries...
..as Cal McGregor lectures us
on the need to be ever-vigilant.
Isn't it time this attorney-general did
the honourable thing and resign?
What do we know about Fenton?
Another one of these pricks
who make a sport out of
crashing high-profile events.
Yeah?
Well, he's not gonna get
any fucking publicity on my watch.
Barry. Cal.
You gotta pull your digit out, mate.
This little arsehole's
fucking humiliated us.
There's bugger all
I can do, mate! I'm State.
All I can get him on is a trespass,
he'll walk out with a 50 buck fine
and the press will be
hanging off his every word.
Barry, we have to
gag this prick, pronto!
I mean, surely there's
something you can ping him for
in the Anti-Terrorism Act.
Who's that lunatic judge
that droned on about the Saudis
having the right idea,
chopping off the hands?
Beesdon?
Beesdon.
He's insane.
Barry, Beesdon's still
on the bench, isn't he?
They have to be stopped!
We must rise up.
We'll have nothing left
if we don't stop them soon!
Fenton is one of only
a handful of people to be charged
under the Federal Government's
anti-terrorism legislation.
Oh, God.
Now, I'm not allowed
to comment on this case.
Safe to say that it seems that
it was way, way more than a prank.
There are some very, very
alarming elements to this
and I thank God
for the great men and women
of our intelligence services
who may have saved untold lives.
No, you've got
every right to be angry.
Yeah. Look, I'll write some emails.
I'll call you in the morning.
OK.
That was Emily, Ella's mum.
Uh-huh.
You know that school that we spend
so much money at year in, year out
that should be delivering
the best possible education?
I know where
our children go to school.
Well, Emily just told me something
that confirms what the kids told me
on Tuesday at our debrief.
Your what?
My sharing time — focus one-on-one
with the children.
You refer to it as a ‘debrief'?
It's just a term!
Sure.
Do you know what they do on wet days
at lunchtime? They watch movies.
On Tuesday, they watched
‘Wind in the Willows'.
I don't follow.
Emily thinks it's nothing
but childminding. She's right.
I mean, surely it's
the school's responsibility
to provide a proper educational
indoor activity when it's wet.
We send our children there
at considerable expense
to get core learnings,
not watch cartoons.
“Core learnings”?
I don't see the problem.
Well, Emily and Denise are ropeable.
Really? ‘Cause of
‘Wind in the Willows'?
Maybe we should set up some sort
of victims' support group.
Hey, it's not funny! What if we didn't
let our kids watch cartoons?
Yeah, but we do!
And we bought them
‘Wind in the Willows' three years ago.
I grew up on Bugs Bunny
and I've survived relatively intact.
Babe, what is this about?
You're a terrific mum. You don't
need life coaching tips from Emily.
Have you thought some more
about going back to work?
I don't want to go back to the bar.
I couldn't.
You're a brilliant woman, hey?
The bar's not your only option.
I'm here now, for them,
for you, 24/7, 365.
You hungry?
Yeah.
Will you shut up?!
Hello.
I told you
never to phone this number again!
Lawrence is in serious shit here, OK?
You have to put aside
personal feelings.
Sad Who is it?
From Fiji?
Yep. I can hardly hear him.
No, no, no, no,
you mustn't come here.
Listen, I'm gonna be
at the Imperial Hotel
tomorrow at midday, OK,
and I will stay there for one hour.
If you don't turn up,
I will...understand
and I will never bother you again.
Has he been snorkelling?
Yep.
Oh, g'day, mate.
Oh, Barn, you've gotta be kidding.
Happy birthday
for last week, by the way.
Thank you. Can you get
to your point, please?
Alright. You have to
brief me on this.
Come on. In your heart,
you know it's the only way.
I'll find the right man.
Oh, sure.
Look, I'm sure there's
millions of barristers
who'd kill to be briefed by you.
I thought you told me
solicitors were a dime a dozen.
I was angry, hurt, lashing out.
I said things I never meant.
What I need to know
is what you want.
I made a promise to Scarlet.
Dammit, Barney.
If you want me to walk away, I will,
but I need to hear it
from your lips.
It doesn't matter what I want.
It's how it is.
From your lips. Do you
want me to walk away?
Don't do this, Cleave.
OK, there's the door.
I'm walking out.
We won't need to speak again.
Maybe just... I don't know.
Send me the occasional card,
let me know how you're getting on.
I am standing up
and walking out now, alright?
Here I go.
Oh...
Oh, Jesus. This isn't necessary.
Tell me what is happening, please.
When can I get out of here?
They've refused bail.
But they can't, can they?
I just committed trespass —
a fine, a reprimand.
No, you've been
charged with offences
under the Anti-Terrorism Act.
I'm not a terrorist!
You are
under this act, my friend.
Pretty much anything you do
under this act is terrorism.
Wear a loud shirt after dark
in Adelaide, they've got you.
You just couldn't resist
this one, could you, Lawrence?
Not after I read
their press release.
It was an ocean of mixed metaphors.
Well, I'm afraid there's nothing
metaphorical about it now.
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
you may have read some
highly irresponsible articles
suggesting that trials such as this
conducted under
the Anti-Terrorism Act
resemble witch hunts.
Let me set your minds at ease.
Although there will be some aspects
of this trial that are different,
these proceedings remain
very much open and transparent
in the best tradition
of the Australian judicial system.
Ms Crown.
Your Honour, my opening remarks
may touch on certain matters
pertaining to national security.
Therefore, I would like
to respectfully request
that my opening address be held
in camera without the public.
Of course.
Clear the court.
Your Honour, this is an opening
address. It's not evidentiary.
My client is a retired
English teacher.
The Crown, by its own admission,
cannot adduce evidence
that my client was
in possession of even a BB gun
let alone a handgun,
a bazooka, a landmine...
Your Honour, we have
made our position clear.
We do not submit that Mr Fenton
had the intention of committing
violent acts himself.
He had the intention to break into
high-level private security meetings
in order to glean information
that he could share
with like-minded individuals
who would then carry out
acts of terrorism.
OK, let's humour my friend Ms Crown.
What was this information
that my client was seeking?
What precious secrets drove my client
to endanger himself in such a way?
The defence requests access
to all records and transcripts
of this conference.
Your Honour?
I'll reserve my decision.
Let's move on.
Yes, the vet was ordering in
some Prozac for our dog Rusty.
That's right.
The dog has behavioural problems
and is very anxious and frets.
No, no, listen.
You hear that?
No, no, that's the strange thing.
I am here more often.
Let me get this right.
Your name is John Smith?
That's it?
You're not John Hubert Smith?
John Du Jean Valjean Smith?
It's just John Smith?
Yes.
Just Agent John Smith, then? I see.
Your Honour, may I please
read the Crown's witness list?
Now we've got
John Smith in the box.
Next we've got a John Jones.
Then Jane Jones.
I wonder if those two are married.
Mr Greene, you know perfectly well
that it is in the public interest
that active intelligence
field officers giving evidence
must be allowed to keep
their identities secret.
Move on. Move on quickly.
Mr Bond... I'm sorry.
Mr Smith, you were in charge of
security procedures at the symposium.
How did Lawrence Fenton get inside?
It appears he may have joined
the British delegation on their way in
and we presumed him
to be one of theirs
and they presumed him
to be one of ours.
And so how long after
observing my client
in conversation with
the head of MI5 and ASIO, etc,
did you twig to the possibility
that this former English teacher
was not in fact
a crack member of the Johns?
We can do without
the sarcasm, Mr Greene.
These people are our gatekeepers
against a very dangerous world
and it behooves you to remember that
and to respect them.
Duly behooved, Your Honour.
Our attention was alerted
shortly after Mr Fenton
proposed a birthday singalong
for the British home secretary.
That's it — the full transcript
of everything said at the forum
minus some deletions
for reasons of...
National security.
It's like the night sky.
Everything's been blacked out.
Shit. Scarlet can't
see me on the news.
Cleaver Greene.
Look, I can't speak directly
to the press about this case,
but let me just say this —
that when a bloody-minded government
and an irresponsible minister
trample on the democratic rights
of a citizen,
it is one sorry day for this country.
I'm sure it is. I'm here
to serve you with a summons.
Pardon?
OK, I'm sorry, but this
little game is over, alright?
You can tell the Attorney-General...
He's the shadow attorney-general,
isn't he?
Who or what
are you talking about?
David Potter, the man
suing you for defamation.
He is the shadow attorney-general.
What?
Harry-sorry-Fuckwit is what?
Oh.
“Harry-sorry-David Potter
hid like the coward he is
‘under the cloak
of parliamentary privilege.”
Yeah, taken
completely out of context.
No, said verbatim by you on radio.
And then you repeated every word
in your stupid, look-at-me,
aren't-lI-clever blog,
and I quote,
“Potter's dishonest nature
“and contempt for common decency
‘makes a mockery
of the position he represents.
“He is not fit for public office.”
Can't accuse me of not being clear.
How many times has Barney
told you not to drink and blog?
You know in the eyes of the law this is
published throughout the planet?
How much does this whingeing toerag
think he's gonna get out of me?
Word is around a mill.
I can prove all this stuff.
Oh?
“Mr Potter's psychological issues
are clear evidence of a man
‘who has a troubled relationship
with his penis.”
Alright, that one's a little trickier.
Mmm.
http://hiqve.com/
Honourable Lord Barnaby,
you do me humble honour
in allowing me to pleasure you.
Tell me, are you a peasant girl?
Yes, I...
I can't. I can't.
Hey, love, it's fine.
I can't either.
I feel like a total dork too.
No, let...let me try again.
It matters. No, this
Is our special time.
Love, there's nothing special
about Wednesday night.
We're not geisha,
Lord Barnaby kind of people.
Then can you tell me
what sort of people we are?
Because I don't know anymore.
We're just your ordinary,
“root every now and then”
kind of people.
You know, a leg over
on Saturday mornings
when the kids burst in on us,
the occasional grope in the laundry.
I'm looking for something
that I can hang onto
and say, “Yep, this is me.
This is who I am.”
But nothing sticks.
I don't have a clue who I am.
Hey.
I don't...I don't trust myself.
God...God, I've even
sent the dog insane.
No.
It's a labrador, Barney.
They use them as guide dogs.
Oh!
How can I be expected
to mount a proper defence
if I can't get a full transcript?
This is nonsense.
I'd wonder if you'd think that
if the full content of these papers
ever got into
the hands of terrorists
and suddenly your children
were seized from your home
and tortured and butchered
before your very eyes.
Pardon?
I refuse to compromise
the safety of our nation's children
because you want
to grandstand in my court.
Let me just quote you one of the few
surviving exchanges, alright —
this between the British
home secretary and the head of ASIO.
“Sarah, have you been
to our botanical gardens?”
“No, I have not.”
“Oh, a shame. The begonias
are in full bloom.”
Then six lines are deleted.
Then the British home secretary
says, “I love begonias.”
Now, what do we think
was in those deleted six lines?
“No, I've not been
to the botanical gardens.
“We launch a nuclear strike
against Pakistan at 0800.
“But I do love begonias.”
It's not relevant what was said.
My client's future
rests on establishing
exactly what was said, Meg.
Nothing of any consequence
appears to have been raised at all.
The fact that begonias
was the predominant topic
of conversation
is neither here nor there.
Isn't it?
Listen.
If you were to illegally wire tap
somebody's phone
and all they happened
to talk about was the weather,
that does not mean
you haven't broken the law.
It just means you didn't
get what you wanted.
Precisely.
Let us resume.
Let's cut to the chase, Lawrence.
What the hell possessed you
to bust into this forum?
What these so-called important people
are doing with words,
the way they use language
to actually hide what they mean.
It's a form of corruption.
The writer Don Watson
calls them ‘weasel words',
where corporations and governments
complicate what they say so much
that there is no longer
any accountability or integrity.
Once we stop believing
in what is being said,
once language loses
its power to connect us,
civilisation is finished.
Thank you, Mr Fenton.
They have to be stopped!
We must rise up.
We'll have nothing left
if we don't stop them soon!
It is obvious
from this footage
you knew when you
entered the building
that you were doing so illegally.
Well, my concern was
that they were using...
Did you knowingly trespass,
Mr Fenton?
I admit I trespassed, but only to...
Yes, it was about words.
We heard you!
“We'll have nothing left
if we don't stop them.”
There's no hidden meaning
in those words, is there?
You seriously expect
this jury to believe
that you penetrated
that forum to what?
What? Correct their spelling?
- Your Honour.
- No.
I don't care a jot about their spelling
or their split infinitives.
Would you tell this court,
did you also illegally
attend meetings
at Omnico Communications, Durmack
Chemicals and Pachen Software?
Objection, Your Honour.
We all know where my friend
is going with this
and we all know she can't go there.
Yes, she can.
Yes, I gatecrashed
those meetings, but...
Funny choice
given that Omnico, Durmack Chemicals
and Pachen Software
each have direct links to the defence
forces of this country...
Objection, Your Honour. My client has
never been charged with any of this.
Overruled.
Look, I don't care what they do.
They're all clones to me.
I put it to you that your intent
has never been some quixotic cause,
but in reality
you sought to discover
these companies' deepest secrets
in order to undermine
the stability of this country.
You're kidding.
The man's an English teacher.
Mr Greene!
Mr Fenton, on May 14 last year,
did you publish in your blog
the actual minutes
of a Pachen Software meeting
in which they discussed
their potential role
in the deployment
of a military satellite?
l...I only published
the bit where someone said,
“Motivating support
“within a stringent,
regulatised umbrella agreement.”
Yes or no, Mr Fenton?
- Yes.
- Jesus. Fucking blogs.
So you admit you leaked information
from a secret meeting
that anyone from a hostile power...
“Hostile power”, Your Honour?
Be very careful, Mr Greene.
Let's drop the harmless
pedant guise, Mr Fenton.
I don't think anyone's buying it.
Clover. Very good to see you again.
You are looking gorgeous as ever.
Cut it, Cal.
I know very well I'm the last person
on earth you wish to see.
You know why I'm here.
I got a fair idea.
I've given more time
and money to the party
than almost anyone else
in the state.
You worked in my father's
electorate office for five years.
I know all you've done, Clove.
And we all love you.
But...
..you're married to a turd.
So I keep hearing.
And what he's done,
no-one can forgive.
It's not about him!
Your eldest goes to ALC,
doesn't she?
Mm.
You know that world.
How do you think my two girls
will survive there
if this ever becomes known?
And how the hell do you think
the charity will recover?
I have worked so hard for them.
We are keeping it under wraps, Clove.
None of us want this to get out.
The moment he's sentenced
the gloves will come off.
You know that. It will go viral.
Give me an out, Cal.
My daughters and I
don't deserve this.
There must be some...
arrangement we can come to,
some way of...
..massaging this.
There he sits,
the most dangerous criminal mind
of the 21st century —
this man who taught
Austen and Dickens
at a private school for 27 years
before he took an early retirement
so that he could nurse his dying wife.
They want you to believe
that he is capable of tearing down
the walls of this country.
Are we really that afraid
and untrusting now?
Isn't it interesting
that when people talk about the
measures needed to protect freedom
they are usually discussing
ways of limiting it?
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Crown has no case.
All my client committed was
a minor trespass and they know it.
Lawrence Fenton's sole mission
is to have us say what we mean
as clearly as we can.
Please, you cannot
send a man to prison for that.
It is very important for each of you
to make up your own minds.
My own private view
is of no consequence here.
You will have observed the open
and transparent nature of the trial
and much of the prosecution's
case is conjecture.
But as Ms Crown points out
in her fine summation,
Australia is at war, like it or not.
We have enemies who hourly threaten
our borders and our values.
The question then
is could Mr Fenton's presence
jeopardise our security
in this dangerous climate
by exposing certain vulnerabilities
which could now be known
to our enemies?
Of course, only you can decide that.
Get in.
Tell me — did you pay Beesdon
or are you just relying
on his dementia?
I understand you're
representing Damien Trengrove.
That's my business.
No, it's not. It's mine.
The man's a piece of fungal rot.
At last we have common ground.
Mm, the problem is
if he goes down
a very fine charity
goes down with him.
So what if, by chance,
it doesn't make it to trial?
How could it not?
Well, instead of closing the doors,
the Hyacinth Foundation
could stay open
with one very generous donation
of 3.1 million from the Trengroves —
a million more than was stolen —
Damien never finds work again,
Clover Trengrove divorces him
and the fungal rot dies sometime
in the not too distant future
in a puddle of his own vomit.
What am I expected to do?
The DPP will, obviously,
need a submission from you
incorporating no end
of eminent medical opinions,
especially one from
a leading professor of neurology
which argues that Mr Fungal Rot
was prescribed
a relatively untested medication
that may well have fogged his reason
and caused a pattern
of compulsive behaviour.
You want me to cover your arse.
Well, the party's arse.
But in return, I will reluctantly
call off the dogs of war.
OK, but you have to help me
with this bullshit Fenton case.
Oh, it's got nothing to do with me.
But as an impartial outsider,
I would say he's fucked.
Ah.
Close the door behind you, will you?
And don't push your luck.
Jesus, is this creep
gonna get away with this?
This one is particularly
creepy, isn't it?
Yeah, I think I even liked
your cannibal better.
What? What is it?
Your friend's baby.
Uh... Oh, a boy.
Gonna call him Dylan.
Nice one.
Yep.
Lawrence Fenton,
I sentence you to a period of seven
years in a maximum security prison.
You'll be eligible for parole
in five years.
Please remove the prisoner.
Five years? Are you out of your mind?
Mr Greene, how dare you!
All rise.
I am...
I'm...I'm a...
Could use a beer.
Yeah, I gotta get home.
Goodbye, Cleaver.
Beesdon's insane.
There are a thousand grounds
of appeal from day one alone.
No.
No?
I'm on the front page
of the papers, am I not?
People have to notice now.
There's a tide in the affairs of men,
Cleaver, and ours is turning.
Maybe I can better
win my war from here.
Besides, it's quiet, I get to read
and no-one seems interested
in me as a toy boy.
May I read you something?
It's an extract
from a letter I carry.
“Sand ate into our skins like an
abrading stone, yet we felt nothing.
‘Instead, we stood in ox-dumb awe,
“diminished and humbled
by these weathered, ancient blocks
“that were once some ruler's
vainglorious grab at immortality.”
My grandfather wrote that to my
grandmother from Cairo in 1915.
He left school when he was 12,
worked all his life on the railways.
That's how people
used to communicate.
Hm.
Oh, God. What have you
done to yourself?
I bring manifold gifts —
a vacuum cleaner and a moron's guide
to constitution law for Fuzz.
He's out jogging, which is why
I suggest you always ring first.
Oh, a shame. Could've done
with his company.
It seems like
the minor threat of terrorism
worries people more
than tidal waves of stupidity.
I'll call you a taxi
and talk to you later.
Can I come in?
Yoga group, OK?
Who was it?
No-one.
Someone flogging something.
Cleaver.
Julie.
Missy.
http://hiqve.com/